Dispatch?
Go ahead, 26.
Yeah. Contact the FAA.
Tell them some smart-ass is flying a jet plane
around out here with no lights on.
Roger that.
Did I hear you ain't comin' to the game?
Somethin' about "you don't want to
drive five hours to see a football game?"
Well, I'm not a big croud guy.
Plus, someone has to stay behind,
to keep the peace.
- You going boating?
- I'm undercover.
Sure, Ray.
You blend right in.
- See you Sunday.
- Hey. Whoa, whoa, whoa. What about your car?
It's parked in a fire zone.
If there's a fire...
go ahead and move it.
But please, be careful with her.
Schmuck.
- Morning, Sheriff.
- Morning.
- Hey, Sheriff.
- What a beautiful day.
- Yes, it sure is.
- Hey, Ray!
- Hey.
I almost didn't recognize you in plain clothes.
Well, it's my day off.
Should be a quiet weekend.
- No more of those big omelets, OK?
- All right boss. But you know you like 'em.
Oh, yeah, but ...
Thanks.
- It doesn't matter.
- It does!
Howdy fellas.
- Hey.
- Howdy Sheriff.
I'm guessing that's your rig out front.
What are you guys hauling today?
- Auto parts.
- Yeah.
- Gotta hit New Orleans by noon tomorrow.
- Oh, that's a long drive.
- Sure is.
- Yep.
Check please.
- Keep the change.
- Thanks!
- We're 'bout to hit the road.
- Well, drive safely.
Sure will.
- Thank you, sir.
- Thank you, boys.
Boy, you sure are bad for business.
Did you want somethin' to eat?
- Sheriff?
- No. No thanks, Christie.
I'd better get going.
Bye.
- See ya' later, Ray.
- See you.
... that's the Arizona State Fair,
where Grand Avenue and W. McDowell Road...
That'll put another asshole
in the elephant right there boys.
My turn, come on.
Wait! Now watch that kick.
She don't know it's your first time.
- Just hand it over. Stand back.
- All right, all right. Here we go.
- What the Fuck?!
- No, no, no.
Easy! Easy!
- Hey, I warned you.
- Let me see. Let me see.
What? What?
Shit!
- Is it broken? Do you think that it's broken?
- It should be.
- Is it broke...
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
I thought he wasn't working today.
What's up, Ray?
Hey, Ray. How you doin' man?
Good to see you.
Can someone tell me
what two-thirds of my force is doing out here
firing rockets at a slab of beef?
Afternoon, Ray.
- Do you have a permit for that monster?
- Yeah, right here.
Why don't you get him a towel or something?
He's messing up his uniform. And you,
- clean the chunk of beef off your hat.
- I gotta' chunk of beef?
Oh, look at that. That's nasty.
Thank you.
There you go.
The Dinkum Firearm and Historic Weapons Museum?
- That's right.
- You got a museum here?
And the tax returns to prove it.
Open every second Thursday of the month,
noon 'til three, bring the whole family.
Sorry.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
Ray, I'm really sorry.
Ray? We were just havin' a little fun.
Not much to do in town,
it's pretty dead over there, and uh...
you know, we needed somethin' to do.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Well, I've got something for you.
- Okay.
A couple of truckers stopped in town.
They weren't too happy to see me.
There's something off about them.
Run those plates for me.
Mine, Sheriff.
If you get a hit, pass it on to the troopers.
Wow! You're lookin' jacked, Ray.
You been workin' out?
- I warned him about the recoil.
- Give me the damned thing.
Let me have a go.
Before I change my mind,
and write you a citation.
We've secured the location.
Okay, are we all ready?
- Game on, boss.
- Love it.
Yeah, boss?
We've got some trouble with the farmer.
What? Can't handle one farmer?
Tell you what...
Let's get started!
I'll talk to him.
I'm great when it comes to farmers.
Howdy.
How's it goin'?
Things be goin' a lot better if you tell me
what the hell you doin' on my property.
My name is Burrel.
You see, I'm shooting a commercial,
I'm sure you've seen one on TV...
and your property...
- would be just perfect...
- Hey!
Get the hell off my property.
The company I'm workin' for,
gonna pay you a lot of money.
- You don't have to do a damn...
- Did you hear what I said? Huh?
Don't you at least want to hear
what I have to offer?
No. Do you want to hear my offer?
You clear out now,
and I won't fill your ass full of buckshot.
Old man, you better put that piece away,
before you blow your toes off.
We just talkin' here.
Now we finished talkin'.
You get out the hell out of here!
Okay.
That's your decision.
You don't want to take the silver?
Better take the lead.
What I'm trying to say is...
It's embarassing to have to
lock up your ex-boyfriend.
- Who's fault is that?
- The person who stole. You.
I mean, who's fault is it we're exes?
- We are not talking about that right now.
- Oh yes, we are.
I mean, we're talking about something else,
but we're really talking about that.
Do you have an aspirin?
This isn't the nurses office.
- I mean, what is wrong with you?
- Oh my God.
You had everything. You were smart,
you were popular, you were a great athlete.
I mean hell,
you had a full ride through college.
Had you not gotten yourself
kicked off the track team.
You really want to do this?
Ok, I served my country in
fucking Iraq and Afghanistan.
No, we're not talking about the war, OK.
We're talking about your being locked up
for being drunk and disorderly.
What do you care if we're not together?
Hey, Sarah.
- What's up, Frank?
- What's up, buddy?
That was awkward.
Hey, are you two dating again?
- Maybe.
- No.
Do we really have to keep him locked up in here?
Yes!
Why?
Because the boss say I gotta' keep you
locked up for the weekend. That's why.
Could you show me how to run these plates?
Idiot! Give me that.
- I'm just doing this once, okay?
- Oh, I know.
Pay attention.
Hey, Ray.
Damn.
The plates on that truck checked out.
Nevada registry, The driver is one Burrel Thomas.
Clean record.
Great.
- Good work.
- Thanks.
But I'm sure you didn't come all
the way over here to just tell me that.
I need to make a move.
Go some place where there's some action,
where I can make a difference.
Like when you worked Narcotics in L.A.,
I just don't understand how you ever
gave it up to come to this place.
The most exciting thing I've
done in the past four days is...
rescue a cat out of a tree.
Sommerton has its charms.
Maybe...
I've never been out of it,
and I'm going stir crazy here.
Do you think you could
help me get a job in L.A.?
L.A. is not all you think it is.
Look...
I understand that you want to move on.
You're young.
You want to experience adventure.
When I was your age,
all I wanted to do was move to Los Angeles.
I wanted to be part of the action.
But now...
thinking back, I feel differently.
But if that's what you really want,
of course I'll help you.
Morning.
Thank you for coming on such short notice
at such an early hour.
This is a top secret operation.
In 45 seconds, we'll move a prisoner
to Federal Death Row.
That prisoner is Gabriel Cortez.
Cortez is the most vicious cartel boss
since Pablo Escobar.
Let's make sure this guy never
sees the light of day again.
We will travel underneath the radar.
Let's do this.
Convoy is holding at position Alpha.
Awaiting clearance to proceed.
Be advised.
Fuck! What the hell?
Jesus!
- Spread out!
- Cover me!
Hold your fire!
Fire!
Cease fire!
On the roof! On the roof!
Move! Move, move, move!
- John, I'll cover the alley.
- Good. Ok, you go with her.
HRT, you take the stairwells.
You two guys are comin' with me.
You shut down elevators.
The rest of you secure this place.
Nobody gets in or out.
- Ready.
- Let's do it.
Cover all flanks.
Move, move, move!
Pick it up, gentelman!
Pick it up!
Here.
1167, What happened?
I need back-up and air support.
Medic!
Let's go!
HRT, report.
We've got two agents down.
Cortez is gone.
Stop! FBI!
Cut him off!
Stop!
Show me your hands!
Don't fuckin' move!
It's not him.
Stop! FBI!
Son of a bitch!
McKay!
Richards, what do you see, tell me.
All quite in the rear entrance.
We're checking the alley now.
John...
Richards. Richards.
You copy?
Richards!
Don't.
It's McKay, isn't it?
Baby on the way, right?
Put the gun down.
Richards! Richards?
- Man down! Man down!
- I got it.
Shit.
- Yeah? Yeah?
- No.
I want you to shut down every private airfield
and landing strip in a hundred mile radius,
I don't care how small.
- That's going to take some doing.
- Then get doing.
You need to check every building
that has a camera facing the street,
I want you to check that and see if
you can get an ID or a license plate.
How much did he pay you?
He asked how much you were paid.
For what?
He doesn't know what you're talking about.
What, you think I'm an idiot?
Do I look like an idiot to you?
Do you want me to ask him?
No. I want you to ask him why he's wearing that.
Why is he dressed that way?
Why are you dressed like that?
He's wondering why are you dressed like this.
I wear the colors of the
Dutch National Team. Why?
He says he supports the
National Dutch football team.
- What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
- The soccer team.
He's wearing their team colors.
You can't fuck with me, or what?
All right. I'll play this game.
What country do Dutch people come from?
He's an asshole,
he almost broke my hand.
He says his arm hurts from where you grabbed him.
He was reaching for something,
I was worried for my life.
So I tried to hit you.
I should have hit you the fuck harder.
That's such bullshit!
Oh, so now you speak English?
If you knew any Spanish,
you'd know I was barely speaking it a minute ago.
All right, smart-ass.
What were you doing out at 4am?
It's Vegas, man!
Sir, we have something.
Owens here, what's up?
Hi, sheriff. It's Christie.
Did I wake you up?
No, no, no, no, no...
I was already busy.
What can I do for you?
Well, I just came in to open up the diner
and the milk hasn't been delivered yet.
Is this really a police matter?
Mr. Parsons always delivers
fresh milk first thing.
He's a very early riser, you know.
I don't even care about the milk,
nobody's even around this weekend, but...
that man hasn't missed a delivery
ever since I can remember.
And I'm worried about him.
Well, have you ever thought about calling him?
Stubborn ole bastard doesn't have a phone out there.
Oh, that's right.
I forgot.
I'm just afraid he's got
a heart attack or somethin'.
Sorry to wake you.
There's just nobody else around,
and I didn't know who else to call.
No, you did the right thing, Christie.
I'm going to send a deputy out there and
I gonna have him check up on him, All right?
- Thanks, Sheriff.
- All right. Bye, bye.
Cortez and his crew, they dumped the white sedan
and they got into two separate cars.
And as of right now, we think,
that Cortez is in this one.
Hold that right there.
What is that?
Where's Mitchell?
He ​​knows cars.
Mitchell, come here.
- Yes, sir?
- Blow that up.
Aaron, Aaron. What kind of car is this?
I think it's a "ZR1".
- What the hell's a ZR1?
- The Corvette ZR1.
This one is a specially modified show car.
It's a monster on wheels.
It was all over the news, like two days ago.
It got stolen from the L.A. auto show.
Normally something around 700 horsepower.
But this is upwards of 1,000.
I got a psychopath in a Batmobile.
How am I suppose to stop them?
Blow it up?
What if there's a hostage inside?
All right.
Let's get this out to everybody in intel.
This is the car we're looking for right here.
The car that you are looking for is
a modified version of a Corvette ZR1.
Yeah, I'm looking at a picture now.
I'll let you know when he reaches our position.
Officer.
- License and registration?
- Yes, sir.
Here's my license.
Registration.
All units, call it in!
Hey! Hey!
Hold on, cowboy.
You don't sneak up on ole man Parsons.
You know what he's like.
Hey, Mr. Parsons!
It's Jerry Bailey.
We just cme by to check up on you.
So please don't take any shots at us, OK?
Shit.
- All right. Let's check around back.
- Yeah.
Hamburglar. Want to try the door first?
Mr. Parsons?
I check upstairs, you check the ground floor.
Cortez just blew through their checkpoint.
But all airfields are closed,
so he won't be flying out.
I want a roadblock here.
Bullhead City. Nothing gets through.
What the hell is he tryin' to do?
Southbound on the 95.
He thinks he's getting to Mexico,
but that's not gonna happen.
Why doesn't he take a chopper?
The ZR1 is faster than any chopper.
It's more than that.
Cortez, he's third-generation cartel boss.
He thinks he's untouchable.
That's how his mind works.
He wants to be behind the wheel.
Literally.
What do you mean?
Cortez has been racing cars
since he was a teenager.
His father build him his own track in Sinaloa.
He's been racing on the pro circuit
in South America under a pseudonym.
I saw him drive.
He's good.
Quiet!
Bannister.
Are you having a nice day?
It's gonna be.
This can only end one of two ways.
And you know what?
I'm fine with either one of them.
With your pretty little
agent dead or alive?
I can cut her up in a hundred pieces,
and mail them back to you
one by one. Is that what you want?
You've already killed one federal agent, Gabriel.
You kill one another, and I guarentee you
this world is not big enough for you to hide in.
How are you going to explain to her parents
why their daughter is
returning home in plastic bags.
Here's how it's gonna go, John.
Pull your men back and
stay the fuck out of my way
or your agent is rood kill.
I'm good either way.
So let me talk to her.
I'm sorry, John.
I really screwed this up, I'm so sorry.
I'm gonna get you out of this.
All right. Don't worry.
If you try to stop me, a lot of people
that don't have to are going to die.
It's your choce how to play this.
Right now I'm just a guy out for a nice drive.
So much for blowing him up.
Shut the fuck up!
Yeah?
Ray, we're here at Parsons.
We found his body.
He's been ​​murdered.
We got a positive ID. A cyber-grey
metallic ZR1 headed southbound on US 95.
Hostage is visible inside the vehicle.
He's almost on you, chief.
Copy that.
Don't worry.
We're ready for this guy.
A lot of people have said that.
Cortez has a way of proving them wrong.
I need you to be alert.
And you need to remind your men that
there's a hostage in that vehicle.
Coming up on the Arizona border.
- He'll be on top of you soon.
- Copy that.
Everything's in place.
Five minutes.
Move.
Get comfy.
I want you to have a good view of the show.
What?
Fall back!
Good God.
The barricades' been completely destroyed.
It looks like a war zone down there.
We've got several officers down.
I'm on my way.
Now remember, this is a crime scene.
Don't touch anything.
10-4 on that.
Ok, so the way I see it, we got a busted window.
All right, it looks like
a burglary gone bad to me.
I think what Parsons did,
he came in, and he surprized them maybe.
It coulda been that.
Did anyone check for tire tracks yet?
They were here first.
I'll go check.
- Stay together.
- Yes, sir.
Show me the body.
Right over here.
Oh, Jesus.
No burn mark on the entry wound.
The bullet passed clean through.
A pistol round didn't do this.
Can you tell which way they went?
Towards the canyon.
Let's go.
Three million dollars in
Swiss accounts per our agreement.
You know, in my country, the police
say "Gracias" after being paid off.
If you're going to continue
driving like a maniac,
Can I stop playing hostage now?
Sorry.
What is that?
Excitement.
What?
Shit. Just lost visual
We just lost visual.
- How? How? Get it back.
- We're goin' around.
He's gone.
What do you mean he's gone?
Just keep looking.
You gotta keep looking. Keep looking!
Find him!
We lost him.
We'll stay on it.
Fuck!
He was killed outside.
His body was moved inside after the fact.
How quickly can Cortez make the border?
At the speed he's going,
65-75 minutes.
That little patch of border he's
headed towards is mostly deep canyon.
Can you bring that up for me, please?
The only crossing point is here.
Los Algodones.
I know the CBP agent in charge down there.
He's a hard ass.
And the border crossing was just rebuilt last year.
Concrete blast walls, in-ground retrackable steel barriers.
It's a fortress.
Cortez isn't racing towards a target
without a strategy to get through.
So whatever he's planning,
we've got to be ready for.
Start moving assets to Algodones.
Reinforce that crossing, all right?
What about this town?
Sommerton Junction.
There's no official crossing,
but it's the closest point in his path.
Hang on.
The ravine is too deep to cross.
It's a long shot.
Let's not ignore it though.
I'll give the Sheriff a call.
Tell him to keep out of the way.
- Yep?
- Sheriff Owens?
That's me.
Who am I talking to?
John Bannister with the FBI.
We have a situation.
Well, talk to me.
I have a violent fugitive making
a run for the Mexican border.
Now there's a small chance that he
might try to cross at Sommerton.
It's unlikely that he'll be comin' your way,
but I'm going to send over a
SWAT team from El Centro just in case.
No offense, but I want them handling this.
Listen, I can't talk right now.
I've got to go.
What's up?
I don't know.
The FBI says there's an escaped fugitive
that might be heading our way.
Shit, when it rains, it pours.
This is no coincidence.
First the guys at the diner, now this.
It's all connected.
I've got to reach Bailey and Torrance.
Shit.
What's that light over there?
Do you think it's them?
Do you think the killer's
stupid enough to hang around here?
Damn it. Give me the Glock.
Stop the car.
What the hell is that?
Bailey, Torrance, where are you?
We followed some tire tracks to the
canyon edge at the south side of town.
There's someone out here.
We're checking it out on foot.
Negative. You need to fall back immediately.
Do you copy?
Give me this.
Ray, we got work lights.
Something big is going on here.
Ray, do you copy?
Stop!
Jerry, Run!
- Cover!
- Go!
What the hell is goin' on out there?
We're taking fire, multiple shooters.
I'm almost there!
NVGs on.
Kill the lights, now!
What...?
You OK, Jerry?
Can you make it to me?
Yeah!
Yeah.
No...
Bailey's over there.
He's been hit.
- I'll cover you.
- Go!
Bring me the gun!
Bailey, come on.
Shit!
Go! Go, go, go, go, go!
Is anyone following us?
That's a negative.
I didn't see any headlights.
Good.
Are you both OK?
- Oh my God, Jerry. You're still bleeding.
- It's nothing. It's nothing.
- Ray...
- Find the wound and apply pressure.
Okay.
I'm Sorry.
It's Ok, it's OK.
I hear uniform blood stains
take forever to get out.
Yeah, well, what do I care?
You're the one that's going to
be cleaning it for me anyway.
As soon as we get you patched up.
Do you think Frank would be jealous
if he saw us the two of us like this?
I know, you can just tell your buddy
that he's just wasting his time, you know.
I don't date prisoners.
Yeah, he likes you too.
Okay.
Hold on, Jerry.
Jerry, hang on, Jerry.
Ray, hurry.
Stay with me, Jerry.
Everything will be fine.
Jerry...
Come on.
Ray...
Jerry...
Sarah?
Sarah!
I can't believe he's gone.
He's was talking about you,
only minutes before he died.
What'd he say?
He told me to go easy on you.
That you're not all that bad.
What do you mean cops gave you trouble?
- What kind of trouble?
- Listen...
Are you going to be ready on time?
Yes, not gonna be a problem.
I expect you to complete your mission.
I don't want to hear any excuses.
Oh, shit!
- Bannister here.
- How far is the SWAT team?
45 minutes or so.
- Why?
- Because I need your help.
Your fugitive is trying to cross
the border right around here.
What are you talking about?
There was no crossing at Sommerton.
They're going to build one. Because the
ravine south of town here is very narrow.
There's a whole team out here.
Military background, heavy weapons.
They're building a moblile assault
bridge across that canyon.
- Oh really. You think so?
- I know so, I've seen them.
We've been engaged in a
fire fight with those guys.
Now, who the hell is this fugitive anyway?
- Gabriel Cortez.
- What?
Why the fuck didn't you tell me that earlier?
My deputy would still be alive
if I would have known that!
You know what? I don't have time to
explain every little detail to you.
Why don't you go out there and patrol,
or something like that?
Look, I don't know you.
And I don't answer to you.
Son of a bitch.
Hung up on me again.
Piss-ant country Sheriff.
Phil, give me the SWAT captain, all right.
Got it.
And throw up a map of Sommerton up here for me.
I want to check something out.
- Sir?
- Captain.
There's a chance Cortez may
actually try to cross in Sommerton.
When you get there,
if you find bridge, destroy it.
Yes, sir.
Mobile assault bridge?
That's SWAT up ahead.
What are you gonna do?
Death doesn't come when you expect it.
Driving a race car...
or in a gunfight.
Death is waiting in the kitchen when you
get up at night for a glass of milk.
My niece, my sister's oldest,
she was a good girl.
I practically raised her.
Then one night, I find her pointing
a Glock at me in the kitchen.
If she hadn't hesitated, it would have been my brains
splattered all over the marble floor, instead of hers.
Shit!
Don't try to see death coming.
You won't.
SWAT's not coming.
So we're on our own?
Well then, who's gonna stop this guy Cortez?
This is on the feds.
He was in their custody.
They lost him.
He should never have been our problem.
Maybe not.
But if he comes through our town,
he will be our problem.
Okay, so...
So we can turn our back for a half hour.
We could do that.
If you do that, might as well throw these in the trash.
Ray, let it go.
I can't.
Jerry's dead because of that guy.
Ray, you know me.
I'm not a coward. Look...
I would more than happily draw down
on those guys with you, for Jerry.
But Cortez, he's out of our league.
He's ​​got an army.
Look. If you guys want to just step aside,
that's fine with me.
I'm not going to fault you for doing so.
But I'm not gonna let that
guy come through our town...
without a fight.
I took the same oath as you, Ray.
Ray!
Looks like you're a little short handed.
You need my help.
Are you still as good a shot as you used to be?
Muscle memory lasts a long time.
Frank, I've seen you start a lot
of things you didn't finish.
Jerry was my friend.
I've never quit on my friends.
Set him free.
Consider yourself deputized.
I won't let you down.
Ok, ok.
That makes four of us.
You happy?
Phil.
I want you to pull financials
on everybody in this division.
Including me. No exceptions.
Cortez has somebody on the inside.
Somebody who tipped him off when we were
about to move, and I want to know who it is.
All right?
Ray, I...
I gotta tell you...
When Jerry and I were being shot at...
I was scared shitless.
I mean, I could barely keep my hands from shaking.
That's quite normal.
I mean, everyone feels like that during a fire fight.
I tell you a secret.
I'm probably more afraid than you are right now.
How can that be?
Because I've seen enough blood and death.
I know what's coming.
I want you to ask Washington
to get us real time satellite imagery
of the area surrounding Sommerton.
You know if this sheriff is right,
and we've got a hundred
federal agents standing around
Los Algodones crossing with their
dicks in their hands for no reason.
What's the fastest way to get there?
We can charter a jet out of McCarren.
Do it.
Ready?
Yeah, but how are we going to go up against all
that firepower with a bunch of shotguns and knives?
I got an idea.
I got two conditions that need
to be met before we do anything.
Well, name it.
I want to be deputized like Frank here...
so any damage caused to or by me
will be official business of the
Sommerton Juctions Sheriff's office.
Put ​​your hand on it.
I do hereby instate one Lewis Dinkum
who'll serve as deputy from this day forward,
or until his services are no longer required
by the people of Sommerton Junction.
- Witness?
- Witness.
- What else?
- Huh?
Second condition.
Oh, I want to hang on to ole Georgetta here.
Seeing as I'm the only one fit to handle her.
Ok. Let's go.
I mean, you can handle her too, Ray.
And you too, Frank.
You might be able to handle her.
- Well thanks, Lewis.
- Well, let's go.
Voila!
Jesus Christ, Lewis.
Shit.
What a beauty.
- Where the hell did you get this?
- Vicky?
She's my little Nazi killer.
1939 Vickers gun.
My little crazy bitch.
Of course she can't really fire
in the legal sense though.
But I did run down all the missing parts for her.
So she could function theoretically.
Course that's between us and Jesus.
Uncle Sam don't need to know nothin' about that.
- You have more ammo?
- A few rounds.
Well, bring everything you got.
What do you think,
we are fighting in the crusade?
You never know.
We meet on Main Street in five.
We need as many vehicles
as possible, for the blockade.
I'll drive ole Henrietta here.
You have stupid names for all your shit?
Only the shit I love.
Let's go.
All right. I'll brief you when we touch down.
Update me.
Border Patrol is putting a team together
but they won't be there for over an hour.
- National Guard?
- Longer.
What about the military?
It takes a presidential order.
We're not going to get that in the next 45 minutes.
Now Cortez has to come through Main Street
in order to get to the canyon.
The only other option is Asamora.
Torrance, you take Frank and Lewis
and block that off.
And Fig and I are going to warn the civilians.
Got it.
- Hey, Ray.
- Listen guys...
There is an escaped fugitive coming through town.
It's too dangerous for you to stay here.
I want everyone to go home.
Did you hear what I just said?
We just ordered breakfast.
It's for your own safety.
You're talking to a 72 year
old man with high cholesterol
eating a bacon and cheddar
omelet with extra cheddar.
Do I look like I'm afraid of death?
Don't look at me.
I ordered the same thing.
Well, I just started cooking.
- Where's Christie?
- Went to get milk.
Just stay away from the windows, Ok?
Stay away from the windows.
- Okay.
- We can do that.
All right.
How do you want to do this?
All right, lets put your truck on the far side
and then try to find some more cars to use.
I've got a better idea.
- We might need somthin' bigger.
- Yeah.
Maybe three on this side.
Have to be enough to fill it in.
What are you planning to do?
- Just stay back.
- No Dinkum, what about the lines?
This is the phone and cable.
Electricity's over there.
No, that's not what I mean.
If you cut the phone lines...
Geronimo!
- Geronimo!
- Get back. Get back!
Fucking perfect.
Let's get some cars in place.
Well, shit!
Jesus.
John?
- You'd better take a look at this.
- What is it?
The Satellite feed from Home Security,
this is the live view of the canyon
just south of Sommerton Junction.
Look at that.
- That's a bridge?
- Yeah.
I don't believe it.
The Sheriff was right.
Who is this guy?
In 1988, Owens joined the LAPD.
He trained under their Elite Tactical Division.
Worked Narcotics for five years, then he quit.
Why?
Well, he crashed a party on some
bad guys movin' a half ton of coke.
He took home the Medal of Valor.
Five bullet holes for his trouble.
Owens lived, but seven other cops didn't.
So that was it for Owens.
Guess he'd seen enough bloodshed,
so he walked away.
He went to Sommerton to play Sheriff.
Thanks.
Yeah, we need two more.
Oh my God! What are you doing Dinkum?
- Have you lost your mind, you idiot!
- Settle down.
I almost got it.
- Dinkum!
- Don't do that!
Dinkum!
Dinkum, are you okay?
Oh my God, are you all right?
- Henryetta?
- It worked!
Nice job, deputy.
Nice job.
Ray, we're gonna need something bigger than this.
I got an idea.
- Torrance.
-  Asamora's blocked off.
Good. Have Dinkum and Martinez
meet me in the school yard.
And I need you to be on top
of the roof of the old hotel
to be my spotter.
Figgy, you go to the Southside and
check if the buildings are cleared, okay?
- I'll be right back.
- On my way.
Time for a turkey shoot.
Oh, shit!
I got guys on Main Street
approaching from the South.
Do not engage,
wait for us to get there.
Copy that, Ray.
What the hell is that?
This is gonna be a lot of fun!
I'll need two guys on the left.
You two take the right.
Shoot anything that moves.
If it doesn't move, shoot it anyway.
Once our work is done here,
we're gonna burn this place to the ground!
Christie!
- Jesus, Figgy?
- Christie, you have to get out of here, now!
What the hell's goin' on?
What are these cars parked for?
Look at that ass.
- Christie, you have to get off the street, baby.
- Why are you hiding behind a car?
I could kill for that ass.
Shit!
Come on! Come on!
Go! Go!
Get down! Get down!
Come on! Come on, come on!
Get to the diner!
Is that the best you got?
Look at that squirrel
with that big motherfucker hat.
This is getting boring.
Get the big gun!
Oh Shit. Shit.
Yeah. Give him something to remember.
Oh, shit!
Take him out!
Get him!
Figgy!
All clear...
What the fuck happened?!
-  Torrance, are you okay?
- I'm Ok, Ray.
But Figgy's down.
Damn!
Now, what the hell is that?
Welcome to Sommerton.
Nice shooting, Sheriff.
Get this the bus into position.
- Vámonos!
- I got it! I'm on it!
We're in place!
Get down!
Torrance, where is the fire coming from?
Behind you.
Roof next to the diner.
- Cover me guys!
- Yes, Sir!
- How are you, Sheriff?
- Old.
Ah, you got a ways to go yet.
Oh my God Sheriff, you've been shot.
- Somebody help him!
- I see it. Hold on.
Don't worry, it's just glass.
- Where are the stairs to the roof?
- Over there.
He's goin' after Sarah.
We have to warn her.
Give me the radio!
- Give the radio!
- We don't got no damn radio!
We got nunchuks though!
- Just cover me!
- Cover you?
What the hell?
Sarah!
Does this mean I'm forgiven?
Probably.
Shit!
Thorzetta!
God damn cowbell!
Fuck!
Jesus.
Motherfucker.
- No trespassing!
- Quiet Granny.
- Mrs. Salazar?
- Sheriff.
Obliged!
Put the hurt on em', Ray!
Okay.
- Figgy?
- Lewis, what are you doing?!
Figgy's over here...
Fuck!
Ray!
You get Dinkum.
I'll cover you!
I've got you.
Come on.
Jesus.
- What are you doing out there?
- I'm a deputy.
Lewis.
Hey!
Here I am!
You little motherfucker!
Come on! Shoot!
Where the fuck are you?
Little rat. You wanna play?
I love to play.
Okay.
Oh shit!
Drop the weapon.
Who the hell are you?
I am the Sheriff.
I'm here.
Do you copy?
Are you ready for me?
We will be.
You're very good in close quarters, aren't you?
You're very beautiful, Agent Richards.
And nothing would give me greater pleasure...
than to demonstrate...
How good I really am.
But since you're still going to need
to look the part of an escaped hostage,
consider this a goodbye gift.
What do you mean?
What the fuck?!
Shit!
So you want to play?
Let's play!
Yeah!
Now what?
Shit.
Son of a bitch!
Fuck!
I'm gonna kill you!
Shit!
You fucked up my car.
You fucked up my day off.
You know what, Sheriff?
All you have to do is let me
walk across that border.
Hell, twelve thousand
Mexicans come across every day.
You shouldn't mind if one goes back.
What do you say?
You make us immigrants look bad.
Well then,
let's discuss my deportation, shall we?
Carlos, uno momento.
This is my personal banker.
Simply tell him your account number.
You will be five million dollars richer.
We will part as friends.
Ten million.
Put those on...
or I will.
Maybe once upon a time.
Your time is over abuelito.
My time is just starting.
Game on.
You should have taken the money, old man!
Ok! Ok!
Twenty million.
Twenty million dollars just to look the other way.
My honor is not for sale.
Fuck your honor!
You are under arrest.
Here comes the cavalry.
- John Bannister, FBI.
- Glad you could make it.
So what happened here?
Where's Cortez?
The Sheriff went after him.
I'm more concerned about him right now
than I am about Cortez.
Looks like you're both in luck.
Look at that.
Good thing.
Good for him.
One last time. Only this time,
the surprise is on you.
Let's go guys.
John!
Richards!
Are you Ok?
Yeah, I'm Ok.
I'm so sorry, John.
He was going to kill me.
It's so good to see you.
Yeah, I'll glad he didn't.
I'm really glad he didn't.
Because that would have cost me the satisfaction
of being able to arrest you myself.
I know the two of you are
use to being driving buddies.
And for your information, Swiss bank accounts
are not as secret as they use to be.
Let's go.
Shit!
That's why I shot him.
I can walk!
Just because a man gets wounded
in the line on duty
don't mean he can't walk.
I don't want that.
Way to go, Ray, Martinez, Torrance.
I can walk.
Maybe if Christie wants to help me, she could.
- Thanks little one.
- Anytime, Lewis.
Figgy!
Sorry!
Let me see, let me see.
- That's a .50 caliber.
- That's a painful .50.
Look at that.
What about you?
I'm fine.
Oh, please, come on.
That's a BB gun.
Let's finish the report and get out of here.
Good.
I'll say it.
I completely underestimated you, Sheriff.
It's Ok.
You're a hell of a lawman.
And you don't give up too easy.
You're right.
This is my home.
Impressive.
Sheriff...
Keep it.
You earned it.
- Thanks, Ray.
- Jerry would want you to have it.
Thanks.
Ray!
What in God's name happened to my car?
Next time don't park it in the fire zone.
Schmuck.
Sub completely redone by zathras69