Kiss_the_Girls_(1997) ,WEB_MKV_H264(Paramount,Eng,Chi) 1280x544
CASANOVA: You want to know
all about me, don't you?
Well, let's see, now.
The first time I was in love
was June, 1975, in Boca Raton.
Her name was Coty Pierce.
She lived there with her parents
and her little sister Karrie...
And I loved her, too.
I loved them both...
and they were in love with me.
They just didn't know it.
No one did.
I lived with them all that June.
WOMAN: I don't understand.
CASANOVA: I lived in the attic.
I was watching.
I loved the expression
on their faces when they slept.
And then I decided
to declare myself...
and show them
how much they loved me.
WOMAN: What happened?
CASANOVA: What happened?
Coty was honored.
She kissed me back.
And then Karrie.
[Girl whimpers]
CASANOVA:
And finally that night...
I kissed their mother, too.
Just a little pinprick. There.
[Woman gasps]
WOMAN: Ohh.
Ohh.
CASANOVA: Kiss me.
ALEX: That's it.
Now watch and listen.
Good. Knock it back.
Knock it back.
Good, but you gotta remember......
this game is 80% wind, 20% talent.
You gotta keep running.
That's it. That's my boy.
Good. Bring it over.
Right hand. Good.
I don't want you to fall on your
face 'cause you missed that jab.
What am I always telling you?
Power comes from leverage
and technique.
You paying attention?
[Pager beeps]
I gotta go, guys...
so you pair off
and hit the heavy bag.
Three rounds each. Go.
How long has she been inside?
I'm on my way.
POLICEMAN: Their names are
Edmond and Dianne Wainford...
ages 48 and 42.
An item about 7 years.
No prior complaints.
The neighbors
are saying the usual.
They were divorced,
they were married...
they were separated,
they were reconciled...
or in the process of.
His idea or her idea.
No one has a clue.
All I know is that's Edmond,
and Dianne's in the bedroom.
ALEX: Whose gun?
MAN'S VOICE:
Stupid fucking bitch!
POLICEMAN: He had
a .38 Smith &Wesson registered.
Look like a .38 to you?
You want a vest?
I don't think I'll need one.
[Knocks on door]
Dianne.
This is Alex Cross, D.C.P.D.
I need to talk to you. OK?
Dianne, I'm gonna open the door.
All right?
I'm gonna open it now.
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Please. Please, Dianne.
Look, I'm gonna close this door.
I'm gonna move this chair
and block the door.
This way nobody comes in...
and it stays
between me and you, OK?
Could you take the gun
out of your mouth, please?
Look, it's just as effective
if you put it to your temple.
Just makes it easier to talk.
DIANNE:
What sort of policeman are you?
I'm a forensic psychologist.
It's a fancy way of saying...
I'm a guy who walks
into a room like that...
and determines
the hows and whys.
Then you don't need
to hear from me.
No, no, I don't,
but I need for you...
to confirm
a couple of things for me.
For instance, did Edmond
often beat you after he drank?
And the turtleneck
you're wearing...
is that to hide bruises?
Do you often have to hide marks
that he put on your body?
2 weeks ago...
he hit me...
and I swore
it was the last time.
I finally get the nerve
to leave that son of a bitch...
and then he suckers me back.
ALEX:
You know what I think, Dianne?
I think you did
what you had to do.
The thing now is to figure out
how to finish things off.
The right way, Dianne,
the right way.
Look, is it all right
if I come a little closer?
Thanks.
As I see it, we have to get
photographs of your bruises.
I know at least a half a dozen
top-notch lawyers.
They specialize
in battered women's defenses.
The point is, Dianne,
if you pull the trigger...
no one will ever know
the truth.
Can I have it?
Dianne.
ALEX: Samp. What are you
doing here? Doughnut raid?
SAMPSON: Alex, hold on.
Look, uh, May's inside.
Yeah?
- We got a call from Durham.
- Durham?
Naomi's missing. Come on.
ALEX:
What do you mean "missing"?
They called May this afternoon
from the law school.
She called me.
I called them back.
Told them who you were,
her uncle and all that.
They said
she's been missing for 4 days.
4 days? Christ.
But Durham police is on it now.
The guy I talked to
sounded solid.
MAY: Don't talk to him.
Talk to me.
They stole my child.
Now, May, just take it easy.
Take it easy.
We're gonna handle this
together...
but with your
high blood pressure...
I need you to relax
right now, OK?
- Yeah, but what if...
- Now, now, now.
ALEX: You just take it easy.
Relax and breathe.
Look at me.
I want to tell you something.
Do you remember when Naomi
was about 10 years old?
She got lost.
You got all frantic...
because you thought we'd
never find her. Remember?
Yeah.
You were worried she'd have
an asthma attack or something.
Remember that?
Turns out
she was with the neighbors...
and everything was just fine.
Well, everything
is gonna be fine now...
'cause I'm gonna
handle this myself, May.
You know
you can trust me, right?
You know I'm gonna handle this.
- I trust you.
- OK.
Nana's gonna take you
up to Janelle's room...
and you just relax for a while.
- I don't need to relax.
- May.
- Yeah.
ALEX: Good. All right.
ALEX:
I'll have to go down there.
SAMPSON:
Listen, Alex. Stay here.
Come on, John.
If they got a chance
to wrap it up down there...
how long do you think they'll
hunt for one lost black girl?
SAMPSON: Just stay here, man.
I'll go down there.
There's nothing
you can do anyway.
- It's out of your jurisdiction.
- You don't understand.
I got to go.
MEGAN: Please talk to me.
Talk to me the way you used to.
Please. Say something.
Please. I'm sorry.
I can be better. I can be good.
I won't be bad anymore.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Yes, I swear.
CASANOVA: You promise?
Yeah. I'll make you happy.
CASANOVA: How?
I promise. Let me show you.
CASANOVA: Tell me you love me.
Tell me you love me.
I love you.
CASANOVA:
Megan, I don't believe you.
I love you.
CASANOVA: Of course you do.
Aah!
ALEX: Good afternoon, Sergeant.
Dr. Alex Cross,
Washington, D.C.P.D.
I'd like to see
Chief Hatfield, please.
SERGEANT: The chief's tied up
at the moment.
We'll let him know you're here.
I'm sure he'll be with you...
as soon as he possibly can.
Take a load off.
Thank you.
RUSKIN: Dr. Cross.
You've been waiting for us
for a while.
ALEX: About 2 hours.
SKES: We got us
a laid back way down here.
ALEX: So I see.
RUSKIN: Good. Run these names
through the printer.
I'm sorry about the wait.
Nick Ruskin.
ALEX: Nick.
- Davey Sikes.
- Sikes.
RUSKIN:
It's been real busy 'round here.
We've had a homicide and not
your garden variety, either.
ALEX: Meaning?
RUSKIN: That's all I know.
We're heading out there now.
You can ride with us
if you like.
ALEX: The board shows
8 women missing.
How closely connected are they?
RUSKIN:
They all share the same profile.
All young, late teens,
early twenties...
pretty, all from inside
the research triangle...
and each of them was ambushed.
No witnesses.
Does his homework.
SKES: And then he ties 'em
naked to a tree...
and chops off their hair.
RUSKIN:
Only 2 bodies have been found.
This'll probably be the third.
And the killer left a note
at the second murder scene.
Signed it Casanova.
ALEX:
Casanova? The great lover.
SKES: Mm-hmm.
ALEX:
This one here, is she, uh...
she white, black, or...
SKES: All we know
is she's a young woman...
who didn't die happy.
SKES: Our chief Hatfield
will be up at the scene.
I'll bet you two will get along
like pigs in a blanket.
RUSKIN: Well, it's not her.
[Flies buzzing]
RUSKIN: Dr. Cross.
My boss, Chief Hatfield.
ALEX: Chief.
HATFIELD: Now, is it
Detective Cross or Dr. Cross...
or Dr. Detective Cross?
ALEX: At a time like this,
it really doesn't matter.
HATFIELD: As you see, It's not
your niece. I'm happy for you.
ALEX: Figured out who she is?
HATFIELD: Megan Murphy,
university sophomore.
I told your Captain Hathaway...
I'd extend help
any way we could...
given your special situation
and all.
ALEX: I appreciate that.
HATFIELD: I want you
to consider yourself my guest.
Make yourself at home...
but don't mess around
in the kitchen. Understand me?
KYLE: Well, the TV news crews
can't be far behind.
The best-selling crime author
has arrived.
ALEX:
Kyle, it's good to see you.
You, too.
I thought you were in Rochester.
Well, things change.
I see you're
making friends fast.
Well, doing my best.
I heard about your niece.
I'm sorry.
How long has this been
on the Bureau's wish list?
A while.
Were the other two
tied up so extravagantly?
Yeah. The guy seems
to find square knots tedious.
You saw it's Dayton cordage,
seven gauge.
Yeah. America's favorite.
I suppose everything else
was too prolific to trace.
Guy's a pro.
A real student of the game
and an enthusiastic rapist.
First two postmortems
indicate vaginal tears...
like I've seldom seen,
inflicted hours before death.
And then that's it.
No prints or fibers,
no semen or hair.
Except what he cut off her.
What about cause of death?
There are no signs of torture,
no weight loss, no drugging.
He just ties 'em up
and leaves 'em for the critters.
A real student of the game.
And he likes to play.
[Church bell rings]
RUSKIN: We've liasoned
with the campus police...
posted fliers.
Figure somebody out there had to
have seen something important.
ALEX:
An environment fit for blending.
For you, a security nightmare.
For him...paradise.
We're gonna get this animal.
DOCTOR: We've got a critically
injured eight-year-old girl...
thrown from a motorcycle.
No helmet.
She's gonna get a cat scan
as soon as you get her stable.
KATE: That's the third grade.
Why was she on a motorcycle?
Her daddy decided
to take her for a ride.
KATE: The pressure bandage
is about to go.
We're a minute away
from a 30-second bleed out.
I need a tourniquet.
- Retractors are ready.
- I'm gonna do a cut down.
- Watch your pressure drop.
- Scalpel, please, nurse.
KATE: Gauze and suture.
- What's her name?
- Laura.
That's an awful lot of blood
for such a little girl, Laura.
Try to put you
back together again.
[Speaking Chinese]
KATE:
Hi, Mrs. Lee. Dr. McTiernan.
MRS. LEE: Doctor. Hello.
KATE: She's alive.
[Speaking Chinese]
Wait. Mrs. Lee. Listen.
Laura has suffered
severe head trauma...
and she is in a coma.
[Speaking Chinese]
You can be with her
as soon as...
[Sobbing]
[Speaking Chinese]
WOMAN:
Please, let me see my baby.
[Rock music playing]
INSTRUCTOR:
I want to see the jab.
There you go. Good.
Now move around the ring.
Around the ring. Let's go.
Don't stay there. Back up.
Watch your contact.
[Buzzer]
OK, Barry off. You can stay on.
Who's next?
Kate, let's go.
KATE'S FRIEND: OK.
INSTRUCTOR: Go get him.
All right,
let's keep it light, guys.
Come on, Kate,
let's see something.
I want to see the jab.
Stick the jab in there.
There you go. Good.
Let me see the jab.
Come on, use the jab.
Nice! OK, good.
Let's go. Work it.
Come on. On your toes.
Ethan, what are you doing?
Watch your contact, OK?
Kate, are you OK?
KATE'S FRIEND: This is
a sorry substitute for sex.
I said this is
a sorry substitute...
- I heard you.
- Yeah, OK.
- You know what I'm looking for?
- Hmm?
The way my daddy
looked at my mother.
What way?
I can't settle
for anything less.
SKES:
Sure picks lookers, doesn't he?
ALEX: Yeah, he does.
But, you know, these women
are more than just attractive.
They're all extraordinary
in some way.
Smart, talented.
SKES: He ain't choosing them
just for their congeniality.
ALEX: Ordinarily, they don't...
but I think our guy
is a little different.
RUSKIN: How so?
ALEX: I think killing's
not his ulterior motive.
This guy's a collector.
I bet these women are alive.
SKES: Come on, doc.
Our boy's brain is soft
as a two-minute egg...
and nothing personal,
but I figure...
every one of them gals
is tied to a tree...
just waiting to get found.
ALEX: Think about it, Sikes.
The three you found
were killed out of sequence.
They weren't even among
the first abducted.
SKES: That's right.
RUSKIN: That don't mean
they're not still out there.
ALEX: But you would
have found them by now.
He makes absolutely
no attempt to hide 'em...
and the way they were killed,
very revealing.
That last long walk
through the woods.
KYLE: Marching to their fate.
ALEX: Exactly. The rape,
cutting off their hair.
KYLE: It's a punishment.
ALEX:
Maybe for violating some trust.
HATFIELD: What goddamn trust?
ALEX: I don't know, chief.
I don't know.
CLERK:
How would you like to pay?
KATE: Actually, there's
another book I'm interested in.
It's a picture book for children
in the hospital.
It's about being brave.
It sounds like a book by Burke.
I'll see if we have it in stock.
Good night, fish.
[Thunder]
[Creak]
[Trees scraping window]
[Thump]
[Scraping]
KATE: Aah! Aah!
Aah!
What do you want from me?
CASANOVA: Everything.
[Rap music playing]
SETH: Hit it, hit it, hit it.
What is that, man?
Give me the ball, baby.
This is my court.
Show you how we do it.
There it is.
OPPONENT:
Get mad, get mad. What's up?
MAN:
Come on, fellas. Back it off.
OPPONENT:
Don't ever come back again!
Don't ever come back here again!
It's my court!
ALEX: Seth Samuel?
I'm Dr. Alex Cross.
Naomi's uncle.
SETH: And a cop.
Look, I don't recall
inviting you here, so...
Can we talk for a minute or two?
Like I said, I don't recall
inviting you here.
Look...we can talk
anywhere you want.
I already told you guys
everything I know.
Which was nothing.
Look, I've had cops
on me for days.
In the middle of the night...
hauling me down to the station,
all up my ass about Naomi...
and things that are nobody's
fucking business.
Looks like your business
is in the public domain...
doesn't it, Seth?
What do you want to know?
I want to know
about Naomi's violin.
It's not on
the police inventory.
Is it here?
Well, she used to practice
here sometimes.
She was always practicing
on the thing...
but she always took it
home with her, always.
Yeah, I know.
The cops don't have any idea,
do they?
Not a clue.
[Groaning]
KATE: Unh...uhh.
CASANOVA:
I got all the glass out.
[Startled gasp]
CASANOVA:
Everything you'll need...
to change the dressing's
right next to you.
I brought
some of your clothes, too.
Something for every occasion.
Can you hear me?
Systemic analgesic...
What did you give me?
That's one of the reasons
I picked you, Kate.
- Your intelligence.
- Uhh.
I appreciate that.
I know most men don't, can't.
I'm different.
You'll see that in time.
Now try not to go back to sleep.
KATE: Aah! Aah!
- Shh.
- Aah! Oh, my God!
- Oh! Oh, my God!
- I need to tell you the rules.
CASANOVA: Shh, shh, shh.
Stop, stop, stop.
Why am I here?
CASANOVA: You're here to fall
in love, to experience love.
KATE: Uhh!
But now I need you
to listen very carefully...
and take what I say
very seriously, all right?
Don't try to escape.
Don't cry out for help.
And do not try any of
your kick-boxing tricks.
- Do you understand?
- Uh...
Now, I'll do what I can to help
you not break these rules...
but if you do,
you will really disappoint me.
That's it.
There.
See? That didn't hurt, did it?
Don't worry.
You're with Casanova.
MAN: Yes?
CASANOVA:
Thought you'd be out...busy.
MAN: Well, you were wrong.
CASANOVA: You've got mail.
You like?
MAN:
Nice. Exceptional. Really.
CASANOVA:
I think she's extra special.
SWIMMER:
How you feelin', old man?
COACH:
Swimmers, take your mark!
[Blows whistle]
COACH: Come on, keep to it.
Move those bodies. Let's go!
Kick it up! Move it!
Speed, speed! Muscle, muscle!
- Excuse me.
- Yeah.
I'm looking for Dr. Wick Sachs.
Uh, lane five.
He's, uh, destroying my varsity.
Thank you.
Sure. Let's go, blondie.
Pick it up!
SACHS: I can't tell you much
you don't already know.
I gave Naomi
some academic guidance...
which she politely disregarded,
and that was that.
Excuse me.
I really don't have time to get
to know my patients very well...
although I do know that Naomi...
was a special woman.
My heart goes out to you.
ALEX:
Word is that you make time...
to get to know
some of your special patients.
Whatever you may have heard,
I certainly don't have time...
to kidnap and mutilate
any of them.
I understand how you must feel,
you being a...psychologist...
and a policeman...
and her uncle.
It must be like suffering
the tortures of the damned.
For me or for her?
Well, both.
[Pager beeping]
It's yours.
ALEX: He's never made strikes
this close together, has he?
An intern, huh?
Yeah. He had a vacancy.
Out. Never call out.
Never call out.
Somebody help me.
My name is Kate!
I'm Kate McTiernan!
I'm a doctor at the Carolina
Regional Medical Center!
I need help!
I know you can hear me!
Come on! Who's out there?!
Somebody help...
My name is Kate McTiernan.
Somebody talk to me!
Who is out there?
YOUNG WOMAN: Be quiet.
Be quiet, or he'll kill you.
Oh, my God.
What's your name?
Talk to me, please,
please, please.
Tell me your name.
I'm Mary Jane Capaldi.
It's good to...it's good to hear
your voice, Mary Jane.
Are you OK?
SECOND WOMAN: I'm
Kristen Miles. I'm here, too.
THIRD WOMAN: Melissa Stanfield.
I don't know how long
I've been here.
What month is it?
FOURTH WOMAN:
I'm Samantha Gaines.
FIFTH WOMAN: Carol Akers.
My...my name is Naomi Cross.
I've been here for 8 days,
I think.
[Knock on door]
ALEX: Yeah, I know.
I miss you, too, darlin'.
No, you know I do.
How's Nan?
Well, that's good.
You stay with her, you hear?
Hang on, Janell. Just a second.
ELDERLY MAN: Aah! Oh! Jesus.
ALEX: I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
KYLE: "Odalisques
were the most valuable...
"of the emperor's treasures...
"gifted in the arts
of music and poetry." Talented.
ALEX: Special.
"Welcome to Durham, Dr. Cross.
"Giovanni Giacomo Casanova
de Seingalt."
Well, I guess you've got a fan.
RUSKIN:
I'll say one thing for our boy...
He's got very nice penmanship.
SKES: He's fuckin' with you,
that's all it is.
ALEX: Yeah, but this tells us
he's trackin' the case.
He's readin' the local papers.
We can use that.
RUSKIN: An odalisque, uh,
it's a statue, right?
A tall, pointy thing...
- You're thinking of obelisk.
- Oh.
ALEX:
Odalisque is a harem girl...
a concubine, sex slave.
RUSKIN: Oh, there it is,
just like you said.
SKES: So he's telling us
all these gals are alive.
- Mm-hmm.
- Why is he telling us that?
ALEX: Demonstrates his power,
his dominance.
KYLE: That certainly fits.
Our profiles
of the murdered women...
show they all shared
one trait...
that would have set off
the control freak in our guy.
They're all strong-willed.
They're all defiant.
SKES: How many of the other
girls share that profile?
ALEX: At least one.
KATE: You want to hurt me?
[Claps hands]
OK, come on.
They can be bigger...OK.
And they can be stronger...
Fuckin' nuts!
Knock me down.
[Breathing]
[Coughing]
[Retching]
Oh, my God.
CASANOVA: You could
have been the best, Kate.
I may be going crazy here...
but didn't I warn you
about breaking the rules?
- I'm sorry.
-"I'm sorry."
"I'm sorry."
- I'll do anything you want.
- What? What did you say?
I said I'll do
anything you want.
CASANOVA: Oh, I know you will.
Give me your arm.
I said, give me your arm.
Come on.
Give it to me.
CASANOVA: Kate!
Kate!
Aah!
[Casanova breathing]
CASANOVA: This is not the way
it works, Kate.
All right, now. OK.
Easy, girl. Easy, now.
Come on.
ALEX: What do you know?
RUSKIN: Only that
she's in some kind of shock.
The kids who found her...
were fishing near
the Wykagil White Water.
The what?
Wykagil,
it's a river way out of town.
SKES: Well, lookee here.
We got us a circus up ahead.
[Siren]
REPORTER: Here he comes.
Detectives, can you confirm...
[All speaking at once]
DR. RUOCCO: What concerns us
is behavior...
that suggests psychological
trauma, especially acute...
HATFIELD: Doctor, doctor,
can you tell us exactly when...
she'll be able to talk to us?
What I'm getting at
is Kate McTiernan...
appears to be suffering
from posttraumatic shock.
There's no telling
when she'll be lucid.
It could be hours or weeks.
You guys have to remember...
that this girl
is very lucky to be alive.
POLICEMAN: Can you at least
tell us your best guess?
SECOND POLICEMAN:
We can't go on that, doc.
KATE: Dr. Ruocco. Excuse me.
My name is Cross.
I'm Dr. Alex Cross.
Yes, I know who you are.
I know your work.
I'm consulting with
the local police on this case.
I need to see Kate McTiernan.
I'm sorry, but she does not
need another doctor.
Listen, the last thing
I want is to crowd you.
My request is personal.
One of the women
abducted was my niece.
I really need to talk
to this woman.
[Beep beep beep]
[Monitor beeping]
ALEX: It's all right.
It's all right.
You're safe now. You're safe.
ALEX: This woman's a fighter.
DR. RUOCCO:
I wouldn't argue with that...
but we were off pegging this
as posttraumatic shock.
Her vitals
are meandering downhill.
Everything is
systematically shutting down.
And, of course,
you screened her for drugs?
Yes, we did.
Her blood, her urine...
they're clean.
Something is doing damage
that we don't have a finger on.
- Whoever did this...
- Is cunning.
Yeah, he's cunning,
but he doesn't know his history.
Hmm?
The real Casanova
would never have approved.
ALEX: Excuse me.
Do you have a P.D.R.?
NURSE: Mm-hmm.
ALEX: Nonresponsive pupils...
progressive loss of muscular
control, escalating tremors...
DR. RUOCCO: That's what I see.
ALEX: An overdose of
Benzodiazepine would do that.
DR. RUOCOO: Yes, but every drug
in the Benzo family...
shows up in blood and urine.
ALEX: Ah, except Sistol.
It's a Benzo cousin.
Leukemia specialists are using
it to take the edge off chemo.
- Is it an amnesiac?
- Absolutely.
[Monitor beeping]
We'll see what your theory
is made of by morning.
[Monitor beeping slower]
KATE: Mmm.
Who are you?
ALEX: Um...
My name is Alex Cross.
I'm a policeman
from Washington, D.C.
How do you feel?
Sick.
- I'll get you a doctor.
- Wait.
Wait. I was given a drug.
I think it was
a nervous system...
Yeah. It was
something called Sistol...
but we flushed it out of you.
It's nice to have you back.
- Washington?
- Yeah. I'm, uh...
I'm down here
because of my niece.
She disappeared
about 10 days ago.
Her name is Naomi Cross.
I talked to her.
ALEX: Thank you.
I'll get that doctor for you.
I heard...l heard...
so many different voices...
and I tried not to cry.
SKES: No way does our boy
show his face here.
ALEX: If he's not here,
he's watching. I guarantee you.
You make it sound like he ain't
cooking on the front burner.
If he's so dumb, how come
we haven't caught him yet?
HATFIELD: Ladies and gentlemen.
Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen.
I'd like to introduce to you
a very brave young lady...
Dr. Kate McTiernan.
Dr. McTiernan will make
a brief statement...
and that's all.
No questions, please.
Hello, I'm Kate McTiernan.
First...I'd like
to say something to...
the families who have
a loved one missing.
Please, do not give up hope.
There are other women
where I was held...
and I believe in my heart
that they're still alive.
Second...to the boys who
fished me out of the river...
and saved my life...
and to the nurses
and doctors here...
who are taking
such excellent care of me...
and for the thousands
of letters and prayers...
I've received from
all across America...thank you.
And last...
to the man...
who calls himself Casanova...
the man who took me
from my own home...
and ultimately
tried to kill me...
I broke your rules...just me.
None of the other women helped.
So if you're looking
for someone to blame, blame me.
That's all I have
to say right now.
Thank you
for taking my message...
to the families
of the missing...
and I hope it helps
a little bit.
Thank you.
[Reporters asking questions
simultaneously]
ALEX: What do you hear? Dogs?
KATE: No.
ALEX: Any kind of animals?
Is it a farm?
KATE: I don't know.
- Do you hear the river?
- No.
I hear him...whispering.
What does he say?
I can feel...his mouth
on my ear, his breath.
He tells me that he loves me.
ALEX: Tell me about his face.
Tell me about his eyes,
his mouth.
He has no face.
[Gasps]
A mask.
He always wears a mask.
- What kind of mask?
- I can't...
- What does it look like?
- It changes.
I can't show him
that I hate him.
[Screams]
But you escape.
What do you see when you escape?
I don't know.
I'm just running...
and my legs are heavy
from the drugs.
And then I'm lost.
I'm running through hallways...
and there are all these rooms,
and I don't know where to turn.
[Screams]
- He's behind me.
- He's not behind you, Kate.
You get away.
- How? How do you get out?
- Light.
Light.
The light and the sun.
- Do you see a barn?
- No.
- A house?
- Cabin?
- No.
There's nothing.
Just the light.
It hurts my eyes. And...
And then the trees...
the trees again.
And the rocks
are digging into my feet.
And I hear him
shouting behind me.
And I try to run faster.
That's all I'm thinking...
just run faster!
l...l left those girls behind.
I wasn't thinking.
I just told myself
to run, to run and run.
ALEX: It's all right. It's OK.
It's all right.
I left those girls.
ALEX: It's all right.
It's all behind you.
[Playing classical piece]
ALEX: Are you pretty
familiar with these woods?
SETH: Yeah.
I come up here sometimes.
ALEX:
What do you run into up here?
Besides the obvious...
hikers, bikers, campers.
SETH: Locals, college kids...
that's about it.
- What about this river?
- It's good for trout fishing.
It's been that way since
the early colonial period.
It's over here.
What? What?
ALEX: Guess I'll have
to remember that my niece...
wouldn't be fooling around
with some knucklehead.
SETH: Right.
ALEX: Kate. You OK?
KATE: I'm fine.
Really, I am. I'm fine.
I'm just sorry
I can't take you to her.
ALEX: I made an interesting
discovery last night.
KATE: About what?
ALEX: I ran a check on
all the Sistol orders...
over the last five years.
- Guess what?
- What?
ALEX: A Beverly Hills plastic
surgeon came up on the list.
KATE: There's no protocol
for Sistol in plastic surgery.
ALEX: Bingo.
Two years ago,
this guy ordered enough...
to treat leukemia
in a medium-sized country.
KATE: What's his name?
ALEX:
Rudolph. William Rudolph.
Grew up in Durham.
Did his premed work here.
Dr. Cross, is it him?
Is he bicoastal?
ALEX: Bicoastal.
That's an interesting way
of putting it.
There are a dozen predators
operating in California now.
There's one...male Caucasian...
probably early thirties.
He's known as
the Gentleman Caller.
They've been onto him
for over a year.
And what I realized
last night...
was that his abductions
follow the ones here...
by about 10 days to two weeks.
Matter of fact...
it was exactly 10 days
after Naomi disappeared...
that a pretty black coed
disappeared from UCLA.
So he's doing it there, too.
ALEX: Compulsively. And if
he follows true to form...
he's due to hit California
pretty quick.
Can the FBI pick him up?
If I give Rudolph to the FBI
and they make one mistake...
what happens to all these girls?
I can't risk Naomi starving
to death in a cell somewhere.
No FBI.
You're going out there
on your own.
ALEX: I got people.
Take me with you.
I think you're best served
by staying here.
And pretend like
nothing's happened?
No. That's not
what I was going to say.
I just think
you should be trying...
I'm the only person
who's seen this guy.
I know his size, his voice,
I know the way he moves...
ALEX:
I know how you feel, honestly.
KATE: Would you please stop
treating me like I'm a victim?
You think I'm some kind
of tourist in all this...
because I wasn't raped?
Every night when I go
to sleep...
I hear those women's voices.
You want to save your niece?
Well, guess what? So do I.
ALEX: Ought to see my cousin.
SAMPSON: Alex!
- There he is.
- Hey, hey.
ALEX:
Kate McTiernan, John Sampson.
DCPD, cousin,
compadre extraordinaire.
- How do you do?
- Hello, Kate.
SAMPSON:
Meet Henry Castillo, LAPD.
- Nice to meet you.
- Pleasure.
- It is a pleasure.
- Mine, Henry.
SAMPSON: Alex, can we huddle?
ALEX: Excuse me, Kate.
SAMPSON:
Well, this is a surprise.
ALEX: Time was surprises
made you giddy, John.
What's the matter?
SAMPSON:
Look, we're out on a limb here.
I've pulled every string.
I've called in
10 years of favors...
to get those cars and equipment.
This thing has got to go
as smooth as silk...
or we are both fucked.
ALEX: Understood.
I got him, 10:48 a.m,
crossing the north window.
Attention.
Rudolph just walked past
the window.
Thank you for the update.
It's him.
He's on the move.
This does not look
like a 7-Eleven run.
Where does this road go?
Vancouver.
He sounded so sincere.
How's that?
When he told me that he loved me.
I expect that's because he does.
Please.
Multiply your anger
by about a hundred, Kate.
That's how much
he thinks he loves you.
OK. Rudolph has landed.
There's a cabin
about a half mile in.
So he hasn't traveled
that far after all.
He's back in the woods.
HENRY:
First time in California?
It's a pretty state, isn't it?
KATE: It's unforgettable.
RUDOLPH: What's wrong? Huh?!
Go ahead! What?!
I can't hear you!
Don't tell me!
No! Shut up!
Because you said!
SAMPSON:
What the fuck is he doing?
[Glass shatters]
[Yelling]
He's in a rage.
He's going fucking nuts.
He's about to scare the wildlife
out of this forest.
SAMPSON: Do you see him?
RUDOLPH: What?
RUDOLPH: Piece of...
[Muttering]
[Door slams]
KATE: Tell me...
what did you see back there?
A killer getting organized.
KATE: He's not going to abduct
somebody from this place.
HENRY: This guy's pulled people
out of these joints before.
KATE: Not in the triangle.
ALEX: We'll cover him loose,
see what he's got.
Henry, you stay here.
KATE: If it's so crowded,
how come I can't come?
ALEX: If he even thinks
he sees you, it's over.
What about you?
20 years of experience
blending in.
You stay with Henry.
[Loud dance music playing]
ALEX: There he is...
across the bar.
SAMPSON: Damn, he's in there.
Just like that.
Mr. Lover Lover.
We ought to nail his ass
right now.
HENRY: It's never been the same
without Fernando.
I can't believe
those guys let him go.
Unbelievable, man.
He had this knuckle ball.
It was like a floater.
Then bam !
Right off the table.
Couldn't even come near it.
You were kidding yourself.
What do you got down there?
The Durham Bulls?
Right? Triple "A"?
Got any prospects?
EDF 40, full military specs.
KATE: I'm gonna go in.
What? Hey. Hold on.
- Come here, you.
- I got to pee.
HENRY: No. You don't.
I'm not that stupid.
KATE:
It's not really your style.
HENRY:
You don't know what my style is.
KATE: Your style
is to help me blend in.
Henry, help me blend in.
Come on.
HENRY: All right.
Right here, right here.
OK, I am going to walk over
and find our boys, all right?
You shall stay right here.
KATE: Mm-hmm.
HENRY: You won't move.
Wonderful.
Hey.
Kate.
Is that him?
Is that Rudolph?
ALEX: Yeah. Yeah, that's him.
It's him.
ALEX: Are you sure?
Yeah.
- Come on.
- OK.
ALEX: Stand still.
ALEX: Follow the tree line
to the drive.
Henry, you break left.
You and I will take the front.
Now, guys, remember,
when it goes down...
I need this guy intact.
KATE: Alex.
Be careful.
WOMAN: Aah!
[Woman screaming]
[Glass shatters]
WOMAN: Help me.
Help.
ALEX: Go.
- Uhh!
- Aah!
[Woman sobbing]
SAMPSON:
It's OK. It's OK, it's OK.
Ohh!
SAMPSON:
Oh, shit. Henry. He's hit.
[Engine revs]
ALEX: Come on, come on.
SAMPSON: Just take it easy.
[Groans]
Hold it! Hold it!
Put your hands
where I can see them !
Get out of the truck.
Get out of the truck!
PARAMEDIC: Yeah, roger.
We're ready to transport.
[Sampson sighs]
ALEX: How is he?
I'm sorry, Sam.
For all this, I'm sorry.
REPORTER: Yes, shocking is
an accurate way to describe...
what went on here
in the early morning hours.
Local police won't comment,
but channel 6 sources...
tell us what happened here
in the pre-dawn hours...
KATE: Does this hurt?
REPORTER:
...reaches beyond California...
and some say involves
a rogue branch of the FBI...
They sure can document a fuckup
at the speed of light.
KATE: I guarantee you won't
be seeing a picture...
of that woman
whose life you saved on TV.
OK, breathe in.
How's this?
[Groans]
A little tender there.
What about here?
[Groans]
We need x-rays.
Not a chance.
ALEX: Gone in the night.
KATE: At least now the FBI
know who they're looking for.
How far can he run?
ALEX:
It's not a question of how far.
It's how long.
...Questions and receiving
very few answers.
Questioned on the scene,
Detective John Sampson...
whom we've learned
is about 3,000 miles...
KATE: What do you want to do?
REPORTER: Sampson is
a detective in good standing...
with the Washington, D.C.
police department.
Local police tell us...
Sampson was part of
a rag-tag surveillance team.
Sampson, Detective Castillo...
and two other unidentified
individuals were on a stakeout.
But staking out whom or what?
Property records indicate
the cabin owner is...
KATE: I'd like to see about
making reservations...
from Los Angeles
to Raleigh-Durham.
REPORTER: ...was Dr. Rudolph,
a man with no criminal record.
KATE: It's the return portion...
ALEX: Hang up the phone, Kate.
KATE: Pardon me?
Hang up the phone.
CRAIG: Dr. McTiernan...
welcome to our crime scene.
The sight of yellow tape
and flash bulbs...
must be getting a little old
to you by now.
- A little.
- You got here quick.
CRAIG: Not quick enough.
ALEX: Now wait a minute, Kyle.
Let's not downplay
the upside of this.
- Upside?
- Yeah.
She ID'd Casanova.
You got a trail.
Alex, don't even try.
It's bad form.
The day you set foot
in Durham...
I feel like you've been
screwing me around.
Look, I let you in.
I shared information.
What have we got? A mess.
And a cop who's looking
at two years of rehab.
Kyle, do you want me
to say I fucked up?
All right. I fucked up.
Just...don't shut me
out of this.
ALEX: What do you see?
KATE:
Maybe I'm looking too hard.
ALEX: For what?
I don't know.
It seems so cold.
Not like him.
CRAIG: Alex.
Keep looking.
CRAIG: Thought the closet
looked a little tight...
so I brought in
a DX fluoroscope...
scanned what appeared
to be a lunar module.
It's a freezer.
ALEX: A trophy case.
CRAIG:
Guy's got divergent MOs.
Don Juan on the east coast.
Joseph Mengele on the west.
- We found feet.
- What?
You heard me. Surgically
band-sawed at the ankle.
Vacuum-bagged, 15 pair.
2 lefts. Go figure.
Obviously not a dancer.
Check out the shrine.
Gentleman Caller...Casanova.
There hasn't been a true
multi-territorial predator...
since Jean de Salle, 1921...
eviscerating
Paris prostitutes...
and strangling widows
on the Riviera.
And running
a bicoastal operation.
This is
the most ambitious stunt...
in the annals
of serial pathology.
This guy is Houdini squared.
ALEX: Put on the brakes now.
We're not dealing
with Houdini here.
What we have here
is Leopold and Loeb.
Home team...visitors.
We got 30 ampules
of Sistol here.
The chronologies match.
There are two of them...
and they're collaborating.
Collaborating and competing.
ALEX: Got an ID on him?
It's probably just some kid
Rudolph did 20 years ago.
Comb through Missing Persons,
we'll find him there.
- Don't bother.
- You know who he is.
Mm-hmm.
And he's got both his feet.
[Sirens]
HATFIELD: I'm giving you
three minutes to throw the bolt.
Am I wasting my time?
OK, boys. Nobody home.
You all take upstairs now.
- Yes, sir.
- Be clean, boys.
Clean and thorough.
Keep the goddamn media out.
[Drills whirring]
Nick, you got the chief there?
CRAIG: Alex.
ALEX:
How long has he been in the box?
KYLE: Five hours. They took
him in the middle of a class.
ALEX: This is bullshit!
CRAIG: You know
I wouldn't sanction this.
Hatfield got the tip.
I don't know how.
Stages a huge public arrest.
By the time I'm on the ground,
he's already got this guy...
ALEX: You haul in $2 million
of surveillance equipment...
and these clowns stage
a cold arrest?
That is top-notch police work.
- This is all politics.
- It's all bad, Kyle.
CRAIG: Not all.
ALEX: Dr. Sachs.
It's good to see you again...
circumstances notwithstanding.
Can l, uh...
Can I get you anything?
Coffee? Soda?
Oh, come on, Wick.
There's some questions
you can answer without a lawyer.
For instance,
you might have said...
"Yes, thank you.
I will have coffee,"
or "No, thank you."
You know, just to be polite.
But you don't drink coffee,
do you?
You probably stick
to bottled water.
OFFICER:
What the hell's he doing?
ALEX: That's how
you stay in fighting trim.
CRAIG: He's doing what he does.
Where's the best bottled water
in the world come from?
The Alps?
Some French aquifer?
SACHS: Futican.
ALEX: Sorry?
SACHS: Fu-ti-can.
It's Japanese.
You wouldn't know it.
It's in the Japanese character
to do this sort of thing.
They build
these special ships...
and sail them to the farthest
navigable extremes...
and look for the bluest
iceberg they can find...
and they tow it back.
And one is able
to drink something...
that was last in liquid form
about 30,000 years ago.
ALEX: Expensively clean.
What does it taste like?
SACHS: Like water.
By the by, Alex...
writing a bestseller?
You must be a millionaire.
ALEX: No. Far from it.
SACHS: I bring it up only
because I mean to sue you...
along with these
other local imbeciles.
For what?
Defamation of character?
I like to fuck...
variously fuck...young women.
I have fucked nearly
100 of them in 75 ways...
but I have never hurt
any of them.
There's no record of violence
anywhere in my past.
Megan Murphy.
Oh, yeah.
This is a painstaking
recreation of an image...
from Friedrick Thelen's
Die Welt der Flagellanten.
Do you know it?
It took me 3 hours
to tie her up properly.
And consensually, by the way.
Dr. Cross, tell me
you have more than this.
I have pictures of Megan
tied to a tree.
No.
I was thinking
we'd discuss that at the trial.
In, say, six months?
Maybe you'd like me to go
on record now about Naomi.
I'll start with
the first time I saw her.
In my office.
She was wearing a silk blouse,
which pleases me...
because I like to turn up
the air conditioning...
to constrict the capillaries.
You know, tweak the nipples.
You should have seen
how self-conscious she was...
how nervous
the chill in the air made her.
And, like the others, her manner
belied her real predilections.
Which reminds me, Dr. Cross...
have you seen
the photographs of Naomi?
CRAIG: Alex!
Alex!
Hey! Hey! Back up!
Move! Move!
Unh!
RUSKIN:
Dr. Cross, put your hands down!
All right, settle down.
Settle down, all right?
Everything's all right.
[Coughing]
Naomi...
well, you're just as
pretty as your picture.
Beautiful feet.
ALEX ON TAPE:
What did you hear? Dogs?
Near the river?
KATE: No...
I hear him...whispering.
ALEX: What does he say?
KATE:
I can feel his mouth on my ear.
[Door unlocks]
KATE: I take it
we didn't get our confession.
ALEX:
We didn't. He's not Casanova.
His picture was on the wall.
ALEX:
That's part of their thing.
- But his picture...
- Kate, it's a setup.
Brothers in arms,
watching each other's backs.
Wick Sachs
is a perfect patsy for them.
He's too smug and too vain
to even know what hit him.
He's just a bush-league lech.
The cops think
they got the right guy.
I've been listening
to the tape.
ALEX: Yeah?
Have you ever heard
a fetal sonogram?
An ultrasound?
You know on the tape you
asked me if I heard anything.
ALEX: Yeah. You said nothing.
That's not true.
I heard something.
It was in the background.
It was constant.
I heard water.
- Water?
- Everywhere.
Below me, above,
around, everywhere.
I had to have been
in a basement.
Not possible.
Every farmhouse, barn, outhouse,
chickenhouse, doghouse...
the FBI checked everything out.
They missed it.
I saw the aerial photographs.
They didn't miss an inch.
There were doors,
there were walls...
there were stairs.
It was manmade. It was built.
When you escaped, you had
no recollection of a house.
You said there was light.
"Suddenly, there was light."
And I had been in a house.
Alex, I am sure of it.
OK, here's what
we're looking for.
A plantation layout.
See, now, there weren't
plantations on the Wykagil.
There was a plantation.
ALEX: What?
SETH: Check it out.
All this is Mason's property.
Now, this is hundreds of acres.
Here's the big house,
slave quarters, stables...
cellars for stashing food,
ice, tunnels everywhere.
ALEX: Can I see this?
ALEX:
River runs right through it.
KATE: Where was I found?
SETH: Around here. Two miles
down from the big house.
ALEX: OK.
Figure that's about
a thousand yards, right?
Forget here. Forget here.
This square.
That's where we concentrate.
[Violin playing]
No!
Bach is crisp.
Crisp.
[Footsteps]
Buon giorno, fratello.
This is quite a collection
you've assembled here.
Your palette
is so...multi-cultural.
That's very P.C.
I applaud you.
But this place is a little
overdone, don't you think?
Subterranean gothic went out
a while ago, didn't it?
You ought
to get yourself a maid.
You know what this shit is?
This is Civil War bat guano.
It's full of fungus.
You inhale
enough of this stuff...
you'll have a prostate
like a 70 year old.
What about you girls?
Any complaints?
Any muscle aches? Lesions?
Malaise?
Come on...
don't you think they'd
be better off in a freezer?
CASANOVA:
You know this is off-limits.
Nobody tracked me.
Just like your cabin
in the woods, right?
I'm not the one who made
all the phone calls.
I wasn't posting fucking
photographs on the Web.
CASANOVA: That's not
how they found you, Will...
or they would have found me.
You don't belong here.
If you're here, I'm here.
RUDOLPH:
I need you to help me.
I only want what I'd give you.
CASANOVA: You gave me nothing!
Remember '75?
Roe Tierney, homecoming queen.
Blood on the walls.
I cleaned up your slop.
I always do.
Face it, Will,
I'm your mentor...
and you're the bad seed.
RUDOLPH: Let me tell you
something, my friend...
no matter
how far out there you go...
no matter how you dress up...
when you come back...
you're still just like me.
RUDOLPH: Naomi,
let's hear something triumphal.
Something worthy of rebirth.
Play something for me.
Play!
CASANOVA: No!
She plays for me.
RUDOLPH:
She only plays for you?
Well, of course she does!
Because you are the great lover!
The dark figure of her dreams!
Come on, darling.
Tell him.
Tell him how grateful you are.
Tell him how you always
wanted to be his.
Go on. Tell him.
Tell him how you wait for him.
Tell him how
he's the most sensitive...
the best you ever had.
Tell him that you love him.
[Gun cocks]
That's what he wants to hear.
[Gunshot]
CASANOVA: I could have
aimed two inches to the left.
RUDOLPH:
Don't forget who we are...
and who you'll be if I'm gone.
You could have
a hundred women here...
but without me,
you'd still be alone.
CASANOVA: Take the stairs.
CASANOVA: Go on! Go!
Police! Freeze!
Hold it!
Aah!
- Naomi?
- Alex?
- I'll be back.
- No, don't go!
I'll be back.
KATE: Alex!
ALEX:
I found them ! Up the hill!
[Honk honking]
[Car approaches]
- Yahoo!
- Ha ha ha!
[Gunshots]
MAN: Aah!
William...
who is he?
Tell me his name.
RUDOLPH: He's too good.
You won't...
[Helicopter]
[Sirens]
CRAIG:
I'm waiting for the good news.
AGENT: It keeps getting better.
Come on.
This is Casanova's next crop,
blueprinted to a "T."
And we're in luck.
He didn't wear gloves.
CRAIG: Yes.
Yes, yes, yes.
OK, I want all this stuff
to Quantico now.
If you can't find a plane,
buy one.
REPORTER: Dr. Cross!
The man that you shot...
SECOND REPORTER:
...Sex slaves in L.A...
THIRD REPORTER: How did
Casanova escape without a trace?
You got company.
ALEX: Good to see you, Seth.
SETH: Thank you.
ALEX: Hey, you.
NAOMl: Hi.
ALEX: You OK?
NAOMl: Mm-hmm.
ALEX: Got something for you.
Ta-da!
NAOMl:
What happened to the strings?
ALEX:
New strings for new music.
Thank you.
- When's her mom coming down?
- In the morning.
KATE: When are you heading out?
ALEX: The bureau thinks...
they'll have Casanova
ID'd within 12 hours...
which really means 24.
As soon as Kyle gets a bead
on him, though, he's done...
no matter how much road
he's burned.
After that, I'm out of here.
KATE: So then that's it?
I only have you for another day.
All right. Supper at my house.
Home-cooked.
I promised Naomi
I'd meet her at 8:30.
I'll make a lousy date.
Do whatever you gotta do.
Be at my house by 7:00,
you'll be gone by 8:15.
Hey.
RUSKIN: If you would just
verify and sign there.
Ten shots fired...
and one W. Rudolph,
room temperature.
Good luck to you, Alex.
You, too.
Take care of yourself.
CRAIG: As you already know,
the hostages are now safe...
and are being cared for
at Carolina Regional Medical.
As for the forensics team...
they include our very best...
specialists in latent prints...
fiber and hair study...
serology, and DNA analysis.
We're very encouraged
by their progress.
In less than two hours,
over six...
[Music plays]
KATE: Yeah, it feels...
it feels really good.
It's not exactly normal.
I think that'll take some time.
It's different, but it's nice.
It's like getting acquainted
with an old friend.
ALEX: Are those Rottweilers
of yours out there on the case?
KATE: Well, I'm tempted
to yank your chain...
but they're out there,
standing post.
Is that what you call it?
ALEX: [Chuckles] Yeah.
Thanks for indulging me.
I'll see you soon.
OK. Bye.
You got to live
For yourself
Yourself and nobody else
You've got to live
For yourself
Well, look who's here.
[Doorbell rings]
KATE: Hi, Detective.
RUSKIN:
Hi. Sorry to bother you.
I brought this
from the property clerk.
I'm sorry. Would you like
to come in for a minute?
May I get you
something to drink?
No, thanks. Uh...
The next shift won't be here
for an hour or so...
[Telephone rings]
I really ought to wait
for them out here.
Excuse me for just a minute.
Don't go, OK?
Hello? Hi, Jen.
Son of a bitch.
Quit hovering. Come on in.
No, I'm not talking to you.
I've got company.
Can I call you back?
Bye.
How do you feel
about Indian food?
Oh, please, I don't want you
to trouble yourself.
KATE: I could use
some help cooking...
and I have enough food
for an army.
Would you like a glass of wine?
RUSKIN:
No, thank you. I'm on duty.
KATE: Your first chore is to slice
mushrooms. Can you do that?
RUSKIN:
I believe I can do that.
KATE: If you don't mind,
rinse them first.
Come on.
KATE: Use a colander.
That way'll take forever.
It's down on the...
[Ring]
ALEX: Oh, shit.
RUSKIN:
How are you feeling, by the way?
You feeling like you're
getting back on your feet?
KATE: I guess
if I felt solid anywhere...
it should be in this house.
I've been in it in one way
or another my whole life.
It was my great-aunt's.
But I don't know.
It's just different now.
Something's off.
KATE: I used to walk
in the middle of the night...
down to the corner market
for a quart of milk.
RUSKIN: That's true.
I mean, people just get
complacent. It happens.
Would you please hand me
the big chopping knife?
RUSKIN: The department
gives courses on self-defense.
KATE: I've been thinking about
spending more time at the dojo.
RUSKIN: Kick boxing's fine,
but that's not what I mean.
I'm talking prevention.
We teach things like, uh...
varying your routine.
Keeping your lights on at night.
Maybe getting a dog.
I'm sorry.
Does this bother you?
KATE:
It's good. I need to hear it.
Just simple things, like, um...
carrying personal alarms.
Taking your garbage out
the morning of.
Not using cordless phones.
Anyone with a scanner
can listen in.
KATE: What does taking your
garbage out the morning of...
have to do with anything?
RUSKIN: Night before,
anyone can tear through it.
KATE: Who in the world possibly
cares how much tuna I eat?
Would you rinse this
off for me, please?
RUSKIN: Think about it.
A guy could come by, say...
Tuesday night,
3:00 in the morning...
dump your trash in one of
those 30-gallon plastic sacks.
Haul it down
to an abandoned lot and bingo!
- There it is.
- Thank you.
What a lady eats,
how often she shaves.
He can even tell
a lady's time of the month.
Anything you want to know.
What kind of lipstick
she wears...
and used condoms.
How often's she gettin' it?
Twice a week?
Three times?
The same guy, different guys?
[Losing accent] Of course,
that doesn't apply to you.
Let's face it. In your case,
it's been quite a while.
Not since that...
that surgeon...
What? Six, seven months ago?
You were special, Kate.
[Whimpers]
Do you have any idea
how much time I gave you?
Months.
Yes, months.
I sacrificed for you...
but now I'm going
to show you sacrifice.
What are you going to do?
Are you going to cut me?
Do it!
Good girl.
Sometimes I live
in the country, baby
Sometimes I live in town
Sometimes
I take a strange notion
To jump in the river
and drown
Irene, good night
Good night, Irene,
good night
KATE: Aah!
I'll see you in my dreams
RUSKIN: Now I'll show you.
Sing, everybody
Irene, good night
Good night, Irene,
good night
Aah!
I'll see you in my dreams
[Gas hissing]
Unh...
[Gun cocks]
Don't do it, Nick.
Alex.
ALEX: Let's talk about it, OK?
You want to put
the lighter down, Nick?
Please?
She has to know.
She knows, Nick.
Then why don't you shoot me?
[Gas hissing]
Ah, I don't think so.
Muzzle flare, room full of gas,
all that, you know?
Look, Nick...
I'm gonna put the gun down.
Look, see?
There now. How's that?
I want you
to think about this, Nick.
If you do this,
no one will ever understand.
Oh, don't mind-fuck me!
No, I'm not, Nick.
See, Kate?
It's all about building rapport.
You use the subject's
first name...
and your tone...
you gotta keep it soft...
and steady.
ALEX:
Establish eye contact...
seek his level.
RUSKIN: You want to know
the truth, Alex?
You're the one
who really needs help.
Well, enlighten me, Nick.
Tell me what truth is.
Truth is looking
at a beautiful woman...
like our Kate here...
and saying to yourself...
"l gotta have that.
"l gotta break her down."
It's your basest animal self.
Dig deep, Alex.
You'll recognize him.
He's ugly.
ALEX:
I've run into him now and then.
Go ahead.
Reach for the Glock
and take me down...
before I tell you about
the 10 days I spent with Naomi.
10 days, Doc...
things she'd never tell you.
My brown sugar...
face like an angel...
perfect...
every inch of her.
You never knew Naomi.
Not like I did.
Deep down...
you envy me that.
Say it.
I don't work like you.
I don't...hate.
You only wish
you had the courage.
[Whispering] Good night...
Sweet Kate.
Kate...
it's all right, Kate.