Hello
Tessa!
Yes.
l'm on my way home.
ls it okay if l call?
No.
l will call you back once l reach.
Okay.
l love you for what you did.
And l mean it.
Thank you dear.
Bye.
She is Tessa.K.Abraham.
22 years old.
One among several girls from Kottayam
who aim at a nursing job abroad.
''ls crystal....your body
is a shining crystal..''
''Crystal which is hotter
than burning sunlight..''
''You are a flower, a girl
dripping with honey..''
''Enthralling beetles
who hover around..''
''Breeze from a sandal
forest is coming''
''And cover your flower like body..''
''A star appeared on
the sky to watch you..''
''ls crystal...on which
golden sunlight shines?''
''ls a stone..a stone on the nose
stud which is as bright as moon..''
''Colorful butterflies in a
forest of magnolias...''
''You are searching for honey in
the songs which are sung..''
''A rainbow has descended
from sky to embrace you..''
''ls crystal...on which
golden sunlight shines?''
''ls a stone..a stone on the nose
stud which is as bright as moon..''
You have got good marks,
good experience...
Even then, why haven't you got a visa?
Why?
ln your passport it is Tessa Abraham..
in certificates Tessa. K. Abraham..
ln some other cases,
only one 's' for Tessa.
Why is like this?
A smile like this won't do.
First all these complications
need to be cleared.
Then these papers are to be resubmitted.
Aren't you from Kottayam?
- Yes.
Who all are there as relatives?
To go to Trivandrum to
get these things cleared.
l have a younger sister..
but she is in Ernakulam.
No one else there...
Okay, let's try.
But you have to pay us.
That doesn't matter.
Tea.
Have tea.
Thanks.
Sadanandan...
- Yes.
You donkey..
- What? - This is coffee.
Oh! This is coffee, right?
Get out.
- Ohhh!
l am Cyril.
lf need be, they will call
you from the office.
You need to come here then only.
Okay.
Thank you.
Will be there they after. Got a
surprise for you. - Tissa Mol.
l am so sorry sir.
So you are a nurse?
Yes sir.
Very nice.
l had been in Kerala for 10 years.
l don't want any apologies.
What's your name?
Tessa.
Bye.
Oh God! l'm so hungry.
Where the hell is she?
She will come.
DK...From Monday l have nigh shift.
- l know that.
Go.
l will go once you go in.
Good night.
Bye.
She has come.
Come.
Got chicken?
Yes there is.
Give me that.
My visa is ready.
Really?
- Yes.
l have to go next month.
lt's good news.
Then l didn't heed for anything.
Called DK and went for a shopping.
l didn't get those sandals.
But..
How is these?
Great!
Hello.
How is these?
My visa processing is still in trouble.
ls it?
- Yes.
Some complications with the name.
You can tell DK...He will
help you to clear everything.
He has a special interest
in your affairs.
Stop your crap.
Why?
God won't give all the
blessings to one person.
My life has become
a hell in this hospital.
But one won't feel like
that from the way you eat.
Girl..
You are not supposed to toil here.
You marry me.
l will die soon.
lsn't it correct doctor?
Good deal!!
l have three shops in Thrissur
town...some bank deposit too.
l'm getting pension from
government to boot.
That is enough for us to live.
My children need not know about this.
Take rest. l will come later.
Rest in peace!
Drink it.
Where are you going?
l have some urgent works.
l will come later.
What is your right name?
- Tessa. K. Abraham
K stands for...
- Kurissuparambil.
So, you are a cross!
Advocate...Note this...Tessa. K. Ab...
Only after that is finished.
You brute!
l never expected such a big surprise.
What's wrong with this?
l'm planning to change like this.
How lengthy was your hair?
Didn't you feel any sense
of loss when you cut it short?
How easy now to maintain this..
After bath it is a matter of just 5 minutes.
Needs to just do like this.
You changed a lot living in
Kochi for just six months...
...much more than me who spent
a long time in Bangalore.
Kochi is not the same in the olden days.
That is correct.
What a fragrance!
Like that of orange.
Feel like eating it.
That's why it is made as a body cream.
Tell me..
Okay..
Okay.
What happened?
The driver will drop you.
l had promised an outing with my wife.
l forgot that.
Okay.
l have taken Rs.3,000 from the purse.
Tessa's younger sister has come here.
Does she have a younger sister too?
Did you get Burger?
- Yes.
One is staring at us.
Where?
- Don't look.
ls he coming towards us?
Cyril
l know him.
Are you alone?
No..some of my friends are there.
Don't you have friends of your own age?
This is my younger sister- Tissa.
She is my colleague- Jincy.
Ohh..Okay.
This is Cyril - Crossover consultancy.
What happened to the other sir's nose?
ls he fine now?
That is okay.
He is okay. l talked to him yesterday.
l got really tensed.
Where are you staying?
- Near here Cocks Town...
Nice ass!!
Okay.
Bye.
What an ass!
l have warned you...
Why on earth did you say
like that in front of him?
Do girls love those men
having big buttocks?
Have a good day.
Was a little embarrassing.
l have warned you thousand
times....aren't it embarrassing?
What all has she told you about me?
That you are the one who
has answers to all questions.
Did she tell you about my proposal?
- Yes.
She is not interested.
l'm also not interested.
She has become a little aged.
l think you will be perfect.
What's your opinion?
Don't laugh. l was not joking.
l have in Thrissur...
...3 shops, bank deposit, pension..
She has exposed the suspense.
l wish God took my life now itself.
This is the moron whom l told you about.
He?
- Yes.
Hello!
You are going today?
- Yes. By 8.30 bus.
Meet you next time.
- See you.
l will be back after seeing her off.
- Okay. Bye.
Aren't your father dying there?
Stop gaping and sit somewhere there.
l will call you back. Okay.
Don't look...walk.
l have come to drop Jincy.
- Okay.
She is your younger sister, right?
- Yes.
l'm DK.
What's your name?
- Tissa.
Wow!
Tessa!!
Tissa!!
Very good.
Shall we move?
- Yes.
Lift?
No, thanks.
DK is a 'set up' of Jincy, right?
Shut up.
You can't work in this hospital for long.
You need to shop some winter cloths.
The temperature in
Canada will drop up to -14.
My God! l was really worried about this.
Applications are through.
You need not be so humble.
lf there is no need, okay.
What about a treat?
Okay. But l will drink.
Okay..you can.
Okay.
Tessa - Cyril.
Cyril - Tessa.
lt's not as matching as Raju-Radha.
Raju and Radha are brother and sister.
Who told like that?
They are a couple.
ls there any mention in 'Balarama'
that they are brother and sister?
No..right?
Will there be a dooms day in 2012?
l won't say that it will happen..
But by December, there
will be some changes.
That we will have to know
from our own experience..
So, we have to finish the
pending works at the earliest.
Correct.
Many who come to my office say
that the job of a nurse is thankless.
ls it?
- Yes.
l haven't felt like that.
Why should we expect
gratitude for doing ourjob?
Sometimes we will get good tips.
lf we are pressed for money
that time, we will accept it.
l never had any doubt about my
career right from my childhood.
l was born to become a nurse.
l don't know how far Cyril
can understand what l say.
But..
My mother was a nurse.
Are you used to drinking?
Can you have one more?
- Okay.
lt seems l only speak.
Now it is your turn to speak.
You continue...its fun listening to you.
l don't think that l can speak any longer.
lt is like l stepped onto
the podium at school.
You are very used to drinking, right?
- Yes.
l'm a Christian from Kottayam, right?
There will be a bottle on our dining table.
ls it not your house?
ls it not?
l will pay for the taxi.
l will pay the bill
But goal..
Hello.
l was a little fit yesterday.
A little only?
A little over..
l have got hang over.
Just got up.
Where are you now?
l'm in the hospital.
l'm just out of the OT.
OT?
Operation theater.
There was an emergency laparotomy
Which means?
ln some accident cases...
...if there is any internal
injury, the surgeon...
...will take out all the internal organs
from the abdomen and replant it.
Only that much.
l understood.
l will call you later.
Okay.
Bye.
Gone!
Hello
- Yes.
That bystander..
Which bystander?
...Of Dr.Jayachandran's patient..
You should see the way he stands.
ln the very morning..his
flirting and his vulgar gait..
l feel like slapping him.
Rascal!
The person who sent him as
bystander should be blamed.
Do you hear anything?
What?
Tessa Mol...Tessa Mol...
Go go.
Go
- l'm not going.
l tell you...go.
l...
l am not a virgin.
l was in love with one Benny who
was running a medical shop.
l used to go there to buy
medicine for my mother.
l felt that l was in love with him.
Now l feel it as nonsense.
What was his name?
Benny.
l thought that he was a good man.
Till that time, l knew only good people.
lt was an accident.
When it came to the stage of
marriage, he fled the scene.
He had a wife and
children in Ernakulam.
l got the entire bad name
right from my school days.
lt was a big punishment.
l don't know about the
future of our relationship.
But l won't get any peace of
mind, if l don't tell it to you.
l also wanted to tell you one thing.
The sound is not 'faa', but 'bhaa'.
'Bhaa'.
'Faa'.
l'm saying the same.
Not 'faavi', but 'bhaavi'.
'Bhaavi'.
'Faavi'.
No...'Bhaavi'.
l'm saying the same - 'Faavi'.
Yes you are right.
- What is the matter?
'Feautiful'!!
l am saying the same, right?
Okay, you are correct, perfect.
''Snow which slowly kills, burning girl..''
''You are far too a destination
that few can reach you..''
''Oh twilight! Oh breeze,
Oh thorn, Oh rose, Oh petal..''
''Oh ember, Oh shade..''
l will go after some days, right?
- Yes.
Can you stay with me till that.
''Oh wings, Oh clear sky..''
''Breeze which wafts across my mind..''
''Oh dream..Oh sea..''
''Slowly...''
''Snow which slowly kills, burning girl..''
''You are far too a destination
that few can reach you..''
Hey..What you doing?
What's this, Cyril?
Come.
Hey..Cyril...
What happened?
- Nothing. l will tell you..come.
Didn't he leave after dropping you?
Not that..l started a little early
today as l have duty in the casualty.
Still out of range.
Nothing to worry..don't be tensed.
Not that...yesterday's problem...
That still stirs in my mind.
Must have reached home.
Try once more.
The customer you are
calling is unavailable.
You can leave message...
The customer you are
calling is unavailable.
Sir..Cyril...
Wasn't there an incident yesterday?
- Yes.
Cyril hit the son of the Karnataka
Rakshanavedi's secretary.
They are after him to chop off his hand.
The issue has been solved
after some discussions.
Nothing to worry.
lt is safe to be in hiding for two days.
He is in my farm house now.
No mobile coverage
there to contact him.
Give the phone to Cyril.
Tessa...
l didn't expect it to become
as serious like this.
l was really scared.
l know.
Hegde sir has interfered
to solve the problems.
l will be backing home in two days.
Okay?
Okay.
How is your hand?
That's okay.
l am fine.
Don't worry.
We can meet after two days.
Have you watched this movie?
Cyril should see this situation
with a matured mind.
You should convince her that the
incident is not a big disaster in her life.
Only a few of us know
about this incident.
At this time when the visa is ready...
Tessa also demanded the same..
lf this news is leaked out to the media.....
The management is also concerned
about the goodwill of the hospital.
Cyril...
Three stitches on Tessa's head.
A finger is fractured.
Bite marks are seen all over the body.
She needs you at this moment.
Understand that....go and sit near her.
Please...
Cyril...
l want to kill him.
Everyone told me to be practical.
But l can't be practical.
Please Cyril.
l only pray for hanging on
somehow till l leave.
We have a way before
us to start a new life.
How do you behave
so normally, Tessa?
Looking at me, do
you feel that l'm normal?
Now l don't even know
how one feels so normal.
l'm unable to erase
his face from my mind.
Then, what about me?
l see my own weeping face when l
close my eyes...do you know that?
l don't want to commit suicide.
l only need a life with you.
You don't understand what l say, right?
Something else is disturbing you.
What else?
Has anything changed between
us because of this incident?
What do you mean?
Tell me.
Oh God Tessa..l haven't
thought like that.
Cyril...
You hurting me Cyril.
Tessa...
Was shifted to the lCU yesterday.
Still critical.
Do you want to see him?
l will be leaving next week.
Don't feel sad.
Cyril is here with you.
This is the worst period
of time in your life.
l know.
lf you recover fast, Cyril
will also become normal.
Tessa...
Cyril...
Don't get scared.
Where is Cyril?
l want to apologize to both of you.
He is like my brother.
l'm a patient undergoing treatment.
Cyril...
l can't sleep.
lf l don't take medicines...
But after that incident
between us, l slept well.
Lord...if possible kindly takes
back this grail from me...
Let Lord's wish prevail and not mine..
First time it was my commitment.
Haven't you borrowed
a lot of money from me?
For that l have worked hard.
She would have gone like any other girl.
l don't want to go anywhere.
He is a brute.
No other girl should have
such an experience.
Won't you be with me?
What did you say?
l'm with you.
Not we...you are in trouble.
l'm still with her.
You only have something to lose.
What will you do now?
Money is not a constraint.
Shall we go?
- Yes.
You wait here.
l will come with the bike.
Okay.
Give the bag. l have to check it.
Give the bag.
Cyril!
Sir...look.
Where did you get it?
l don't know.
Come on.
Cyril!
Bloody cold!
Madam...
Yes..come...come.
Come.
Give me the file.
Give me that.
Move this side.
What is your name?
l ask you bloody...
Tessa.
Full name?
Tessa. K. Abraham.
Your's?
Bobby's Meroona.
Check them.
Remove your dress.
Remove.
Remove quickly.
Quick.
Sit like this.
Don't you understand?
Move legs.
Understood.
l will take care of the nurse.
You are nurse or drugs?
Why all Malayalee
girls come for nursing?
Which hospital?
CMC.
How many years of service?
Two.
Do you know Tamil?
Yes.
Go to cell with your luggages.
There is a woman called Subaida.
She is born criminal.
Give her some respect.
She is pregnant also.
Take care of her well.
Understand?
Take them.
Do you know Tamil?
Did Jailor said everything?
Come.
Massage my legs.
lt has become wooden.
lt is hard to give birth to a child.
Come here.
Look what that police lady did to me.
Did you commit any crime?
l asked you only.
No.
l can see it in your eyes.
But l won't tell you not to cry.
God is seeing all those.
Good, bad all those understand to Him.
Go and sleep peacefully.
Are you tensed?
No.
We must took her to hospital soon.
Take rest.
Come.
Subaida is very weak.
Be careful on her till
shifted her to hospital.
Am l going to die?
l know that this is not going
to be a normal delivery.
Always all of you will
try to save the mother.
But you must change that for me.
Even if l die, my child should alive.
Nothing will happened to you.
l don't know that l am
pregnant when l kill them.
l won't do that if l knew it.
lt is difficult to get
released from jail by killing...
...the Mayor and his brother
those who killed my husband.
lf l was outside they
won't spare me and my child.
Jail is safe.
Now l was alive to give birth to my child.
Do you know Pankajam's story?
No.
She has been here for the past 8 years.
Her husband, a drunkard.
He raped his own daughter after drunk.
Without suffering that she killed him...
...give poison to daughter
and she hanged up herself.
But some scoundrels saved her...
...and put her in jail in order to
kill her husband and daughter.
Because of hanging she
can't speak anymore.
See that?
Everyone here has a different tale to tell.
What is this?
Are you going to open a shop in jail?
No. These want to
give to all those in jail.
This is for that.
Everyone must be happy.
ls it?
- Yes.
How are you?
l am fine.
And you?
Yes.
Why are you looking so dull?
lt is a boy!
How is your business?
Now it is dull season.
2 tamil movies are flops.
Your phone is ringing.
- Okay.
l change the ringtone yesterday.
Where are you?
l am in jail.
ln jail? What happened?
Nothing.
l came to see my sister.
ls it? - Yes.
Talk at outside.
Call you later.
Did the doctor check you recently.
Everything is good.
She is with me.
She will take care of everything.
Her name is Tessa.
She is a smart nurse!
She is from Kerala.
What? 'lssa'?
Not 'lssa' mother - Tessa.
Are you proper Kerala?
- Yes.
l have a friend in Kerala.
Very famous.
Mattanchery Martin.
Do you know him?
No.
Why don't you know?
He is very famous!
A fat one with beard.
Super quotation!
Keep quiet.
His name is Cyril Mathew, right?
He is not much famous.
But he is an important one
for some special circles.
He came to Bangalore 4 years ago.
Now he is in Cochin.
The last girl that he deal
was a Malayalee nurse.
That is you?
After Hegde...
Big land lord!
Already his name is in a case
of raping an 8 year old girl.
lt's okay.
You are trapped in a super team.
This is me.
l don't have the humor sense to
enquire about your well being there.
Last week a decision was
taken regarding my left hand.
Before my game is over,
l need to tell you something.
l have spent so many days
in different hospitals.
l have met so many
efficient doctors and nurses.
But there is something
special in your eyes - kindness.
Your life should not end in that jail.
You should learn more, work more.
l have bequeathed half
of my wealth to you.
l didn't have any problems
to give you the whole.
But my children might turn
against you if l do so.
This world remains a good place to live
only because of a few people like you.
''Life is a heaven
and you an angel''
Daughter....
Bye
Sister...
What happened?
No problem.
One minute.
l will call someone.
Warden...
Some one please come.
Sister...
Warden...
Who is that?
Who?
Who is making noise?
Don't be tensed.
Warden...
Who?
Open.
Call the doctor.
What happened?
l will call the doctor.
Open quickly.
Wait...
Bullshit! lt won't open.
Call the doctor.
What happened?
Nothing to worry.
We will go to hospital in a short while.
Where is the doctor?
Did you get him in phone?
Sister...
Nothing to worry.
We will go to hospital.
l am trying.
He is not attending the call.
Not attending?
- Yes.
What will we do now?
Tessa...can you do something?
Get me some hot water.
Call the jailor.
l can't Tessa.
l did a lot of crimes in my life.
l can't.
No sister, you can.
Nothing..l am with you.
Nothing sister.
Nothing.
l am with you.
Sister...
Listen to me sister.
Don't be tensed.
l am with you. You must do
everything. Listen to me.
Sister...
l can only help you.
You must push.
Sister...
Push sister...
You must push.
Thank God!
Come on.
Tell the doctor that
she have high bleeding.
Tissa Mol!
You need not worry about me.
Now l'm in a very safe place.
Even if something happen, l get
the training to face it from here.
Don't create a scene.
Can't l cry?
Name?
Bonny.
Place?
Vypinkara.
We worked together, right?
Meet the advocate.
You should meet him before leaving.
l have enough with me for
both of us to live comfortably.
You should not be sad.
No.
Nothing to worry.
Bye.
Look baby! Who you saw first.
''How to live comfortably, when
there is no way forward''
''Can anyone tell me a
way to overcome this?''
''lsn't there a destiny for everyone..''
''How to live comfortably''
lt has been a long time
since l sang a song.
l want to kill a person.
Don't misunderstand.
l didn't say that you can't.
l got laughed when you say suddenly.
There are two villains in your story, right?
ls it enough if one is killed?
Yes.
You want to go out and kill?
l don't take cases now a days.
Because of breathing problem, l can't.
Sign there.
l will give instructions on what you
are supposed to say in the court.
Say only that.
lt will be easier as there
are no past convictions.
Even if this fails, we can
arrange it with money.
Not that. That is for the officials.
Okay.
Tessa...
You need a help outside the jail.
l have a friend named Dinesh.
l will introduced you to him.
What will you give him?
We are born with a weapon.
That's both our problem and power.
What all he hears?
Anyway your jail life didn't
become a futile affair.
Okay. We will do it.
While doing it, you should do it perfectly.
Others should feel it as a natural death.
Subaida is an old friend.
l will help you.
l don't want anything for free.
Nothing will be available for free.
Since you mentioned it...l prefer
it to be offered wholeheartedly.
We should all love...
always we should love.
We should love as many
persons as possible.
Does Jincy call you?
Yes..some times.
l'm not Jincy.
l'm one who was raped twice...
...am out from the jail after being
convicted in a drug case.
lsn't there a courage when
have nothing more to lose?
Now l have only that with me.
Hello
- Everything is fine?
Who?
Tessa!
l'm a patient.
Aren't you a nurse?
You know it, right?
l'm a patient.
You are a patient for me.
But, you can be cured with death.
Cobra in the cover.
lf you budge, it will bite.
The poison will affect the diaphragm
which helps the lungs to breathe.
You will die because of suffocation.
Maximum 30 minutes.
Bitten.
Don't get scared.
lf the blood pressure increases,
death will be faster.
But l know, you got scared.
Now l will watch from here you dying.
Everyone will get angry.
Majority of them are killing in that angry.
The people is very less who is
standing in front of the dead body...
...with braveness on thinking
that it is correct to kill.
On killing him, l saw his
soul going through his eyes.
At that time, we are like Gods!
When do you want the delivery?
By 16th.
- 16th is 1, 2, 3..
How can l help you?
Don't spoil my life by digging up the past.
lt was a mistake.
lf Rosy's relatives come to know
about this, l will be finished.
Even Bible says to forgive the sinners.
How much you have changed!
Where have you been?
Do you know that my youngest daughter
is given your name - Tessa Benny.
There is a model agency in
the Chittoor route run by a Cyril.
'Looksmart'
What should l do?
Good.
l will call you when an assignment
suitable for you arrives.
E-mail the photos.
You should meet this girl.
Please sir.
Wherever you want..she
is ready for any adjustments.
You...
How was the shoot?
l will....in half an hour.
Okay?
Will meet in the flat.
Sure.
What's the name?
Prarthana.
Your name?
Benny.
Hundreds of profiles like this
come to this office everyday.
Many are ready for such adjustments.
My job is different.
Hard work and talent are
essential to survive in this field.
Details are here...we will contact you.
This case is very important for me.
You should meet this girl.
She is really talented.
Won't you understand
things if explained?
l have another appointment.
Bye.
Benny...
Prarthana?
Yeah.
You know Malayalam, right?
Yes.
lf you come with another name,
heavy make up and a sun glass...
Did you think that l can't recognize you.
Aren't a man who slept with you?
You....
Joker Benny!
You are just a nurse.
You are just a woman...
understand that.
l can't live without you.
This is Tessa.
lt's not hangover.
You are under sedation.
ln your last glass it was
not just champagne.
When you were unconscious, l
surgically removed your male organ.
ln medical terms, it is
known as penectomy.
A tube is fitted for urination.
You will have some
difficulties in the beginning.
Then, it will be alright.
Minimal movements only..there
are two lines of stitches.
The effect of local anesthesia
may have reduced.
You have unbearable pain....right?
You have experienced
only pleasure from there.
Are you able to understand pain now?
You may have emotions now.
But the sex you celebrated,
traded is no more for you.
You won't stand before
a girl confidently.
Hello.
ls it not over?
No.
This won't end without making Cyril
understand what he has done to me.
Okay.
l will call you later.
Take this.
Antibiotics to prevent infection.
Don't want?
Are you planning to kill me
after torturing like this?
No.
lf l want to accomplish my
mission, you should stay alive.
l will be here till this wound heals.
Aren't l a nurse from Kottayam.
Didn't you mention
about killing a person?
l want to kill him.
l killed him.
l told you to have the medicine?
You feel angry, don't you?
When one sees things out of control
for the first time in life, one will get angry.
Manhood is not the
6 inches you chopped off.
You haven't understood me well.
Yes, l have.
A person who has spoiled
the lives of many girls.
Yes..so many...l will do it again.
How much did you get when you sold me?
l will use those whom l like.
Then l will sell them.
l reached till here doing this business.
Till where?
Till this bed?
Do you think that you will go alive from
here after putting me in this condition?
Even after doing this much
against me, aren't you still alive?
When called Cyril sir, the
phone is switched off.
We reached only a little while before.
He is asleep.
Will be on leave for two days.
Bye.
God is with me.
l still survive only because
of my belief in God.
When you recognized me yesterday,
l thought it was the end of my life.
l didn't think that l was in disguise
in front of a professional fraud.
But you didn't kill me.
Do you know why?
l'm still somewhere in your heart.
You have not been able to forget me.
lsn't it Cyril?
You only created the Tessa
who sits in front of you.
l was a different person before.
Sending me to jail was the
biggest mistake you committed.
When l looked around...
...l saw a number of women who are
wounded, who have seen death nearby.
l became more confident
about my survival.
l consider Hegde's attack
against me as a dog bite only.
But you...
Doesn't matter.
What l lost is one who sold me.
But you lost one who
loved you so much.
Do you know what position
you had in my mind?
Cyril!
l want a life with you.
l will leave by the evening flight.
You need not worry.
You are safe now.
l think you have understood
what you ought to understand.
l thought a lot about the
punishment to be given to you.
Even l empathized with your mother.
But l couldn't think about
anything less than this.
Tell me the truth..
Are your mother a nurse?
Yes.
Why should l lie now?
My mother was a nurse.
How come you are
able to lie so blatantly?
lf she doesn't understand
even after repeating it...
She don't know Malayalam.
What?
'Bhaava vettyasam'..'Bha'.
Not 'faa'.
'Bha'.
Didn't l say the same?
Okay.
Aren't you from Kottayam?
No one for me.
lt will dip to -14.
My mother was a nurse.
Will you stay with me till then?
l want to kill him.
l will use those whom l like.
Then l will sell them.
You are just a woman.
Bye Cyril.
l can't tell what is in your mind
by looking at your face.
lf you still want to settle scores with me...
l'm going to Canada.
You can come there.
Bye.
Tessa...
You are a woman.
l will come at a time when l can.
To meet you.
Hello.
Tessa...
l'm going home.
Son is down with fever.
ls it okay if l call after l reach there?
No..l will call after reaching there.
Okay.
This is not just a story of a girl
who was repeatedly cheated.
Tessa K. Abraham is a reminder.
A reminder that a woman's
endurance is not her weakness.
''ls crystal.....your body
is a shining crystal..''
''Crystal which is hotter
than burning sunlight..''
''You are a flower, a girl
dripping with honey..''
''Enthralling beetles who hover around..''
''ls crystal...on which
golden sunlight shines?''
''ls a stone..a stone on the nose
stud which is as bright as moon..''