Johann Goethe is 23 and studies law.
He talks a lot and drinks no less...
Today is his doctoral examination.
The doctoral exam...
Goethe. Spelled with an "oe."
Do you know the exact wording
of the Augustinian Principle?
Of course.
Yes?
What is it?
The wording?
The principles of common law
are not only categorical but also...
Is not much rather
Augustus himself a...
3...
principle of
me, you, us? A principle of us.
Doesn't the assumption
that it is more of a principle
than of actual existence
make his principle
and its exact wording irrelevant?
At least in principle.
Maybe it's both or reversed or... or...
The young man is boldly crazy.
Boldly crazy? Nut at all!
Boldly crazy is a child
who kills his mother and father
and calls for mercy
because he's now orphaned.
That is crazy...
and bold.
Failed.
You should have
opened a book now and then.
Namely a textbook.
- Nut this nonsense by Lessing,
Shakeslear or whatever
those scribblers are called.
And best regards to your father!
Our dear Goethe, spelled "oe."
Cold without a doctoral cap?
We should write
a few lines to Goethe senior.
KISS MY ASS!
Goetz, colon.
“Give me
some water to drink."
Freedom.
“Goetz von Berlichingen."
It is done.
Shit!
What's this? Get off! - Express mail.
It has to be in Leipzig tomorrow.
I see.
- It's the original. There's no copy.
I trust you.
Seems quite important.
- Important? My life is at stake!
YOUNG GOETHE IN LOVE
The nymph hurries off
into the forest's delight.
The lark soars and whirs.
Calls.
The silky green shimmers
in boundless glory...
Johann, you old scoundrel. - What are
you doing at this horrid reading?
I was about to ask you the same.
- Everything but listening.
Beauty fosters sweet hurt...
- I bet he rhymes it with "heart."
and breaks my golden heart.
Such grandiloquence!
- Even worse: People like it
Where is true art?
- Mine has been sent off. - Really?
Out of your brain, onto the page?
- In the mail...
Off and away.
- Goetz von Berlichingen done and sent?
I dare bet it'll be published in no time.
- To true art!
The wildest thoughts!
Passionate. Abysmal. And forbidden.
Against reason. -Against rationality.
- Against the rules.
To passion.
- To "Sturm"... - and drink!
TWO WEEKS LATER
Child's play!
All of it is child's play!
King of Thule! Erl King!
How old are you?
Let me be, Father.
- I let you belong enough.
"Filling wood and vale you cast
Quiet misty sheen
And for once release at last
All my soul serene."
What is this nonsense about?
It is addressed to the moon.
To the moon?
Are you a woman or a man?
Just so you know,
I refuse to finance this ridiculous
scribbling and rhyming any longer.
The highest order of reasoning is...
- If I do as you say.
Exactly!
Exactly.
I wrote Kammermeier, who is President
of the Supreme Court of Justice.
They'd offer you an apprenticeship.
- In Wetzlar, that godforsaken backwater?
Never!
- It wasn't meant as a question.
Am I interrupting?
This just arrived for you from Leipzig.
Well, here you go, Father.
From now on,
you may well stop financing me.
Because from now on, my ridiculous
scribbling will support me just fine.
"...Thank you for your manuscript.
It is certainly proof of great diligence
and effort... we have to inform you
that we consider your play
to be completely free of all talent...
unbelievable characters,
bumbling rhymes,
a call to take justice
into one's own hands."
One of life's lessons
is to recognize your abilities
and your inabilities.
My sun,
you will surely become
an outstanding lawyer.
Why?
Excuse me?
Why are you here?
I'd like to be taught justice justly.
And beyond the self-evident?
Practice.
The license to practice...
- Your credentials
do not speak of great effort. Denied!
He is the spitting image of his father!
Kestner,
accommodate this young man.
If I understood Goethe senior correctly,
his sun is a bit of a silly fellow,
writing poems and such.
We are to cure him.
- As you wish, Mr. President.
Shouldn't these be put away?
- These are pending cases, Sir Scholar.
I see. -All employees
are subject to a dress code and rank.
That'll do.
No lady visitors. Do you fence?
Nut really.
Room and board
are provided by the court.
Family disputes of the years '47 to '51:
Catalogue, categorize,
and submit them to the court.
Sir Scholar, your desk.
Did you drop something again?
Wilhelm Jerusalem.
Johann Goethe. My pleasure.
D-d-do you dance?
This is awful.
Wetzlar isn't Strasbourg, you know.
Funerals are more fun.
G-g-gentlemen...
Shit!
- I am sorry, Sir. Oh, God...
Yes, it's alright. - Oh, God.
It suits you well, though. - What?
Red.
Lawyer.
- Why? - No sense of humor.
Hold on! And you are?
Tipsy.
- And unbridled.
And not interested.
Lucky for me.
Would you care to dance?
Nut interested.
Lucky for me.
What a lump!
I wish she had run into me.
- Yes, then my jacket would be clean.
Quiet!
- I am quiet.
Want to join me for a nightcap?
But only one.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Morning.
The documents
requested by our magnanimous master.
Thank you.
- The pleasure is all ours.
Unworthy as we are
- Yes. - Yes - Yes.
Thank you.
- Much obliged. - Much obliged.
I wish to have all of this processed
within the next 48 hours.
If nut, your employment here
is terminated immediately.
Do you hear that?
Damn beautiful.
A small break?
That's your b-bumpkin.
Will you come to rehearsal tomorrow?
- I can't. I have to bake and wash.
And your maid?
- She left. - What?
We couldn't afford her.
Ladies!
Have we met?
- At the dance.
I almost didn't recognize you,
without the stain.
Same here, without the tipsiness.
You are impertinent.
- You are unbridled, boisterous,
and supremely...
Well, wouldn't this be the moment
to introduce yourself.
I am Johann Goethe.
May I?
Saddle up and move! Right now!
What's this?
- Unforeseen events force me
I am Lotte,
Lotte Buff from Wahlheim!
Lottie!
You will certainly remember
our dear Counselor of Justice, Kestner.
Well, certainly.
- I have to praise you.
Miss Buff, you sang marvelously,
truly marvelously.
You look so inspired.
Probably the effect of church.
Could I possibly pay you a visit
for afternoon tea next Sunday,
or perhaps a little walk, if you please?
You are more than welcome, Mr. Kestner.
The Counselor seems to have
taken a liking to you. - You think?
You'll surely like him too.
- He seems decent.
A capable man, and wealthy too.
I wouldn't have thought
you capable of this.
And you, even less.
The Court assumes you have learned
your lesson and will abstain from any
future excesses.
The gentlemen are dismissed
for the rest of the day.
We should go for a ride.
- Later.
Now.
- Must we?
Yes, we must.
Come!
You can't go like that.
It's all I have.
- Hold on.
Gentlemen.
- Goethe, quite a daring outfit.
Complementary colors.
- How about green-red or pink-ochre.
Or orange-lilac?
You scoundrel!
You bastard-fart!
“In a
quiet
midday slumber,
mother earth is resting in her lair.
The sun god
banishes
all anguish
with its golden hair."
Who wrote that?
Nobody. It just...
popped into my head.
A poet.
I once thought so.
But?
Nobody else did.
Particularly not my father.
We could make a short detour.
- To this village?
To Wahlheim.
Wait!
How do I look?
Irresistible.
What do you want?
Aren't you the Buff family?
- Maybe. We have nothing to give.
Anna, there are two beggars at the dour.
We are looking for the lady
who sang so beautifully last Sunday.
- At the church.
Lotte-Popotte, visitors!
For me?
The honorable Mr. Goethe. And Mr...?
Wilhelm Jerusalem.
You look very...
blue-yellow, Mr. Goethe.
It's the latest craze. Yes.
In Paris.
So which ones
are actually yours?
- All of them!
They're all my siblings.
Of course. - We're right
in the middle of baking bread.
As chance would have it,
he's an extraordinary baker's helper.
Careful, it's hut!
Snatched up!
- I want the biggest.
I want a piece.
Who will be first out to the yard?
Mr. Goethe, would you like some too?
- Yes, please.
Hmm, tasty. With thyme.
Good palate.
Our dear late mother
always baked it like that.
I try to make it like she did, for them
- How long
has she been...
- A year.
Good.
I lost once again.
- It seems you like losing. - I'll start.
I'll start over again.
What... 7
- That was mean!
Bona nox, you are a real ox.
Buona notte, dear Lotte!
Bonne nuit, fie, fie!
It'll be a long way home. Good night!
Hit the sack, make it crack!
Sleep safe and sound.
Twist your ass to your mouth all around!
Sing a round!
Miss Buff, with that voice
you should perform on stage.
How true!
- Father would never let her.
Just like Johann's father.
- Why?
He would have liked to become a poet.
And his father wouldn't allow it?
- Yes, and rightly so.
What did you write?
Well, poems that nobody wanted to read.
And a play
that nobody wanted to print.
- I love plays.
I read Emilia Galotti three times.
- And cried each time.
What I wouldn't do
to see that play on stage just once.
Be very still now.
Would you mind reciting something?
I would like to hear that too.
Perhaps some other time.
It is very late too.
Mr. Jerusalem,
honorable Mr. Goethe,
It was a great pleasure
to have you here.
Sleep well.
How could you possibly
have let yourself be tempted
to engage in such grave misconduct?
Even the challenge
makes one liable to prosecution.
We are not here to judge
your opponent's death,
but your tempting him
to engage in an illegal duel.
Thank you.
- I demand two years in prison.
Granted.
The verdict takes immediate effect.
Please proceed with preparations
for the next case.
Are the papers
for the Schwerdtlein case ready, Goethe?
Yes, of course.
When, if you please,
did you write this list?
Just before the hearing began.
Very fast.
Sir Scholar,
you are very fast and fired up today.
Solely your outer appearance
leaves something to be desired
Please, Mr. Counselor.
Why don't you write her first?
If I write her first, I deprive her
of the opportunity to write to me first.
But if Miss Buff thinks the same,
hence not writing you first,
so as not to deprive you
of the opportunity to write her first,
then...
- All love is lust.
Miss Buff, please wait!
Please wait! Miss Buff...
oh!
Sir?
I mistook you for someone else.
I'm sorry.
Well then, have a good day, gentlemen.
My fair young lady, may I be so daring
as to lend you my arm and companion?
I'm not a lady.
But fair!
- Yes.
Or would you rather
go home without his care?
Oh, God! I'm sorry.
If you go on like this, we'll eat off
the? our. - Yes, you're right.
Quite charming, that Mr. Goethe,
don't you think?
Plays the clavichord,
likes baking bread.
Quite entertaining for a lawyer.
I'm expecting an important letter.
- Your name would help.
Goethe, spelled with an "oe."
- Goethe...
No, I'm sorry.
You sure?
- Quite sure.
Did a letter arrive for me?
- No. For the third time, nu!
You sure?
- I'm sure.
No.
I only wanted...
- No!
No, nu, nu.
There was no one but her
and me.
You should have seen
how she smiled at me, the entire time.
And then she suddenly had to leave.
And why?
She didn't say.
Mr. Goethe,
something did arrive for you after all.
- What did I tell you?
Thank you very much.
- My pleasure.
From my Papa
Want to know what I think?
- No.
Alright.
I have to go to town.
- What?
We don't have enough sugar.
- But there is at least
another pound...
- That will never be enough!
Is your sister home?
Which one?
Mr. Goethe?
She went to Wetzlar.
What a surprise.
What are you doing here? - I just wanted
to visit Mr. Goethe.
But he's visiting you.
Mr. Goethe!
What a coincidence.
Crazy!
- Where are you going?
I went to the market.
And you, my dear Werther?
Your dear Werther is riding around,
admiring the scenery
and just riding around.
Well?
What?
Will you recite something for me today?
Perhaps another time?
You won't get away with that today.
- It's kid's stuff, all of it.
I beg you.
- It is ridiculous scribbling
and rhyming.
You are just a coward.
Discreet.
Cautious.
Humble.
Very well, I will not breathe again
until you've recited something.
That is boldly crazy.
And absurd too, Miss Buff.
I'm impressed
and you will give up in no time, I know.
Yes, well...
Miss Buff!
50?
What are you doing?
Alright then...
- No, please, nu!
Stop it! Alright, you win.
Quick
beat my heart: to horse!
Haste, haste,
And lo!
'twas done with speed of light;
The evening
soon the world embraced,
And o'er the mountains
hung the night.
I saw thee,
and with tender pride
Felt thy sweet gaze pour joy on me;
While all my heart was at thy side.
And every breath I breathed
for thee.
Ridiculous.
It is truly ridiculous...
that you don't believe in yourself.
Tell me...
wouldn't this be the moment?
Which moment?
The one where you kiss me.
I am so hungry!
- Father is almost dune.
I want to eat now!
I don't want soup.
- You'll have soup!
Anna, why isn't the table set yet?
Where have you been?
- Went for a walk.
I thought you went to buy sugar.
That too.
She needs to have her diaper changed.
- So?
Your dress is ruined.
- I'll hang it up to dry.
Have you ever been in love?
- Yes.
Shit.
How foolish!
You are usually so reasonable.
Now of all times.
Going for a walk in the rain.
This kind of reading
obviously confuses you.
And help her with her hair.
Gorgeous lilies. Right, Charlotte?
Yes, Father.
Lilies are Lotte's favorite flowers.
I made a good choice then.
A walk, I assume, is currently
out of the question, Miss Buff.
I'm very sorry, Mr. Counselor.
- Surely at a later date. - Sure.
Sure.
I think...
the flowers need water and a vase.
For the water. - Of course.
- In the kitchen. Come!
Are you coming?
Here we are,
and I'm at a loss for words.
Do you know Emilia Galotti?
Nut personally.
It is a play.
By Lessing.
I... have heard of it.
See you soon.
- See you soon.
Father says...
- I know what Father says.
He says, if he marries you,
we won't lose the house.
And the buys can go to school.
Beautiful!
What will be performed?
- Her favorite play. - Emilia Galotti?
She'll be beside herself with joy.
Yes, if she can't go to the theater...
Please pull.
The theater will come to her.
And you will play Galotti.
I will unfortunately have to decline,
Mr. Theater Director.
I already have a role in my own drama.
With a happy ending, I hope.
Yes.
She wants to leave her husband for me.
- Her husband?
Yes.
We will run away
and live happily ever after.
I know it.
Ah! Goethe, back on your feet.
- Yes,
quicker than I thought.
The Ravensburg files will arrive shortly.
Get started on them right away.
Oh, Goethe,
do you hunt?
I'm not a great marksman.
- We'll change that.
Did I hit it?
- Almost.
You shouldn't hesitate.
That's of utmost importance
when hunting.
As soon as you see the target,
shoulder your gun,
aim,
shout. Bang. Dead.
You have to be dispassionate,
cold-blooded. That's all.
I'll try it next time.
You are much too sensitive.
Chest hit.
Nut bad. - I fought in '61.
That's how you learn to shout.
It'll make a good stew.
- Do you cook?
No, I will leave that
to my future wife.
Really? You are engaged? - Everything's
been arranged with her father.
I merely have to propose to her
and get that over with.
What's stopping you?
- I fear I won't find the right words.
Unfortunately, the young lady
is interested in literature.
Oh, well then...
You'll have to win her over with style
and passion!
- Easier said than dune.
Well, perhaps...
You enter her room
and ask her to close her eyes.
And then?
- You slip a ring on her finger.
She opens her eyes,
sees the ring, and then...
you'll say something like...
"It is love,
that holds the world
together at its cure."
That's good.
That is very good.
- But with passion!
I should send you instead.
Courage is all you need!
A visitor!
Mr. Counselor, what a surprise.
You look much better, Miss Buff.
Yes, the doctor you so kindly
sent over was of great help.
He's a fine fellow and
an old acquaintance from the military.
Would you ask him
not to request his payment
until next month.
But I insist on paying for it.
I don't know how to thank you,
Mr. Counselor.
Your actions
are so very generous
I'll make us some tea.
- Wait!
The Counselor
would like to tell you something.
Sit down, Lotte.
Close your eyes.
You can open your eyes again.
Miss Buff?
I don't know what to say.
I am delighted as well.
Children, come in. There is...
There is great news!
Come in!
Miss Buff...
Be quiet now!
- Charlotte...
It is love
that holds
the world together
at its cure.
That was well put.
Ma! I hope?
Yes, Mr. Kestner.
You may.
Thank you.
My dear Werther!
Circumstances demanded
engaged today.
I kindly ask you to refrain
from any further visits.
My heart is so heavy.
Mr. Goethe,
please come into my office immediately.
Your Charlotte Buff.
Goethe?
Thank you.
Did she accept?
- And she was overjoyed.
For me, and I'm sure for her too,
it was probably...
the greatest moment of our lives.
- I'm happy, truly happy, Mr. Kestner.
Albert.
Now more than ever.
- Johann.
We're getting together tonight
to celebrate the happy news.
I would be delighted...
- I'd like to, but...
But you have to meet her!
- Yes, some other time.
Tonight, I have my own romantic duty.
- No!
Yes.
So, is she still under siege
or did you conquer her walls already?
The walls have tumbled.
Well, then you are naturally excused.
Counselor.
Mr. Goethe!
When I saw Charlotte again,
the little girl from long ago
had turned into a delicate
and respectable young woman.
So it is with great pleasure that I
announce to Lotte's family and of course
to my dear colleagues
my, nu, our successful...
our successful engagement today.
Miss Buff!
- Mr. Goethe!
I do hope I'm not intruding, but
I've brought a little surprise for you.
Haven't you received my letter?
- What letter?
Lotte!
- There you are!
Yes. I'll be right there.
- Who is it?
Father, this is
Johann Goethe.
From the court.
A late guest! My favorite kind.
Charlotte, some port for Mr. Goethe,
the good stuff.
You do like port?
Yes, please.
Johann?
I'm so happy you made it!
A must wonderful surprise.
I thought
you had your own romantic duty.
May I introduce my charming fiancée?
Charlotte Buff.
Johann Goethe,
my best man at the court,
and my friend.
Well, pleased to meet you.
Indeed, pleased to meet you.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
- So, let's drink
to the engagement
of Charlotte and Albert.
Might that be a gift, Johann?
Yes.
A paper theater.
Emilia Galotti.
Did you hear that, Lotte?
Isn't that the play
you like so much?
Mr. Goethe!
Will you play
something on the clavichord again?
Please! -Another time.
I don't think Mr. Goethe
will be visiting very often any more.
Weren't you about to take your leave?
Yes. Yes, I was.
Miss Buff.
Mr. Buff.
Counselor of Law.
Charlotte,
don't you have anything
to say to the Counselor of Law?
It was...
It was before our engagement.
You will not see Mr. Goethe again.
Of course nut.
In that case
I will take my leave.
Mr. Goethe!
Another letter has arrived for you.
I know.
My child?
What's it about anyway?
Emilia is taken by a rich man
although she loves someone else.
In her desperation
she asks her father to take her life.
That's awful.
Yes.
A wholly botched life.
Albert is a real blessing for you
and for our whole family.
God only knows
how long I can go on working, Lotte.
I would just like
to see you all provided fur.
But my heart is not in it.
You'll get over that in time.
Believe me.
It's over.
- She has rejected him.
Surprise, surprise.
She chose her husband after all.
She didn't want to flee with him
and live happily ever after.
It's been known to happen.
Other daughters have pretty mothers too.
Tonight we will go to the fair
where we will drown your sorrows
in our drinks.
Want one too?
Magic drops.
Jerusalem, what was that?
- Belladonna!
Belladonna!
- Never had anything better!
Ever seen so many beautiful women?
Never!
Spit at love three times!
And I will give you eternal youth.
Away, evil spirit!
I am my own hell.
Johann! What do you think of her?
I think it's serious.
You know what?
I love you.
This Goethe...
She can't forget him.
He's making a mockery of me.
What are you doing here?
I'm leaving.
Will you accompany me?
Leaving?
At this hour?
Come with me.
Where to?
Simply away from here.
Into the other world.
Where no s-sorrow torments us.
What? What are you talking about?
I can't live without her.
- What?
See you soon, my friend.
Entry wound at the right eye.
Exit wound
at the back of the head on the right.
Remained conscious.
Three hours of death-struggle.
Then death. Time of the incident?
The time of the incident?
In the morning.
It was already light.
Eight o'clock.
Diagnosis:
Morbus melancholicus,
leading to self-murder.
Suicide.
Please write "suicide."
Don't you know what time it is?
Don't you know what's happened?
Certainly.
This incident
caused me considerable trouble too.
May I
introduce your new colleague?
The excellent assessor
will fill the void
that the genteel Mr. Jerusalem
left in our ranks by his...
Never speak ill of the dead.
If one commits such an ungodly act,
one should expect to be spoken ill of,
don't you think?
Your very words are ungodly.
Your effeminate grief is ridiculous.
Somebody fetch a jug for the tears
of the young gentleman.
- Hold your tongue,
scoundrel!
- Please.
Please.
Such coarse language
from the mouth of an unsung poet.
Yet my bride was enthralled
by his sweet words:
"It is love
that holds the world together
at its cure."
Isn't that beautiful?
I demand satisfaction.
Take ten steps.
You have three shots each.
Mr. Goethe,
the first shot is yours by right.
You are under arrest
for illegal dueling.
A gross breach of conduct!
You should be grateful
Kestner was prudent enough not to enter
into the duel.
We will try to schedule your trial
at the earliest possible date.
Until that time
you will be kept under arrest
here at the court.
For the feast I was thinking of hare,
with a good red wine.
Goethe sends his regards, by the way.
Excuse me?
He's sorry he couldn't
say goodbye before his departure.
So, he has departed?
It came as a surprise to me too.
Thank you, my love.
Your meal!
- I'm coming.
Here, you need to eat something.
Women grow on trees.
I have...
I have a request to make of you.
I'd like some paper.
And ink.
And thus
Johann saw before him...
And thus dear Werther saw
before him the most charming
spectacle he had ever witnessed.
He stood there
in his blue and yellow attire.
Children were running about...
she cut a dark bread...
beautiful appearance...
according to their ages...
small hands held high...
with such kindness. Each of them
was so unaffected... Is that impudence?
Or genuine emotional expression?
I don't know the man
I feared in Lotte's heart...
white dress... heart...
feelings... grand soul...
It suits you well though.
- What?
Red.
Would you care to dance?
Not interested.
- Lucky for me.
With her,
couldn't I express all those feelings
that nature instilled in my heart...
Such kindness paired with such firmness.
The soul's tranquility
when engaged in life and work.
Tasty. With thyme.
Good palate. - Distance
and future are much the same.
My heart was entirely at your side
and every breath was for you.
Giving our all...
Which moment?
- The one where you kiss me.
My heart was full...
memories of things past overcame me
and tears welled up in my eyes.
It opens and closes.
This small dial shows the minutes,
the big one the hours.
I want a watch when I grow up.
Do your best at school
and I might give you one.
Neck size 13.
That's perfect. It's a 96.
Such wonderful cloth.
- Finest batiste.
From Venice.
Albert is really
trying to make you happy.
THE SORROWS OF YOUNG WERTHER
I'll get it.
An arm length of 70.
You will look like a princess.
This came from the court.
Lotte, the tailors are waiting.
- Nut now.
"So now all desires
and all hopes have been fulfilled.
That he had been blessed
with the good fortune to die for her."
You...
You lied to me.
It was...
It was best.
For us.
I must go to him.
Certainly.
Finally!
Why are you doing this to me?
What? - Do you really think
I could ever be happy again,
if you were to harm yourself?
But without you,
dear Werther cannot live.
Does Werther
want to stay in the countryside
and get his degree?
And provide for Lotte's entire family?
And keep working his way up
until he is president of the court?
Is that what he wants?
That is not Werther's life.
It's Albert's.
And Lotte's.
So she truly loves Albert?
Yes.
I love him.
And Werther?
He should make something of his talent
and not kill himself.
Please leave.
And still,
the two stay together forever.
Nut in truth.
But in poetry.
Yes.
Burn it.
Very well.
You may take me back now.
I'm back.
SIX MONTHS LATER
I wouldn't have thought it possible
for him to do something like this.
The whole thing is very embarrassing.
- The tendency for feelings
is a virus that has infected
young people everywhere.
Reason is on the retreat.
Old virtues are fading, Kaspar.
He's being detained here.
Johann.
It was my mistake. I overestimated you.
I treated you like a young man,
yet you are but a child.
Until you come to your senses
you will stay in Frankfurt.
There you will work in my chambers
under strict supervision.
Who crammed these crazy ideas
into your head?
An early death is a pointless life.
- Leave it, Father.
I am my own hell.
Hey, make way!
Make Way!
Where are we?
- Home.
But some people are blocking the street.
- Out of the way!
Make Way!
Excuse me, what is going on here?
- Haven't you heard?
Have you been living under a ruck?
- He can't be from here.
You assured me. I paid you
three days ago.
- Please, calm down, gentlemen!
I beg of you. Please calm down.
The day after tomorrow...
The day after tomorrow
I will get new copies.
The printer has promised me.
Maybe as soon as tomorrow.
What can I do?
I can't print them myself.
The people
seem to like your scribblings.
What is that?
And it doesn't even rhyme.
THE SORROWS OF YOUNG WERTHER
Lotte?
Shit!
You would've made
a wretched lawyer anyway.
That's him! It's Johann Goethe!
I know him from university. Goethe,
with an "oe"!
Thank you. Thank you.
Get your head out.
Our Goethe.
- He simply writes
the must banal of stories.
- Boy loves girl.
Girl marries another.
- Boy blows his brains out.
Here's to passion.
- To "Sturm"... - And drink!
I think he is expected. Go on!
Get out there!
That's my sun!
My sun.
Johann Goethe.
It's our story.
It would be an honor to publish it.
I have one last question.
Is this really what happened?
Is it all true?
It is more than truth.
It is poetry.
The Sorrows of Young Werther made
23-year-old Goethe famous across Europe.
Werther's story sparked off a youth
movement and led to a wave of suicides.
Lotte bore Kestner many children.
She saw Johann only one more time.