There is a place
That is so hard to find
Behind the walls
We build inside our minds
Some break the walls
some break the rules
Some even get things changed
And when they do
that leads to the truth
Yet questions still remain
But all that it's saying
Somewhere in life
there's a joy to be
Between the hope and reality
There in a mirror
and then the street
That's where you'll find
People in search of a life
And what of love
Is that a point of view
And when you're alone
It can seem so confused
That's when a friend
can pull you in
Lend you a helping hand
But what happens when
your only friend
Sells you out in the end
How do you face it
Somewhere in life
there's a joy to be
Between the hope and reality
There in a mirror
and then the street
That's where you'll find
People in search of a life
In search of a life
Searchin'
Lookin' in a bottle
Lookin' in a needle
Lookin' in the street,
yeah, yeah, yeah
Searchin'
Everywhere
Straight from Brooklyn
better known as Crooklyn
Never take us short
cos Brooklyn's the borough
Straight from Brooklyn
better known as Crooklyn
Never take us short
cos Brooklyn's the borough
We did it like that
and now we do it like this
Yeah.
Now the clock hits
who got the cocaine
Don't tell me it's
the little kids on Soul Train
The metaphor sent
from my brain to my jaw
It comes from other places
not the typical places
Journalistic values are yellow
and then the court falters
You watch Channel Zero
and that bitch Barbara Walters
She'll have you believe
black invented crack
When President Lyndon had to form
a law way back in '63 with Kennedy
Yes, the double-cross
Remember that's when they blew
his fucking head off
Vietnam vets come back lookin'
like one-armed pets
Mixin' thoughts, purer text
No picket fence,
no job, no ATM in the car
Blue collar comes to bourgeois
Depressed in your chest...
- Chuck D is the bomb, boy.
- What?
Get the fuck outta here.
Chuck D ain't shit.
That nigger Chuck D is assed out,
and the rest of Public Enemy.
Speech, motherfucker. What about him?
Speech? He a bitch-ass nigger.
How the fuck this thing gonna say
Chuck D the hardest rapper?
- Nigger ain't never shot nobody.
- You gotta be hard nowadays!
First, I know niggers
ain't slappin' bitches up.
They ain't takin' pussy.
Niggers ain't shootin' up,
ain't done time for murder.
How the fuck they hard?
Do what you gonna do. I ain't buyin'
shit that ain't hard-core.
You ain't gotta shoot nobody
to prove you're hard-core.
- What kinda shit is that?
- Hold on.
Only niggers I have representin'
is my man Tupac, G-Rap and Wu-Tang.
- Motherfuckin' Dr Dre, straight up.
- You said it. No fuckin' around.
Niggers talkin'
all this positive shit.
Motherfuckin' world ain't positive.
That's why motherfuckin'
sex and violence sell more records.
I like positive rappers, get it?
- Get the fuck outta here.
- Them niggers ain't homeboys.
Put them poor-ass niggers over there.
Come on, come on, yo, yo.
Forget that shit, man.
We gots to be about business.
And, Go, you ain't
supposed to be over here.
Get your ass over there!
You supposed to be on the lookout.
- This ain't no joke.
- It's hot outside, man.
We gots to get that money.
I understand that, too,
but it's hot, man.
Psst!
- What's up, man?
- What's up, man? How ya doin'?
- It's cool.
- What you need?
- What you got today?
- I got red caps. They're phat.
- Two for one, man.
- Lemme take two.
Two? All right, brother.
Just hang tight, all right?
- Everything all right, man?
- Yeah.
Shit, you know that, man.
Children of the ghetto
Runnin' wild and free
In a country's jungle
Filled with misery
There's no inspiration...
What's up, man?
You got the money?
To brighten up their day...
Keep an eye out, all right?
Raise up!
Motherfucker! Come here!
Get off me, man! Get off me!
Strike, where's the fuckin' dope?
Stand the fuck up.
Where the vials at, man?
I know you're carrying.
Collars for dollars. What the fuck
is this? The local church?
Yes, yes. Ah, gotcha.
- What you doin'?
- Don't be touchin' me, man.
I got nothin', man!
Get off my ass! I don't be playin'
that maricone shit.
- I love the smell of surprise...
- Smell your fuckin' breath.
It smells
like victory, brother!
Always in the news
Toughness is their motto
And bitter are their blues...
Open your fuckin' mouth.
Lift up your fuckin' tongue.
Lemme see under your tongue. Open.
Take off your fuckin' pants,
or whatever you call 'em.
Dicky check time.
Spread your butt cheeks, man.
Spread 'em. Let's go.
Let's see under your balls.
You know I hate doin' this.
Lemme see under your ball bag.
Strike's balls.
Strikes and balls. Yo!
Three-two, full count.
Bases loaded. With bacon strips.
- Pull up your pants, bitch.
- Man, where's your personal hygiene?
You're a motherfuckin' liar. I change
my drawers every day. I stays clean!
Let's get the fuck outta here.
It's over!
- See you later, bro.
- Fuck you, too, man.
Fuck whoever you beeper...
Guys!
Some niggers had you assed out.
Glad to be of service!
Somebody gonna drop
a cylinder block on your ass!
Take that gun and badge!
Ain't got the stomach
for this shit no more.
You see my doctor yet?
You go see my doctor
like I told you?
That Moo shit is what's killin' you.
Get rid of that shit.
Here. Drink that.
Not the whole thing.
Yo, Rodney.
Can't take it much longer, man.
I'm tellin' you.
Maybe you won't have to
take it much longer.
You know who that is?
That's Darryl.
That's Darryl Adams, the thief.
That's who that is.
He's stealin' from me.
Layin' back in the cut, passin'
some baggies and rakin' in the dough.
Nice indoors work, huh, Darryl?.
Clean, safe.
You got this clown
in there sellin' ounces?
Why him? What's up with me?
Cos you like my son, man.
Strike, my son.
If I'm so much your son, why my black
ass always on them benches?
I need you to be
where I need you to be.
Had this dream last night.
I'm standin' in the desert
with all my kids.
My for-real kids,
my kids from the store.
They's all laid out in front
of me like they's my army.
God comes up, points at you.
Tells me, "This one right here is
gonna be your sword and your staff. "
God, man. God said that.
He pointed right at you.
Darryl Adams wasn't even in
the motherfuckin' dream,
cos that boy's a thief,
and he got to be got.
- "Got"?
- Got.
Can't you get Errol
for that shit, man?
You know Errol
gave hisself the Big "A".
The virus.
My man messed around
and took that "A" train.
Anyway, can you see Errol in there,
sellin' whale on a bun
and ounces and fries?
Nah.
Strike, you really want
to get off the benches?
You deal with it...
for me.
The illa killa
the one for the thriller
The one from the hood
actin' like a gorilla
I need the illa killa
the one for the thriller
The one from the hood
actin' like a gorilla...
You got any chocolate Moos?
No, we don't got
no damn chocolate Moos.
- This is a bar, son.
- Mooooo.
- Yo, Ronnie!
- Oh, shit.
- What's up, man?
- What you doin' here, man?
You know, just slidin' through.
Yo, big bro.
I was just thinkin' about you, man.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Yeah, well, I love you, too, Ronnie.
All right. Good. Good.
The chick is in a hole cos she
shouldn't have freakin' shot...
Here. Try this. It's sweet.
- You know that's Ahab's over there.
- What?
- Yeah, the competition.
You know that clown that works
in there? The night manager, Darryl?.
- Darryl?. No.
- Darryl Adams.
Yo, the brother is bad peoples.
Now, how is, uh...
How is Darryl Adams bad people?
Cos, yo, he beat up
this honey Charise, man.
She's only 16, kid.
She came in askin' for a job.
This nigger took her
to the back office,
talkin' 'bout "slob my johnson".
And when she said no, he started
slappin' her up and shit.
Yo, the brother's foul.
- A woman beater.
- Yup.
A dope-dealin' woman beater.
Man, I don't know about all that.
- Who's sayin' all this?
- Yo, man, the shit is real.
Her moms is mad stressed out
about that shit.
She wants some
motherfuckin' payback, yo.
She wants to see that man dead.
What if it was you, your daughter?
Charise is her only child.
He just got to be got, huh?
Well?.
Yo, got ya, comin' at ya
chrome to the dome...
- Wasn't that your favourite song?
- Come on, man.
Vic, why you fuckin' with me, man?
I'm tryin' to kick
some serious shit here.
Should've known I couldn't
come to see you about nothin'.
I know somebody.
Who?
- My Man.
- Well, who that?
Look, My Man. A friend of a friend.
He'll do the job.
- How much he talkin' about?
- Nothin'.
So what's the deal?.
I'm listenin'.
What you want me to do?
Nothin', man. All right?
Just chill. All right?
So my little mans,
my nephews, how they doin'?
I miss my kids, man.
Why don't you just
take your ass home then?
There's the motherfucker.
What's up, Strike?
Yo, black, we closed.
Besides, I thought
you don't eat this shit
because it fucks with your stomach.
This is Ahab's, nigger.
We ain't got no Di-Gel,
no Kaopectate, no pussy-Bismol!
Boom! Gotcha!
Boom. Gotcha.
You still here, motherfucker?
What's up?
Mylanta! We need more Mylanta
out here for this girl!
Boom!
Probably a fuckin' triple-header.
Outdoors in the mud,
60 casings around,
and a big herd of Nubians
stepping all over everything, man.
- Alla salute.
- Mazel tov.
Ahh! I just don't like
them aeroplane bottles.
What the fuck happened?
- Oh, that boy got shot up!
- Who did?
I wouldn't know. I wasn't here, so
I can't talk intelligently about it.
Yo, uh... I wouldn't want you
not to talk intelligently.
The body cold already.
Excuse me. Coming through. Thank you.
Damn! Excuse me
Hey! Welcome to the show
that never ends.
Bartucci, what you got?
We got a black male, dead man.
Darryl Adams, 22 years old.
He's the night manager of this joint.
Kid's standin' by the door having
a conversation with another male.
Pop, pop, poppity-pop.
Darryl goes down.
Shooter does a Carl Lewis.
Neighbourhood says
there's four shots fired.
At this point, that's all she wrote.
- Robbery?
- Nah. Way too fast.
Drugs? Was he a scumbag?
To tell you the truth,
I never seen this kid before.
Boys, Darryl Adams.
Darryl Adams, the boys.
- Hey, Darryl.
- Hello in there.
Live by the gun,
die by the gun.
- The kid had brains.
- Good thing he was wearin' his gold.
Bing, bing, bing. Ricochet Rabbit.
I still think it was the food here.
Hal, get in there,
tell me what you got.
There she blows.
Let's see.
No powder burns on the face.
- These eyes have lied.
- Looking about 30, 35 years old.
- Doors one and two.
- OK, let's see.
Nothin' up the sleeve.
He might get better,
but he ain't never gettin' well.
- And presto!
- Hey, slapped him five.
On the light hand side.
Hey, look at that. Looks like some
kind of an Egyptian peace sign.
You're right there. It says goodbye.
Hey, Moe. My main man.
Gonna need prints off that door.
Fuck you, Rocco.
That'll really narrow it down
We'll get half the yos
in Brooklyn off this door.
- What, did you eat at Ahab's Burger?
- Yeah.
- You owe me six more.
- I love my job, too.
More prints than my ex-wife.
- He wearing any?
- Be with you in a second.
Must be his golf jacket.
It's got 18 holes.
Oh, Christ!
What the fuck did he eat?
Come out, come out,
wherever you are
The monkey's on the trolley car
Looks like they did come out.
Here's one. Two. Two exits.
What's the grapevine say?
What they always say.
"We keep our ear to the grindstone. "
- Was he clockin'?
- I don't know.
- Hal, how ya doin'?
- How ya doin', Lar.
- Check the pockets.
- Yeah.
Son of a bitch! That's Darryl Adams!
Who?
He worked in Rodney's candy store.
I saw him a lot.
If he worked for Rodney,
he was clockin'.
- Hal, check the pockets again.
- Sure. Hold on.
- Nothin'.
- What's up, Darryl?.
Clockin' like a motherfucker, man.
You guys done yet?
Ho! Marvello the magician!
- Catch a bullet with his teeth.
- What a catch!
- What a smile.
- Darryl, you've outdone Willie Mays.
You got my vote for MVP.
Another stain on the sidewalk, huh?
Get a pail and a mop.
Get it over with.
One, two, three.
Arrivederci!
All right. Show's over!
Officers, send 'em home!
- See ya, Hal.
- Take care.
Yo, Moe, don't make me have to come
back for those fuckin' prints!
- What you cursin' about?
- I'm sorry.
Beep beep.
Excuse me.
All right. I won't do it gain.
I'm outta here, man.
- Got 50 bucks?
- Nah, man.
Well, all I find, all I keep.
Don't be lookin' at me
in the eye, nigger.
Your ass will be on this mural, too.
I know that look.
See, you wonderin' how
I got that AIDS, ain't ya?
- Nah, man.
- You a lyin' motherfucker!
It wasn't from fuckin'
with them punks.
I ain't no homosexual.
No, man, I ain't say
all that, all right?
Fuckin' with this shit.
I can't believe I got this shit.
All this time
in these motherfuckin' streets!
And I'm a smart motherfucker.
I know I should've
left that shit alone.
One time I was studyin'
to be an accountant.
Now this shit is fuckin' my body up.
I have a goddam death sentence.
That's why I don't
give a shit about nobody.
And I don't wanna
see your ass no more!
Cos you ain't got no business
out here fuckin' with this shit.
You'll end up like me. Or worse.
My old man...
was a preacher.
And when I started messin'
with this shit,
he said, "You gonna pay for that.
"You gonna pay for that shit, boy. "
He was right.
You can't cheat this shit no... mo'.
Get the fuck outta here!
Why you wanna be
always arguin' with me?
No, wait. Listen to me.
How many pair sneakers you got?
- The pair I got on makes six.
- Yo, Rodney.
- Wait a second. Six, right?
- Yeah.
- How many pair o' feet you got?
- Two, like everybody else.
He don't see what I'm talkin' about.
- You don't, do you?
- What, man?
How you gonna make ten and spend ten,
nigger? Ten minus ten make what?
- Zero.
- You wanna be a zero nigger?
- I don't want me no zero nigger.
- You ain't got one.
Right. Now you see
what I'm sayin' to you?
Nigger wanna spend
all his money like that
gonna wake up broke
every day of his life.
Why? Cos the nigger
don't believe in hisself.
Thinkin' like a two-minute clock
instead of the long haul.
Long term. See your future.
Y'all come work for me,
this shit gonna be very different.
You gonna be savin' crazy money.
You gonna buy your moms
a house in Strong Island. Right?
Everybody stick out your hands
like this, palm down.
- What you all see?
- Black.
- What you see?
- You 'posed to be seein' green.
All right. You get it, man?
No. You get it, nigger? You get it?
- I got it.
- All right.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
- You all have a job to do inside?
- Yeah.
Well, let's go. Who trash?
What's the matter with you?
Man, you ain't heard what happened?
I ain't heard nothin'.
You told me if I wanted
to get off them benches...
All's I hear is that Ahab's
lookin' for a new night manager.
I heard that.
Look here. You gonna chill
for a week or two, right?
Let the shit die down.
Be workin' still at my spot.
You gonna be on the benches,
but Ahab is the joint.
I'm tellin' you.
I got it. I'm all right.
Nigger look bad, boy.
What we're gonna do, we're gonna mix
the shit up with the food traffic.
Right? See, right now, we're doin'
way too much business from my spot.
We got a crowd of black,
white customers,
out-of-state license plates,
what have you.
Somebody gonna check that out. They
gonna drop a dime on me, call 911.
With my jacket,
I can't go back to jail.
Ahab gonna be a nice front.
You did good, Strike.
You did good.
Now why you lookin' like that?
Somethin' wrong?
You know it's me and you, right?
What I tell you?
You like my son, right?
I'm gonna look out for you. Right?
- I ain't let you down yet, have I?
- Nah.
OK, then.
Come in here. I'm gonna get
somethin' to eat for you.
Come on.
Strike. What's up with
that train set you got?
- It's all right.
- Fuckin' Choo-Choo Charlie.
You readin' a train book? Choo-choo!
Every man should have a hobby.
What's yours? Collectin' welfare?
That shit ain't funny, man. Word up.
Why you tryin' to play me, Strike?
I don't talk about them...
Fuck that, man!
I don't talk about them toys
inside your crib.
Yeah, I know, cos I'll
bust your motherfuckin' ass.
Yo, Shorty, what you laughin' at?
- One time says freeze!
- Fuck!
Hey, little man. Stay right there.
Stand up, mastermind.
Hmm. Oh. Is that Rodney?
- Rodney rang?
- You oughtta know.
- Y'all hear that noise about Darryl?.
- Yeah, man.
Yeah, well, I had to tell
his moms and pops last night.
That ain't no joke. I hate it.
Rough.
I just hope I never have to notify
none of your parents.
Leave this shit alone!
How them trains comin'?
Little man, come here. Come here.
What'd I tell you about bein' around
these knuckleheads? Huh?
Now, I'm watchin' you.
Go on upstairs.
Yo, Andre. Why don't you go chase
some criminals or somethin'?
Yo, Shorty. What you lookin' at?
Yo, come here, man.
Yeah, you. Come here.
Come on. Hurry up.
Quick. Time is money.
Come here.
God damn, Shorty!
This is some nappy shit.
When the last time you been
in a barber shop?
I don't know.
'Put your hands up. '
Ding-ding, ding, ding, ding,
ding, ding, ding, ding!
Watch out. Flip. Shoot.
Yo.
Watch out! Duck! Now what? Come on.
Throw us somethin' else.
Yo!
- Where you manners at?
- Thanks.
- What's your name, Shorty?
- Tyrone Jeeter.
All right. Shorty.
Yo, there goes
my brother, Victor. Shit.
- Wait here, all right?
- All right.
Be right back.
Vic!
Uh! Watch out! Oh, man!
Uh! Uh! Flip!
- Who did this? Huh? Who did this?
- ¿Qué?
Who did this? Who did this?
Who did this?
Who's tryin' to be my son's daddy
and gave him this haircut?
Nobody don't know
nothin' now, huh?
Yo no sé nada.
I know you. I know you.
Cedric Stanley Gilmore.
And I know you, too. Ronnie Dunham.
Shit.
You used to live
next door to me, remember?
I know your mother. Gloria.
You all ain't nothin' but a bunch of
good-for-nothin', death-dealin' scum.
I find out who's been
messin' with Tyrone,
I'm gonna put a bullet
in your butt my own damn self.
Don't let me find Andre either.
Have a good Sunday.
Shit. I know that bitch
ain't talkin' to me.
- Scientific, man, shut up.
- You shut up, man.
OK, Victor? Ready to go?
Normally I'd cuff you, brother,
but you look like
the kind of guy I can trust.
Like I said.
I had some drinks at Kool Breeze.
- Uh, Scotch.
- "Some"?
Like two or three.
I usually go in there
after most work nights.
Uh-huh. How long were you in there?
Uh, I don't know.
About eight-thirty till about ten.
Uh, see... My shift... at Hambones -
I'm a... I'm a manager.
It don't end till ten.
I wasn't feelin' very good,
so I left early.
You weren't feelin' good,
so you went to Kool Breeze?
It wasn't like it was a "goin' home"
not feelin' good.
You had a headache? An argument?
No, I just... just tired, man.
Go ahead.
So I left Kool Breeze,
uh, started walkin' home.
I cut through Ahab's parking lot.
And this guy just flexed on me, man.
He jumped outta nowhere.
I got scared. You know the rest.
Tell me, Victor.
I just... I shot him.
Hey, little man.
I like that cut.
- Where'd you get it?
- Barber shop.
You know, you used to have
a good head on your shoulders
before Rodney got a hold of you.
Still do.
You know, Ronald, I been lookin' out
for you since you been yea high.
Now, you don't want my guidance?
Fine. It's your life.
Let me tell you somethin'.
You even glance in the direction
of that little kid Tyrone,
and I'm gonna fuck you up so bad
you're gonna wish I had killed you.
Now, do we have an understanding?
Do we have an understanding?
Yeah.
Why do we keep goin' through this?
I told you already.
The guy jumped outta nowhere, I
got scared... Bam! Then I ran. I ran!
You mean bam, bam, bam, bam.
- What?
- Four bullets in the body.
- Where did you carry the gun?
- In my gym bag.
What else you carry in it?
My uniform from Hambones,
a sandwich from home.
I don't eat Hambones myself,
as quiet as it's kept.
OK. Was the, uh,
gym bag zippered, locked?
Don't shake your head, Victor.
- Where's my mattresses?
- What?
I told you about my mattresses
for them kids.
They ask, "You say we gonna have
a tumblin' club. We need mattresses. "
And I say, "Well, Strike's
buyin' 'em. He promised. "
Now, look, I ain't busted you yet,
but till I do,
you gonna be my main benefactor.
You gonna sponsor this club,
you understand me?
And, Ronald, I'm only tellin'
you one more time, you hear?
The store was closed.
One of them Jewish holidays.
- What Jewish holiday?
- I don't know. Pick one.
Tomorrow, all right?
I swear, I'll swing by tomorrow.
Andre, these cuffs is too tight, man.
You and me used to be tight.
Am I under arrest?
What for?
Could you uncuff me, please,
and let me outta here?
You don't have to live like this.
There's more than just these projects
out there, you know.
Don't you wanna go someplace
you never been?
I mean, you love trains,
but you've only ridden the subway.
Go on, man. Get outta here.
And get them mattresses
for my kids, hear?
- Never.
- Never?
You never walked by
on a hot day with your two kids?
- Stopped in for a soda?
- With my two kids?
I barely see my two kids.
I'm always working.
When I get home, I'm exhausted.
Do you have any kids?
Yeah. I have
a two-year-old daughter.
Have you ever come home so tired
you hated the sound
of your own kids cryin'?
Your own flesh and blood.
My wife, Sharon, says,
"Quit a job. You got two. "
What the hell she thinks I got
two jobs for in the first place?
Look, I'm... I'm tryin', man.
I am really tryin'
to move us out of the projects.
You know what I'm sayin'?
I'm working, I'm saving,
I'm trying to do the best I can.
Provide those ends. I gotta work.
I'm never late. I gotta work.
Victor, listen to me.
You're a good, decent,
church-goin', God-fearin' kid.
And if you did pull the trigger,
there has to be a reasonable answer
other than what you've told me here.
I gotta ask myself, why would Darryl,
the night manager at Ahab's,
try to rob you
in his own parking lot?
So I think it had to be personal.
Mm-mm. No.
I never saw him before in my life.
- He flexed, you shot?
- I'm through with it.
I told you what happened.
What else do you want?
- The truth.
- The truth is lookin' at you!
If he did something, if he threatened
your family, this helps you.
You were buggin' - "can't sleep,
can't eat". This helps you in court.
What did that prick do to you?
It was self-defence.
Self-defence, huh?
I wanna see what you see.
Uh. I disagree.
I don't think I do look
that fuckin' stupid.
Dang, man. In the papers.
I thought Vic was legit.
What happened?
Boy already had like five jobs.
Aw, shit, man! What the fuck
the homo-cide want now?
235 Hoyt,
Mandela projects, all right?
- Yo, Tyrone.
- What's up?
Come over here and watch
the car for me, all right?
- All right?
- Yeah, cool. What you gonna give us?
Catch you in a little bit.
We ain't gonna do it
for free.
I'll take care
of you later.
Excuse me, sir.
Which building is 235 Hoyt?
- Right there.
- Thank you.
Is that Nintendo or Sega?
- Sega.
- What's it called?
- "Gangsta. "
- Whatever happened to Tiddlywinks?
Rocco, don't you know this is
the new sensation across the nation?
- Where you goin'?
- My friend's house.
Everybody wants
to be a gangsta, right?
Yeah, you like that, right?
You like lookin' at that, right?
- Wanna know how much it costs.
- I know that.
Yeah, I'm sure.
Probably want to buy one, right?
How you know I don't got one?
- Why did he have that gun?
- Everybody has one.
- Does he drink a lot?
- He only drank at night.
That makes two of us.
- How about drugs?
- He's clean as the Board of Health.
Did he have
any new friends recently?
- Hangin' out with any new people?
- Not that I know of.
You must be thinking of Ronald,
but he hasn't lived here in a while.
- He's quite the athlete.
- Yes.
- You boys must be proud of your dad.
I'll bet. Something's not right.
When I'm workin' on something,
I gotta make it right.
These are my two sons,
Victor and Ronald.
Victor's a hard-working,
handsome young man.
He doesn't lie. If he said it was
self-defence, it was self-defence.
Why don't you believe him?
Do you mind
if I borrow these?
I have to go around and retrace
his steps the other night,
- and I'd rather not show a mug shot.
- Sure.
You be good boys.
Take care of your mother.
- Strike.
- You know him?
He's an arrogant piece of shit.
Comes into my store all the time
like he craps beige.
He used to work with Rodney
last year in his store, with Darryl.
Now he runs the crew on the benches.
Clocks for Rodney just like Darryl.
Let's bring him in.
- What up, man?
- They went to the ninth floor.
Shit! I knew it.
- Did they say anything?
- Asked me about "Gangsta".
- Anything else?
- Nah.
All right, Shorty.
You did good, man.
Go upstairs before your mom
come down flippin'.
All right.
Go on upstairs.
- Who you hidin' from?
- Come on, man.
What you sneakin' up on me for?
I'm not gonna keep tellin' you
to leave him be.
- Tell him!
- How you feel about your brother?
It's fucked up, man.
I heard he confessed.
You been to see him?
I'm goin'. I'm goin'.
You need to have your stomach
checked out.
By the way, my kids thank you
from the bottom of their hearts
for their mattresses.
Now doesn't that make you feel good?
You know this kid?
- Yep. He was in here.
- When?
Boy was in here Friday.
He had one drink.
- One drink? Wasn't drunk?
- Nope.
- He was rude.
- Yeah.
'Ooh! I'm just gettin' warmed up.
But it's The Bomb. '
Was he with anybody?
He came in alone.
Might've had a conversation.
Can't recollect.
Do you recollect the shooting?
Hell, yeah.
Who do you think called the cops?
So that's who you're lookin' for?
Do you remember if the kid was here
before or after the shooting?
He was in here before.
You know how I know?
Cos I was watchin' him.
I never saw him before. He was jumpy.
Thought he might have been
one of those stick-up kids.
This is Strike. Jesus Christ.
They don't look alike to me.
What about him?
Oh, yeah. Victor? A regular.
What's up with him?
Strike, how come you didn't tell me
your brother did it?
Come on, Rodney, man.
What, you forgot?
- You told me you didn't wanna know.
- Yeah, you right.
Victor popped Darryl?.
Hey, I don't know if he even did it.
Victor your brother.
You supposed to know.
Errol, Errol, just...
We ain't had that conversation
about Darryl, did we?
What conversation?
There, you see? Ain't no problem.
Go ahead, man. Break.
That's my boy!
Came in one night only,
on the night of the shooting.
Has the jumps. Never sat down.
Left sober before the shooting.
Yo's jacket shows
possession with intent,
possession of unlicensed firearm,
and assault, for which
he still owes three years.
Listen to me, Rocco.
He's all strung out.
Has a few schnorts over his limit.
He gets fried, walks out of Kool
Breeze with the heater in his bag.
The Adams guy jumps out,
startles him.
Pops the first guy
who steps on his Nikes.
It's like a capper on a bad day.
That's how these Nubians do it. He
gets religion, comes in, gives it up.
I'm not wasting my time on this.
Come on, Larry. Can't you see
what they're tryin' to pull?.
Larry. Yo walks in,
says he's the shooter.
No record,
two adorable kids, two jobs.
Model citizen. Claims self-defence.
- OK. All right.
- Who's gonna argue?
Now, this other one... Strike.
If he tried that, they'd throw
the key away. He's a known scumbag.
No wonder this sounds like horseshit.
He's lying.
Victor never got off that bar stool.
- Yo was taken away for his brother.
- For what?
Brotherly love?
Fear? For money? What?
They ran a game on me, these two,
cos this cocksucker
is an innocent man.
Just because a Nubian -
excuse me, Lieutenant -
got a wife, a job, kids,
a dog and a bank account,
he can't be a shooter?
You did everything but stick
your tongue down his throat.
The kid didn't budge.
Rocco, listen to me.
Even if this Victor kid is sellin' us
a line of shit on the tape...
which is what they all do anyhow,
even if they're givin' it up...
this is still a good,
solid "closed by arrest".
And if I'm wrong, and Rodney
conspired in on this, or Strike...
or the fuckin' Medellín cartel,
I don't give a fuck.
Cos we got the shooter.
We locked up the wrong brother.
The wrong brother. Yeah. Yeah.
Well, it's on you, OK?
What I want to know is where the fuck
did these yos get balls big enough
to think that they could
put this one past me?
I'm tired of hearin' that "yo" shit
from you. Back off.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant. Excuse me.
I don't mean any offence.
Anybody can bust off an oowop.
What makes Vic any different?
Come on, man.
Papers say he had a.38.
- Regardless what the papers say.
- Wait, motherfucker.
When was the last time
you bust off an oowop?
I never murdered nobody,
but I'm gonna murder someone now!
Yo, yo, chill. Hold it, man. Kill
that noise. Homo-cide creepin' up.
How you doin', fellas?
Look who's here.
Ronnie Dunham, big man.
- Ronnie?
- Can I talk to you a minute?
Go on, bitch.
I'm Rocco Klein,
DA's Homicide Squad.
- You got a minute?
- Homo-cide.
I'm doin' the Darryl Adams job.
Your brother, you know?
How's he doin'?
Wouldn't know. Haven't seen him yet.
That's no joke in there.
You been in?
Just overnight on a confusion.
Wasn't no thing.
Errol. I thought you were dead.
I was. I came back.
Mr Barnes waiting for you?
Nah, not me.
I'm not happy about this.
Your brother fessed up,
but it was some bullshit explanation.
Ronnie, you know what he told us?
How the fuck would I know?
I wasn't there.
- Wasn't there?
- Where he was telling you all this.
What do you think happened?
Got me.
You think him and Darryl
had some static? A beef?
- Did you know Darryl Adams?
- No, no, no.
- You didn't know Darryl Adams?
- Nah, man.
I never met him, nothin'. Nah.
When's the last time
you saw your brother?
- It's been a while.
- Week, month, year?
- Yeah.
- Which one?
Two months.
Two months?
You wanna get that?
What you talkin'? That ain't mine.
What do you know?
Ronnie, I was lookin' for
some help, some insight.
Your brother's got those kids,
your nephews.
Hey, maybe the guy was a crackhead.
Darryl?. A crackhead?
Crackin' up? Says who?
Ain't nobody sa... It's just...
It's just around, you know.
You know what I'm tryin' to say.
- You clocking?
- Nah.
- How long you been clocking?
- What is you? Deaf? I don't hustle.
Look. Here's my card.
You hear anything...
boom - pick up the phone.
- Boom.
- Good.
I'll be seein' ya around, Ronnie.
Cos I wouldn't do this
Lord, if I tried...
- What he want?
- Somethin' about my brother.
This is from Rodney.
He say whack it up...
into ounces.
He'll hit you off... later.
Yeah, all right.
- Jo-Jo. You know Rodney Little?
- Sure.
- Rodney's got this yo, Strike.
- Likes to drink the chocolate Moos.
I need yo to talk to me. You mind
laying some cards on him for me?
- Depends.
- Need him to sweat.
- What'll you do for me?
- Nothin' you don't do for yourself.
Strike, my man!
This is a new day, Strike.
Dinkins out, Rudy in. Law and order.
Cut the budget. Party's over.
Crackdown on drugs, crime, niggers,
spics, homeless, squeegeemen,
African-Americans.
Have a seat. So what's up?
Not a thing, Detective.
Detective? Call me Jo-Jo.
You like basketball?.
Nah. I don't like sports.
- What do you like?
- Trains.
Choo-choo trains?
You can't dunk a basketball?.
- Nah.
- Nah. Get the fuck outta here, man.
You been slammin'
before you was crawlin'.
All right, listen.
I'm here cos I like you.
I do. Now, tomorrow night's
gonna be knocko night.
We're coming down on these projects
like a fuckin' broom.
So if I was you,
I'd take my homies out, say 9pm,
for some chocolate Moolies
or whatever it is you drink,
till about 11, bet?
Yeah, bet.
I look out for you,
you look out for me.
- Yeah, all right.
- No, no, no. No "all right".
I look out for you,
you look out for me.
- You look like 500.
- 500. That's a start.
Good. Every week, I look out for you.
I tell you when we're hittin'. Week
in, week out, you look out for me.
- Cool?.
- Cool.
This is my man Kirby.
Kirby gonna double back in
like 30 minutes. You lay it on him.
You tell your boy Rodney
I got some good stuff he could use.
Finest, highest quality.
Peace out.
I think you dropped this.
If I was you,
I think I'd call this guy.
Larry.
Yo, Strike.
- Been waiting for 40 minutes...
- Who's here to see Victor Dunham?
You told me he was gonna
come down a half-hour ago.
Watch your tone,
young lady.
Aw, man. I love you. I love you, man.
- Cool, man.
- You look good.
After you, man.
Somebody got bored shaving.
So they decided
to cut me up with a razor.
And they stole my sneakers, too.
Yo, big brother.
You made the papers, man.
Ronnie...
Can you get me outta here, man?
- I'll try. What's the bail?.
- 50,000.
50?! God damn!
- What's the cash options?
- My lawyer says maybe in a week...
I can get that, um,
that ten per cent thing.
- Maybe Rodney got...
- Rodney?
Tell motherfuckers
to stop fuckin' with you.
Yeah, man.
Yeah. Yeah. Maybe.
Look, man, I'm gonna try
to get you outta here, OK?
Ronnie, some of these brothers...
some of these men...
they love jail, man.
But all this, this ain't for me, man.
I'm gonna get you
outta here, all right?
You kiss my babies for me, please?
- All right.
- Thank you.
We've been open
for about a year.
We've done pretty well so far.
When I read about it,
my heart was broken.
Victor is a sweetheart.
- Was he ever late for work?
- Never. Like Swiss movement.
- Did he ever steal?.
- No, he was honest.
- Get any visitors?
- No.
See him in here?
No.
Victor was my buffer.
He could talk and reason with them.
Anybody ever threaten him?
Open up your eyes
and realise things is tough
Your shit is my rough
when you livin' in the city
Walk with your head high
step with the bitty-bop
Got to survive
when you slam or you do or die
Cos niggers try to read through
a nigger's eyes...
May I help you?
- May I help you?
- Yeah, let me the fuck in the store.
This is a store, right?
People buy shit in the store.
- What do you wish to buy, brother?
- I wish to buy what you got.
Maybe we don't have what you want.
Unbelievable. What are you,
the security house nigger?
- What? They rent you by the hour?
- We're just trying to help...
Fuck that, man!
Cos I'm black, that automatically
mean I'm gonna steal something.
Nigger, I came in here
to buy a birthday gift for my mom!
But you ain't shit
and neither is this bullshit kung fu
Chinese bitch store!
Fuck you, motherfucker!
I'm gonna bring my steel
and pump bullets in your ass.
Think I'm playing?
You disrespectin' me
on my mother's birthday... nigger!
Listen up, man.
I G's up twice a day, man.
How much you make in a month?
See this? See this?
It's a hundred dollar bill, right?
Use it in your kid's birthday.
I'm gonna come back here.
I'm gonna kill your ass.
Thank you.
- What did he want?
- Nothin'.
- Did that kid ever come back?
- No.
- Hey, what's up, Mr Brown?
- Hey, Mr Dunham.
Yo, Ty, that's my landlord,
Mr Brown. Say, what's up?
- How you doing, sir?
- Pleased to meet you, young man.
This is Tyrone.
This is my little brother.
Anybody bother you, and his head's
out here, you let me know.
I got something
for the crackheads my damn self.
You do like your big brother.
Leave those drugs alone.
Hey, I got some food on the stove.
See ya later.
All right. Peace.
Now, go up the steps. Hurry up.
Hey, Shorty.
What you doin'? Don't touch that.
Buggin'. You know anything
about what you're touchin'?
No!
Little buster.
Lionel Trains, right?
They was built in the early 1900s.
But them cheap shits,
they only ran on dry cell batteries.
But, yo, after World War II,
when more folks started getting
electricity in their cribs,
boom, they made the new ones.
Yeah, phat, right?
Yeah.
Yo, profit's all in the cut.
Don't never forget that.
Yo, Shorty, if I ever see
or even hear about you
messin' with this stuff right here,
man, sniffin' or pipin' up...
Yo, come here, man.
The word to my mother.
Put a cap in your ass.
This ain't no TV movie
violence bullshit neither.
This stuff out here is real.
Real bullets hurt.
And real guns kills you dead.
See this right here?
This is.25 automatic.
I keeps this for all them
ill niggers out there.
Like that one dude Errol.
Now that brother's crazy.
He will blast your ass,
just won't give a fuck.
The messed-up thing is
that they never find the body.
Just the blood stains on the ground.
If he ever try to creep up on me,
I'm gonna gat his ass.
You best be ready
to do the same shit, too.
Aw, don't think
that just cos you're 12,
small and shit,
that he won't smoke you.
Just last year,
he caught himself a ten-year-old.
I knows you probably thinking about
what Mr Brown said earlier and all.
But, chill, don't even
sweat that shit, man.
He's old and po'.
He don't know what time it is.
This is how you get
that money right here.
How do you think I got
that phat-ass train set?
From pumpin'
this white shit right here.
Any fly shit you want
in this world, it costs money.
And this is how you get it. Hustling.
Don't never forget that shit neither.
Yo, Shorty, you're smart, right?
Well, answer me this.
Boss buys him a key
for $22,000, right?
Cuts it up to 3,500 $10 bottles.
Boss takes 60%, $17,000 profit,
leaving up $7,000,
50% of which is mine.
How much for me?
3,500.
My man, Shorty.
Keep hittin' them books, all right?
All right.
If I ever catch you playing hooky,
I'll put a cap in your ass.
My name is M-O
and don't you forget it
Takin' out your boys
and you don't know how I did it
Pickin' off your crew one by one
Don't step in my way
cos I just might have a gun
May be loaded just might not be
Cos I'm a menace to society
My name not Thiggy-thiggy
but I still get hip
- So back the fuck up and just
- Chill
Cos steppin' on me
you'll be a-writin' your will
I'm like an Energizer
can't never die
Ba, ba, ba, ba, nice try
Ha, ha, ha,
I saw you run in the building
Throwing up my guns
to the ceiling
Ba, ba, ba, here I go again
Ba, ba, ba, cops are comin' in
Run into the back, man
I'm fast up the staircase
I got no time to waste
Nobody seen my face
so I leave without a trace...
Make the drops over on Smith Street
from now on.
Yeah, all right.
Oh, yeah, crooked-ass Jo-Jo.
He said he got
some weight for you to buy.
Forget that motherfucker.
Fuckin' faggot.
He tapped me up for $500, too.
Errol told me you talked
to the homicide cop.
- How'd that go?
- It was aight.
"Aight" or all right?
It was "aight," all right?
I ever tell you about
the first time I killed somebody?
Nah.
Errol Barnes made me do it...
cos it was three guys burned us
on some bogus dope.
'Errol's already killed
the other two, right?
'We got the third guy. '
Be cool, man.
Chill, motherfucker, chill.
Ain't you all sorry
you fucked with us?
I ain't fucked with you.
You're lucky we don't blow your ass
off like them crackers down South.
- Look, I hate this shit, man.
- What the fuck is my name?
- Errol, man.
- You're goddam right.
'Motherfucker
crying like a baby.
'Tears, snot flying, and shit.
Errol turned to me. '
Says, "You got
to cap him, or I'm gonna cap you. "
Man, come on, that shit
ain't necessary, man.
'I ain't gonna cap that boy.
He's scared like a motherfucker. '
You think I'm playin' with you?
Open your mouth.
You gonna take this piece...
and you're gonna put that
motherfucker's brains out.
- You understand me?!
- I got it.
Go to it.
I said you shouldn't
have did that shit, man.
- Come on, please! Please!
- On three, Rodney.
I can't stop my hand from shakin'.
- Don't you chump out on me.
- I can't stop my hand from shakin'!
- Cap him!
- All right!
Please...
Don't you wish
you'd done us right?
Hey, hey, hey. Don't you
ever, ever fuck with me, boy.
Do you know me now? I'm a bad man.
Errol couldn't have me runnin'
around here knowin' what he did
without somethin' personal
hangin' over my head, too.
Personal, Strike.
Otherwise, I might give him up
someday, you understand?
Strike, that's the reason why
I needed you to be bloody
on this Darryl thing.
You hear me?
'Errol Barnes, boy. '
Motherfucker had a sawed-off
shotgun right in my mug, Strike.
He's my best friend, too.
- What's the matter with you?
- Shit!
You gotta take care of yourself.
Here. Wipe that off.
You OK?
You ain't seen my doctor, have you?
- Huh?
- Nah.
Strike, why I got to tell you things
two and three and four times, huh?
Why you don't want to listen to me?
You OK?
Shit.
To be honest, I don't really
give a fuck because you lied to me.
Lied about what? You said Darryl
had a drug problem, a crackhead.
I asked around. The guy was clean.
I was just speculatin'.
That's some nasty-ass speculatin'.
Damn. You're comin'
at me with mad questions.
I'm just tryin'
to answer them shits.
Then you said you never met 'im.
Maybe just by eye, all right?
"Just by eye. "
You and him never had any static?
Naw.
There's no way Victor could've been
cuttin' through the parking lot
in the dark, and Darryl would've
mistaken him for you?
Naw, man.
Cos you and your brother,
in the dark,
probably look like two peas in a pod.
What the fuck you sayin'?
All black people look alike at night?
I can't even tell you guys
apart in the day.
Hey, you got jokes.
- You and your brother close?
- Not really.
I forgot. Long-lost brothers.
When was the last time?
A month.
Strike, you told me
two months before.
If you know so much,
why you keep asking?
- You know what Alzheimer's is?
- Some kind of beer?
Wise guy. You visit him yet?
Yeah.
He's claimin' self-defence.
He goes to trial with that,
those two nice kids of his,
by the time he'll be gettin'
out, they'll be goin' in.
Did it ever occur to you
maybe he didn't even do the shit?
You know who did?
Who did it?
Come on, man, I gotta go. I'm sick.
- Here's my card.
- Got two already.
You better have that checked out.
Hey, what the fuck y'all lookin' at?
Oh, shit!
You all right, man?
Strike! Strike! You smokin' crack,
motherfucker, huh?
Get the fuck up!
Get an ambulance, man!
Let's get an ambulance!
Let's get him the hell
outta here.
He'll be all right. He'll be fine.
Watch it, guys.
One, two, three.
Let's go!
Here you go. It's all right, man.
- Hit that pipe today?
- Dice that shit. He don't use.
Anyone ever tell you not to do drugs?
Where do you live?
I'll give you that.
Just get him to hospital.
Welcome to Ahab's.
May I take your order, please?
Yes,
we need a Double Whaler on a bun.
'With cheese?'
Yes, with cheese.
A fried shrimp boat.
'One fried shrimp boat. '
- Two.
- Yeah, two.
'Two fried shrimp... '
Uh, could I please get my
Captain Ahab with a clam roll?.
- Captain Ahab, Captain...
- What's up, boys?
Hey, it's a nice car you got.
- Yeah, it's my dad's car.
- How ya doin'?
Power windows,
air bags, cellular phone.
Bet he paid a pretty penny for this.
Oh, yeah. We were lookin'
for the Short Hills Mall.
- It's not here.
- No?
Come down from Connecticut
just to buy some whiting?
Some golf balls.
You buy anything else around here
I should know about?
- Some gum.
- No.
You like soul food?
Can't say I do.
- You like to wear lipstick?
- Todd, why don't we get outta here?
McCauley does
in the back... occasionally.
- You like skirts?
- Something we did wrong?
- You ever suck a black man's dick?
- Let's get outta here!
A big, 16-inch tar baby?
- No?
- No.
If I toss this car and I find any
drugs, I got 12 baboons in a cage
who are gonna be callin'
you boys Mary all night.
- Come on, Todd.
- Shut up, man!
- Who's got the drugs?
- We don't have anything.
- You got five seconds.
- Todd's got the drugs!
- Shut up, man!
- Todd's got the drugs.
- Fuck you guys, man!
- Put your hands on the car.
- Take it easy!
- Fucking cocksucker!
Fucking touch him again, I'll rip
your throat out. Get your hands up.
- What's up?
- You tell me.
What you up to, man?
You the one involved
in all the drama out here.
How you always know
when I'm comin' out of somewhere?
Don't you know I know everything?
Didn't I tell you
to go see my doctor?
Didn't I tell you to stop
drinkin' that Moo shit?
Yeah, you did, you did.
No doubt, man, no doubt.
- How you so smart and so stupid?
- Cut me some slack.
I heard that Homicide came back
on you again yesterday.
He ain't sayin' I'm in.
He's just fishin'.
You and him fuck buddies now?
- You got jokes, man.
- Come on, get in, get in.
- How do you feel?.
- I'm all right.
You better be, cos we got
another big order come in.
Hey, Rod.
If God created anything better
than crack cocaine,
he kept that shit for hisself.
I mean, that shit
is like truth serum.
It will truly expose who you are.
I mean, you happen to be
a low-life rat bastard motherfucker,
who will sell off his newborn
for a suck off that glass dick,
crack will bring it
right on in the light.
I don't care you black,
white, Chinese, rich, poor.
You take that first hit,
you on a mission.
And that mission will never end.
Even when the house,
the money, loved ones are gone,
they send you to the joint,
you still gonna try to cop.
No doubt.
Only time it ends, Strike, that
mission, when you six feet under.
That's the reason I don't ever want
to hear about you using this shit.
- You understand me?
- You crazy?
All right, then.
Cos it's also the reason why
I ain't never goin' outta business.
I'm a great businessman, Strike.
And I got me the world's
greatest product.
Now you think about that.
Yo, so what up?
I'm gonna see you at the store.
- Go ahead.
- All right.
You believe I used to deal with that
woman when she looked like somethin'?
Yeah. You didn't know that, did you?
She used to look good, right?
She looked better than she look now.
- Finest shit we got today.
- Let me see.
- Yeah.
- 50 dollars.
But ain't y'all pregnant,
though, y'all?.
- You got to maintain that, man.
- We already know that.
That's the last
I'm gonna sell to y'all.
Y'all got to take care
of that little girl.
Got red caps?
I'm getting tired
of these nickels, man.
Where the dimes at, Lou?
We don't got it like that.
Come on, let's do this.
You got it?
I got reds and I got yellows.
- What you need?
- Two yellow ones.
- Want two yellows?
- I want two reds.
All right, Veronica. Slow down, girl.
Why you in such a hurry?
- Because I wanna get out of here.
- Wanna get outta here?
- Let me see this money.
- No, I said two.
- Let me see the money. Chill.
- I want yellow.
- You want yellows?
- I want reds.
It's the same shit. Both
of 'em just to crack your ass up.
- I want three of 'em.
- And I said two.
You notice the tablecloths out there,
with the African prints?
The nice carpeting and the plants
hanging from the ceilings?
It's all Victor's ideas.
You see, Victor always wanted to make
this place like somebody's home.
He treated everybody with respect.
The workers, the customers...
even the clockers.
Like, you asked me
about last Friday night.
'We got three
cocolo chocho face maricones
'trying to set up shop out there,
right in front of my business. '
I reach for my... trusty Roberto
Clemente Louisville Slugger here,
and I'm ready to bash in a head,
I'm ready to bash in an arm.
But Victor, Victor, he says...
No, Jesus, no.
Let me handle them, please.
We set somebody up
in the bathroom there.
Put somebody over there
as a lookout in the window.
Sorry, but you brothers
can't clock in here.
This is a family place,
and I need you to respect that.
Here. Take these jumbo sodas.
This is a Pepsi.
An orange. A root beer.
I would appreciate it very much...
if you would leave when
you finish your jumbo sodas.
Usually they would just be happy
to get the free jumbo sodas,
but on this night, Leroy pulls out
a roll this big and says...
My boss says that he'll pay you $300
a week if you let us set up here.
What did he say?
Victor puts please and thank you into
every sentence. So, it was either...
No. Please, thank you.
- Or...
- Please. No, thank you.
What? You tryin' to be fuckin'
burger boy of the month, man?
Wait. Your girlfriend likes you
smellin' like burgers?
No. My wife...
Oh, your wife, your wife.
Got it. I see, OK, look.
We're tryin' to do something here.
I can respect that.
You take your business outside,
and I'll handle my business inside.
You can't even smile, man. You don't
like this job. Feel that money.
- It's power.
- I need you to respect that.
I'm gonna miss you, man.
So, I have to check the floor.
I got a business to run.
- So, Hay-sus...
- I pronounce it "Jesus".
I feel more comfortable
calling you "Hay-sus".
My mother called me Jesus, my father
called me Jesus. You call me Jesus.
All right, Jesus. So is that why
Victor left early Friday?
He said he wasn't feeling well.
- Fuck. I gotta make a call.
- There's a phone out in front.
Wasn't feeling well?.
Would you feel well after working
65 hours a week in a place like this?
It'll make you sick. Try it. Give me
your badge, I'll give you my apron.
How much cheese
you make yesterday, yo?
I made like a motherfuckin' yard.
I did all right.
- Yo, Strike!
- Here comes Shorty.
- Take this.
- Shorty, what I told you?
It's yours.
I told you!
- Here comes your moms.
- Oh, shit.
- It's yours.
- You crazy?
- What did I say? Huh? You hear me?
- What are you doin'?
You hear me? I told you!
You leave my son alone!
Don't you ever put your motherfuckin'
hands in my face.
I will put my hands
wherever I want to!
You stop buying him shit.
I ain't buyin' him shit.
- Fuck!
- Go home. Go!
The Nikes,
the Sega game, the haircut!
You thought you were slick, right?
I saw him riding the bike.
You wouldn't let him bring that home.
You best stay the fuck
out of my face.
I am not scared of you.
Maybe you're scared of Andre.
You get Andre. I don't give a fuck.
You are sellin'
your own people death.
All of y'all. I'm not gonna let you
take him with you.
You hear me?
I can't let you do that.
Can't! You understand?
I'm gonna go get Andre.
She took a pop at him, the ho.
Yeah, here come your friend, man.
Now you're beatin' up
on defenceless women?
- What gives?
- Come on, man. She attacked me.
Can I talk to you a minute?
Have a seat.
Don't look so depressed.
Worse things could happen.
Hey, Ronnie, have I treated you
like a hard-on out here?
What?
Have I not treated you
like a man out here?
Talked to you
with respect, courtesy, huh?
What you talkin' about?
Why you tryin' to make
a fuckin' fool outta me?
- What you talkin' about?
- What am I talkin' about?
You told me you
didn't know Darryl Adams.
I'm running around like
a horse's ass on that.
Not only did I find out
that you know him,
but you worked a year with him
at Rodney's store.
Why the fuck didn't you tell me?
I thought you meant
this other Darryl.
What other Darryl?.
If you knew some other Darryl,
you should have said,
"Yeah, I know him," right?
- I don't get it.
- I only know one Darryl.
You said you didn't see
your brother in two months.
- Oh, God.
- You got all kind...
What? Ronnie, don't "Oh, God" me.
You got all kinds of pissed off
at me just like you are now,
- cos I forgot you said that, right?
- Yeah.
Well, guess what?
I go into the Kool Breeze,
the bar your brother was in
just before the shootin',
the bartender ID'd you
in there that night.
He even remembered the drink
he made for you.
Pina colada, straight out of a can.
Does this ring a bell?.
Why did you lie to me?
- Cos man, it's my brother.
- What's your brother?
Your brother made you lie?
Tryin' to look out for him.
Explain to me how lyin' helps him.
He's locked up.
What you sayin'?
You tryin' to pin this on me?
I didn't say that. You said that.
I asked you why you throwin' me
a line of shit. Why did you say that?
Oh, man.
See, you fuckin' with my words.
You confusin' me.
Twistin' my shits around.
Me? Oh, who's twistin' who
here, Ronnie?
All's I'm askin' is why did you
try to play me like a jerk?
- Please, stop fuckin' with me.
- What's in it for you?
What the fuck is this?
20 questions or somethin'?
We already spoke about this shit.
Hey, Ronnie! I just want to know
what you know.
Am I under arrest?
Fuck, no! If I arrest you,
I can't talk to you.
Then the conversation's over.
Fine. You don't have to do shit.
But if you wanna continue
to do business here,
without Jo-Jo and his crew puttin'
their hands in your pockets,
I would think about
takin' a ride right now.
What the fuck I look like?
I ain't goin' nowhere
with your homo-cide ass.
Look.
Shit.
Are you comin' or what?
How you doin'?
Man, you crazy, man?
I ain't goin' up in there.
No?
Yo, Rocco. Yeah, yeah, come on, come
on, man. I ain't got nothin' to say.
I was prayin'
you could help me out here.
Because to tell you the truth,
I've come completely around
to your way of thinking.
- What's my way of thinkin'?
- I know your brother is innocent.
If Victor was my brother
and I knew what you know,
every day of my life
would be a living hell.
You think we can do something
about this?
- About what?
- All bullshit aside.
You, me, Victor, we all know
who did Darryl Adams.
Who?
Who do you think?
I don't know. You tell me.
You!
- Me?
- You little fuck. You did it.
I know it, you know it!
- Your brother knows it.
- Shit.
What's the thinkin' on this,
that if Victor claims self-defence,
he'll get off
because he has no record?
His life is over!
I know it's rough out here
for young, black males
with racism, no jobs,
single parent families...
- Fuck that.
- Don't fuckin' gesture at me.
Have some fuckin' respect.
But you're the fuckin' king snake!
You're a low-down, cold-blooded,
evil junkyard nigger...
- .. like I've never seen in my life.
- What you talkin' about?
What'd you do, offer him money?
Who the fuck are you kiddin'?
You're not the Mafia.
You're not even Rodney Little! You're
a skinny-ass snake motherfucker.
You think you're hot shit. You ain't
nothing but a cold, fucking fart.
You don't know a motherfuckin' thing
about me.
You just a racist-ass,
nigger-hating cop.
You don't know how it is
for brothers.
And you motherfuckin' definitely...
- Don't point...
- .. nothin' about what's goin' on.
Don't you fuckin' point
your finger at me.
What's goin' on? What don't I see?
I ain't tellin' you shit
till I see my lawyer.
Listen. I talked to...
Look at me.
I got something nice to say.
I talked to all your brother's
people. He's one of the decent ones.
Probably in his deluded decency,
he thinks he's doing a noble thing.
But you and Victor playin' me
for a patsy? Usin' me?
Back up with that shit.
I read you like a Marvel fuckin'
Spiderman comic book!
I been inside your bald pea brain
since you were born.
20 fuckin' years!
You don't play me, I play you!
Fuck!
Rocco, you can't do this
in front of our house.
Understand? It's no good.
Strike.
You want to make yourself crazy
goin' after someone else on this?
There's your man, right over there.
Hold on.
Man, get your little ass in the car.
Fuck Rodney. Yo thinks
he's gonna okey-doke me.
He's goin' down, Larry.
Down for the fuckin' count.
Take it easy.
- How ya doin'?
- Fuck you, too, Rodney.
- Come on. Hey! Take it easy.
- I'm gonna cripple that cocksucker.
I swear on my mother's grave,
I'm gonna cripple him.
You were supposed to be
at my spot an hour ago.
What am I supposed to do?
Tell Homicide I can't talk now?
I gotta go bag up some ounces
for my boss, Rodney Little?
- He arrest you?
- Nah.
Why didn't you tell him
to go fuck hisself?
Well, what did he want?
Nothin' much.
You know, same old, same old.
- He ask about me?
- Nah.
- Huh?
- Nah. Damn.
Cos I never said nothin' to you
about shootin' nobody.
All's I said, you want Darryl's spot,
you got to get it for yourself.
- Shit, I didn't even say that.
- Fuck you, Rodney.
Excuse me. Who the fuck are you
talkin' to like that?
You outta your motherfuckin'
mind, hmm?
You think I'm one of them little crew
niggers sittin' on a project bench?
Open your mouth, nigger.
You feel that?
I put this gun in your bad breath
smellin' mouth,
I will pull the trigger.
I'll splatter
what little brains you got
all over the Corinthian
leather interior of my car.
This is my wife's brand-new car,
so you know I don't give a fuck.
- You understand?
- Yeah.
- Do you understand me, bitch?
- Yeah!
Let me tell you somethin' else.
If I ever hear about you talkin' to
that Homicide one more time,
that Rocco, I don't care
if he asks you the time of day,
if I hear about my name comin' up,
I'm gonna know it was you
and I'm gonna kill ya.
I mean, you are 1-87
on the street, understand?
- Do you understand me?
- Yeah.
Word is bond.
Now get your motherfuckin'
ass outta my car.
Who bought you this shit?
Strike bought you that shit?
Where your mama at?
She know you out here?
When I was a little boy,
my daddy would have kicked my butt
all over this street.
- I don't have a father, all right?
- You got one now.
When Errol is talkin' to you,
you listen.
- You're not my daddy.
- I'm your daddy now.
You get your butt...
You little motherfuckers,
get outta here!
Hey, look here.
Now I got to deal with this.
Look at this.
Shit.
What the fuck is he doin'?
I'm a bad man.
Errol!
Get your hand off me.
- What are you doin', man?
- Get the fuck outta here.
Errol, come here.
Step off.
Hey, Shorty.
Now, fun and games is over.
I warned your ass
about Errol, didn't I?
- Huh? Didn't I?
- What's goin' on here?
I don't want to see your ass
hangin' around me no more.
- What'd I do?
- Now take your ass home.
I don't want to see
your ass no more!
You a little nigger.
This is real nigger shit.
You need to be in school.
Get your ass up...
- I thought I was def!
- Shut the fuck up!
Take your ass home to your moms.
Get the fuck up them steps.
Hurry up, man!
- Hurry the fuck up!
- Shouldn't have taught me then.
Punk.
I busted these
four yuppie dickheads over at Ahab's.
They drove down
in Daddy's Benz to cop.
So fuckin' what?
I'm gonna use them to pinch that
motherfucking shinehead Rodney.
I got 'im set up.
You got Rodney set up?
Got that fuckin' yo
set up just like the movie.
Let me do a favour for ya.
Me and Mazilli know the prick.
Let us pick him up.
You'd owe me two favours.
You ain't gonna let me forget.
I ain't worried.
No, I won't.
I wash my face in dirty water
Cos it gives my mind a little order
And I play that game
just like I should do
But my whole world slips away
I live my life, I live it slowly
And I take my time, I'm in no hurry
Yeah, I'm livin'
And when I go
then I would surely...
Hey, Mr Mazilli.
Klein. What you need, man?
- I need you, brother.
- Oh, yeah?
- For what?
- I got me a warrant on ya.
- Warrant for what?
- Arrest.
You want to arrest me?
For what, Mazilli?
You must have sold
to an undercover, man.
Oh, man, please!
You so desperate
you sellin' shit yourself?
Excuse me.
All right.
- Who tryin' to set me up?
- What do I know?
- Come on, man.
- I'm Homicide, man.
How long we been
doin' business, huh?
All of a sudden
it don't count for nothin'?
All I know is, somebody says
Rodney's your buddy.
He's not gonna break balls
if you go in. So?
Right, Rodney?
Rocco Klein, Rocco Klein.
I always wanted to ask you.
You Italian, you a Jew? What are you?
You can't make up your mind?
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
I'm from the lost Black Tribe
of Israel, the Yos.
Now put the rag away, lock up,
get your shit, and let's go.
I'm a businessman, all right?
I'm tryin' to make a dollar.
- Yeah, I'm proud of ya. Let's go.
- We got a job, too, OK?
Skyler, go find Errol.
Tell him to come down
and mind the store for me.
Tell my wife to get
my bail money together, too.
Give Errol my best, all right?
Better put a leash
on that psychopath.
'The Santa Fe F-3.
'Considered the most attractive
paint scheme on any railroad. '
"Dear, Mr Herman Brown,
"I had to leave suddenly,
but I'll be all right.
"If... my...
"little... brother... "
'It wasn't long before
the Santa Fe dominated... '
".. swings... by... "
'Today, we're going to examine
all 12 F-3 road names... '
".. he... can... have...
"my... train... set. "
'Western Pacific, Southern...
'Texas Special... Wabash...
Illinois Central...
'Baltimore and Ohio...
'Milwaukee Road... Rio Grande...
'Canadian Pacific and the New Haven.
'We will concentrate
on the characteristics
'of the shells and the paint
of over 40 original variations.
'We will make our point-by-point
analysis of actual... '
God damn, man! Who stole my gat?
- Who set me up, Mazilli?
- Ho-ho.
Yeah, you better not tell me.
Save my ass from a homicide charge.
Don't tell us before, man.
We like to figure these things out.
Takes all the fun out
of the investigation.
On the real side, who served me up?
What do I look like?
One of your hos?
Yo, genius. Who do you think?
He's in a jam. It must've been
the chocolate Moos.
Get the ball.
Yeah, get it. Good.
Got it? Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Good, good, good!
- Yo, Sharon!
Hi, Uncle Ronnie.
- Yo, what's up, Mark? Chillin'?
- Yeah.
All right.
So, how Victor doing? What's going on
with that bail situation?
- Down to $5,000.
- Word.
Good. Good. It's about fuckin' time.
Check this out.
Strike, somebody's gonna see you.
Put that away. Hurry up.
That's $5,000 right there,
all right?
Give that to Mommy. Tell her
to get her son up out of jail.
Don't tell her I gave it
to you, all right?
You goin' somewhere?
I might, but I don't know.
Ronald, you need
to talk to your mother.
- You listenin'?
- Yeah, I hear you.
Thanks.
- All right.
- Later.
OK, let's go. The Dunham brothers
are up, and he catches it. Yes!
- Yo, Scientific?
- What's up, B? What's up?
What you guys
just sitting around for?
What the fuck you yellin' at?
That nigger Rodney got locked up.
- For what?
- You don't know why?
- No, I don't.
- Strike!
You know.
- Yo, Strike! Yo, Strike!
- Y'all hold on.
Yo, Shorty. Get out of here, man!
I gotta talk to you.
I said I gotta talk to you!
- Get out of here!
- Hey, Ronnie.
- Stop iggin' me!
- Ah, fuck!
Put it here, pal.
Let me talk to you for a minute.
So you wanna fuck with me?
Let me show you
what fuckin's all about.
What the fuck
you talkin' about, man?
Your man is in the joint.
I just came by to thank you.
Yo! Yo, fuck you, Rocco.
You can't pin this shit on me!
Oh, no? All I know is that
Rodney makes bail tomorrow.
He'll be back out on the street.
What do you think your homies
will tell him?
If I was you, I'd fly down to the
DA's office, get my ass protected.
I don't even be fuckin' around
no more. I don't be hustlin'.
Ronald, do yourself a favour.
Tell me what really happened.
How your boss Rodney
pressured you into doing Darryl.
I tell you, that nigger
set Rodney up, man. I know it.
Nobody wants you on this. You had
no choice. Rodney had you scared.
Kill or be killed, right?
You don't even know
what the fuck you talkin' about.
You just got me killed
on some dumb shit.
Black man say he didn't do somethin',
you don't believe him.
Say he did do something,
you still don't believe him.
Have a good life.
Oh, fuck!
Yo, y'all. I know you niggers
know I wouldn't diss Rodney.
Homo-cide is buggin'. Word up.
Word to Allah, man. You a
motherfuckin' punk ass lyin' bitch!
Fuck you! I'll fuck you up!
You a fuckin' snitch!
That nigger snitched on Rodney!
And you punch like a bitch!
Your mama's in her bed.
Well, I ain't gonna wake her.
You don't get it, do you?
- Yo.
- 'Errol. '
Yo.
- I'm in the lockup.
- Lockup? For what?
I don't know.
I'm still trying
to figure it out myself.
'But I know who put me here.
'That little... punk ass Strike. '
'Strike?'
'You know what you gotta do, right?'
- 'It's done. '
- 'I'll see you tomorrow. '
Yo.
- You still around here, nigger?
- What you think?
All right. I guess
Errol ain't find your ass yet.
- Errol?. What he want?
- Yo, Strike!
- What he want, stupid?
- How the fuck I'm 'posed to know?
Maybe he wanna play
with your fuckin' train set
- Man, fuck you.
- Fuck you, nigger! I mean, snitch.
Shit.
Yo, Shorty, how many...
How many times I gotta tell you, man?
Stop sweatin' me. You a kid.
This is grown-up stuff.
You gonna get hurt out here.
Now, take your little bag
of candy, take your little bike
and go find some friends, all right?
Damn! Fuckin' kids, man.
Oh, shit!
Boogie-Down was performing
Down with the sounds called VDP
It ain't no joke
Back in the days
I knew rap would never die
I used to listen
to Awesome-2 on WHBI
I used to hear all kind
of rap groups
Before samplin' loops
rappers wore bell-bottom Lee suits
Me and Kenny couldn't afford that
So we would go to the park
while they was jammin' to hear rap
I used to listen
till the cops broke it up
Always thought to myself
"Damn, why they fucked it up"
But nevertheless
I was in love with the microphone
And it stayed that way
until I left home
On the streets of New York
now I'm free
But with freedom
comes big responsibility
I used to walk around
driven by the force
I remember how large Super
Rhymes was when he fell off
I used to wonder about crews
that used to rock
They were large but none of them
could manage to stay on top
Do you ever think about
when you outta here
Record deal and video outta here
Mercedes-Benz
and Range Rover outta here
No doubt BDP is old school
but we ain't goin' out...
What you want, little...
Yo, Ty! Ty!
You little motherfucker!
Some years went by, I signed myself
into a group home...
What the fuck is wrong with you, huh?
You buggin'?
Shit.
I don't know what happened.
I've known this kid his whole life,
his mother, too. Good, decent people.
Now, whatever happened out there,
it was a big mistake.
I mean... I mean, Tyrone's never been
in trouble before. He's like...
He's like, uh, 85th percentile
on the national education test.
I mean, uh...
Now this thing could ruin his life.
Please.
Just help him with his moms
and his statement.
You know what I'm askin'.
Does my son have to go to jail?.
Would you permit me to talk to him?
If you talk to him, does he still
have to go to jail?.
Tyrone, you know
what you did, don't you?
- Yeah.
- You know it was wrong?
- He knows.
- OK. We got that outta the way.
You did wrong.
But you were scared, right?
You couldn't help it.
My son was terrified.
Tyrone, you're a good kid, but it's
tough growin' up in the projects.
Drugs, crime, peer pressure. You know
what that means, peer pressure?
- Yes.
- I hear you're real intelligent.
Don't your friends make fun of you
when you get straight As,
speak correct English,
attend school,
go to classes, don't hang out?
Don't they call you white boy?
Don't they call you soft because
you ain't hanging with them hard?
I know they do, but all you
want to do is the right thing.
But they keep threatening you,
threatening your mother.
Tyrone.
So you get a gat.
So you, too, can be hard-core.
Protect yourself and your mother.
- Do you know the man you shot?
- Yeah.
That was Errol Barnes,
a stone killer.
He did time
for killin' a kid your age.
Here you are, riding your bike,
minding your own business.
You have a gun for protection.
All of a sudden,
there's Errol, that kid killer,
standing right in front of you.
He's got this horrible look
in his beady eyes.
You see him reaching...
Tyrone, look at me.
Look at me, Tyrone.
You see him reaching for that.38
stuck in his waist.
You know he's gonna gat you.
Then who's gonna protect your mother?
You never fired that gun before, but
Errol was about to pull that trigger.
You're scared.
All you wanna do is ride your bike.
It's either him or you.
But this killer in front of you.
There's no time to think,
his finger is on the trigger.
Boom, boom. The gun just appeared
in your hand.
That's what happened.
That's what exactly happened.
And when I ask you what happened
with the tape recorder on,
that's exactly what
you're going to tell me, right?
Because you always tell the truth.
Now, one last thing.
We need to know - again, tell
the truth - where'd you get the gat?
- I found it.
- Where'd you find it?
- In the bushes.
- Where in the bushes?
I'm not turning it on yet.
Where in the bushes?
- What bushes?
- The bushes near my building.
Tyrone, you gotta help me out here.
And your mama.
The truth.
OK. I borrowed it by accident.
From who? Remember,
you always tell the truth.
I borrowed it by accident
from Strike.
Strike?
Motherfucker!
All right, son. All right.
You did the right thing.
I was tryin' to give it back to him,
but he doesn't speak to me any more.
I keep trying...
but he keeps iggin' me.
All right, son.
I'm gonna put the recorder on now.
You state your name,
and you tell the story, relax,
just the way you told it to me.
- Your name?
- Tyrone Jeeter.
Oh, shit.
Fuck that nigger up, man!
What the fuck you doing?
You ruined that boy's life,
you fuckin' parasite!
I had nothin'
to do with that shit!
I'm tired of excuses!
Tired of excuses.
- 'Mommy!'
- You know nothin'!
"It's not my fault. "
I'm not hearin' that shit!
It's motherfuckers like you
mugged Rosa Parks.
- Who the fuck is Rosa Parks?
- Who the fuck is Rosa Parks?!
- It's hard on the brothers.
- You stupid, ignorant motherfucker!
Brothers?! Brothers! Is this the way
you take care of your brothers, huh?
Real brothers take responsibility.
I'm gonna make damn sure you do.
I won't be fuckin' around.
I'm done with that.
Done with it? Done with that?
You bet you are.
You are done from these streets.
You're gone from this project,
and you're gone from New York.
You hear me?
Oh, shit!
Come on, you son of a bitch!
Yo, why don't you stomp
that nigger too, man?
- Come on, man.
- Get back! Get back!
- Gonna shoot everybody?
- Get the fuck back!
Come on! You want somethin'?
You got it, man! You got it! What?
Get up.
Get up, get up, get up!
If I ever see you again,
I'm going to kill you!
I'm gonna shoot you in your dome,
put a gun in your hand
and say you tried to raise up on me
for this beat down you just got.
Do you understand? Do you understand?
Shit!
He wants to fly
but his wings won't let him go
He wants to travel
but don't wanna go so low
Oh-oh, Daddy, when I grow up
I want to be a silent hero...
Ah, look who's here!
I was just comin' to get you.
Rodney or Andre?
Rodney! Take a number, you're next!
What'd you think
you was gonna do? Become president?
Yo, man! Why did Tyrone
do that stupid shit for?
The boy did it for you.
He was protecting you.
Rodney ain't no fool.
He sent Errol after you,
and this poor fuckin' kid
stepped into the breach.
David and Goliath.
Now he's a 12-year-old murderer.
Way to go, Strike.
Yo, don't lay that on me, all right?
Don't lay that on you?
- I had nothin' to do with Tyrone.
- You had nothin' to do with it?
Can you look yourself
in the fuckin' mirror and tell me
you had nothin' to do with Tyrone?
Why the fuck you have to come
shake my hand anyway?
Didn't I tell you not to play me?
Did I not tell you that?
I don't give a fuck what you said!
You can't put this weight on me!
Nah, why should you carry
the fuckin' weight?
You must be a wonderful
fuckin' guy,
everybody tryin' to protect you
- Tyrone, Victor.
You know what? They all went down
protecting you from the same guy,
and he's still out there.
I'm the only one
that can protect you now.
That's right. Me. Me.
So you tell me how Rodney
pressured you into cappin'...
Oh, man!
.. Darryl Adams,
and we'll drop him down a hole.
Don't tell me Rodney
pulled the trigger if he didn't.
All's you gotta do now
is tell me the truth.
Did you shoot Darryl Adams?
No, man, no. Damn.
- Who did?
- Scientific.
- Who the fuck is Scientific?
- He's with my crew.
- Did you see him kill Darryl Adams?
- No.
- Did he tell you he killed Darryl?.
- No!
- Did he tell anybody?
- I don't know! Why you sweatin' me?
It was Errol Barnes!
Get up!
Get up, you fuckin' lyin' cocksucker!
You crazy?
I'm gonna hand-feed you
to fuckin' Rodney myself!
I swear to God!
It was a nigger named My Man.
My brother said My Man would do it.
- My Man?
- I didn't have the heart to do him!
- I didn't have the heart to do 'im!
- Victor said My Man would do it.
We was in Kool Breeze and shit,
a- a-and Victor,
he just told me,
he was like, he said, "My Man".
Maybe Victor was so drunk
he did tell My Man to do it.
Bullshit, bullshit!
Let's go see Rodney.
Rocco.
If you don't get your hand
off my son, you better...
- Victor called me from the bar.
- You ain't gotta tell him nothin'.
Victor called me from the bar.
Mom? I think I'm gonna
do somethin' bad.
Ma, I can feel it.
Look, I'm just tired, that's all.
I'm just sick and tired.
And somebody's gotta pay.
Somebody's gotta pay.
He came back into the house
an hour later.
Victor! Baby, what's wrong?
Oh, Mama, I shot somebody!
I shot somebody.
'He was throwin' up all night.
'I didn't even know that other boy
was lyin' dead in the parking lot. '
The next morning... he says
that he can't get out of bed -
his legs are cramped, he can't walk.
Mama, let me tell you,
it was just like a dream,
like somebody else
was pullin' the trigger, you know?
And that's what happened.
Mommy, I swear,
I'm gonna help Victor.
What is going to happen to my son?
Did you get the money from Sharon?
- Huh? For the bail?.
- She wouldn't take it.
My son Victor...
said it was self-defence.
Believe him!
Shit!
Shit.
"Bitch... you is dead. "
Motherfucker
stole my bags, too.
Yo, Strike. Your boy Rodney
took a piss in your car.
So, where do you want
to live, Ronnie?
I don't know, man.
You tell me.
We's goin' to the Port Authority
Bus Terminal.
Please, Rocco, man,
take me to Penn Station.
Same difference.
'Self-defence. Self-defence.
'Victor is pleading self-defence. '
So, what's up with Tyrone?
Does he get bail?.
No bail on juveniles.
His mother has him until the trial.
So, how much time is he gonna get?
Maybe a half-year
in a youth house, if he's lucky.
Yo, Rocco, before I get out, man,
just answer me this one question.
Why was you so gung-ho
about all this shit, man?
Most cops...
Brothers killin' other brothers
ain't no big thing. Blasé, blasé.
What made you care about me, my
brother Victor, Darryl Adams, Tyrone?
Huh? What made you give a shit?
If I ever see you again,
I'll book you on charges
of criminal solicitation
and conspiracy to commit murder.
I'll let Andre beat you down again,
then pick up Rodney
on the same charges,
and I'll make sure you two
share the same cell.
The same fuckin' bed.
Do you understand me clearly?
Yeah, I understand you clearly.
I just wanted to say thanks, for
gettin' me outta town, that's all.
It ain't mine, man.
I stopped doin' that.
Get the fuck outta the car.
Final Call newspaper! Get
your latest edition of Final Call!
Sir, how are you doing today? Get
your latest edition of Final Call.
Justice In Black And White, sir.
No, thank you.
Thank you very much, sir.
Have a pleasant and good day.
Final Call newspaper! Get your latest
edition of your Final Call newspaper!
How about you, sir?
"I'll kill you. "
I guess somebody read his shirt
the wrong way, huh?
Whoo!
Right through his fuckin' mouth.
Another stain on the sidewalk.
- Hal! Lunch.
- Another dead motherfucker.
DMF. All right.
Well, Hal, let's go to work.
- Take it away, Lieutenant.
- OK. Catch you next time.
Hey, guys.
They should blow these projects
to Timbuktu.
Why bother? They kill themselves
anyway, like a self-cleaning oven.
No fuss, no mess.
That's how the Nubians do it.
Cycle of shit.
- Take it easy, guys.
- Take it easy.
What the fuck happened?
One snap, that kid
Scientific got shot up.
What's a Scientific?
That could be you next.
Mr Scientific.
Nothin' you ain't seen
before, eh, fellas?
Did you see anything over there?
Back in the early 1900s,
when trains ran on batteries,
when people had no electricity
in their houses...
After World War II, right?
Tyrone.
- You know I love you, don't you?
- Yeah.
- After World War II, right?
When people started getting
electricity in their houses,
they made these - the new ones.
Wanna hear a whistle?
Here is my hand
for you to hold
Here's a part of me
they have not sold
I've wandered far, I've had my fill
I need you now
do you love me still
Only you have seen
The hidden part of me
Call me foolhardy if you will
I loved you when
do you love me still
So many smiles
and lies surround me
Empty expectations, faceless fears
Sometimes this life
is a bitter pill
I love you now
do you love me still
You have been mine
since time untold
Our love is immortal don't you know
Others will come and they will go
But I loved you young
and I'll love you old
Only you have seen
The other side of me
Call me naive, I think you will
But I loved you then
do you love me still
Here are the eyes that only see you
Here's a mouth
that only calls your name
Here is a song they cannot kill
I love you now
do you love me still