Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Rocketers team presents
love love love....
are you ready
can you come little closer
sit comfortably
when to guys meet each for first time...
how did you experience it???
do you want to tell...
You only say about it...
if you say it would be nice....
you onlyy say...
it was our college first day...
i first saw her in the cafeteria...
she was wearing red salwar....
she was very cute and chubby...
I was not chubby at that time...
hmm no you were kind of chubby but not very much
and it was about those times not now
No ... I was not even those times as well
you being chubby is the reason for you to be beautiful....
ohhh...
So I'm not beautiful now????
eh.. its not like that... do you want to say
you only tell ...
you say.... no you say
five months later....
loving or hating is expressed more by girls than boys
boys can never express so much as girls
Did you ever see a girls anger in your life
I'm now experiencing it...
She is Parvathi....
My girl friend
till this incident happened...
for that second in my mind there were
so many things going through....
There were so many happy moments spent by us in
this cafeteria before....
from today how my life is about to be spoiled
is been running in my mind...also at same time
why did my college cafeteria serve soft drinks in a glass tumbler....
rather than give in a paper cups...
shhhh...
Like always ....It was a small fight...
will be solved in few days..
she will first approach me...
shhhhh.....
after 2 days.....
Why??? without her cant I survive??
Let her go....
I no longer require her...
After 3 days...
I can no longer wait...
I want to see right now...
I phoned to her five minutes back....
should I try to call her now???
she is not coming back to your life dude
Just move on....
How is possible brother....
It was my first real love...
Listen now man!!! to forget her immediately
is hard I can understand....
at least from now try to forget her instead of thinking about her...
don't waste time thinking about her
divert your mind on to some other interesting things
you will forget her...
sorry brother...
I have always been discussing with about this topic...
no no... I fine man...
you know right... I share only with you
I can understand it...
For all these days our love was very smooth...
Usually fights between us not last more than a day....
By hook for crook we resolve the problem between us...
was it my mistake to come to this decision earlier
now even I call her she is not lifting the phone...
Now I can she change in a week pretending
nothing happened ... I cant understand..
she is very good girl...
sorry brother
I always been talking with you about her...
I can only share with you guys... right???
I'm not used to these things...
from childhood I have got things i want very easily...
My mother and father...
I'm everything for my parents...
Dad is a Lawyer...
deals with domestic ; divorce cases
he is a perfect husband and a father
vasantha...... my mother is house wife
I'm her loving child...
full house is in her control....
including my dad...
from my childhood what ever I did...
my both parents have participated in it
bowled... you throw ball very fast towards boy..
can you throw ball to his bat nicely...
why you wearing shoe to boy without polishing it...
wait... let me polish afterwards
There is nothing like a big challenge in my life
Thats the reason.. at least for finding my dream girl
i wish to have a challenge
My dream Girl!!!!   Parvathi!!!
ahhhh..... I wished to have a small challenge but never
expect to finish it so badly...
It is very hard to forget her
to forget her.. friends told so many advice's...
Drink alcohol.... find new girl man.....
talk to me... if you talk it helps..
alcohol is best one man....
with this you can write a story....
drink alcohol...drink alcohol...
Travel to some place with your close friends ...
create a nice atmosphere then drink alcohol....
many advice me to drink alocohol....
but I'm not ready for it...
because my heart is already damaged
and I dont want to damage my kidney and liver by drinking
these are atleast fine advices.... some people approach to me with sad face to ask how everything with you now....
I got to know about it  don't worry....
I knew it before your love would not work well
these girls are always like this...
did you break just now... I thought you break with her long back...
Hi ... My name is Raju ... heard you guys break up... feel sorry about it...
can you please give me her phone number..
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player