(beeping)
(coin dropping)
My name's ralph,
and I'm a bad guy.
Let's see. I'm nine feet tal.
I weigh 643 pounds.
Got a little bit
of a temper on me.
Hey, you moved my stump!
(growling)
Ralph:  My passion bubbles
very near the surface,
I guess, not gonna lie.
Anyhoo, what else? Uh..
I'm a wrecker. I wreck thing.
Professionally.
I'm going to wreck it!
I'm very good at what I do.
Probably the best I know.
(yelling)
The thing is, fixing
is the name of the game.
Literally,
fix-it felix, jr.
Nicelanders:
Fix it, felix!
I can fix it!
Ralph:  So, yeah, naturally,
The guy with the name
fix-it felix is the good g.
He's nice enough
as good guys go.
Definitely fixes
stuff really well.
But, uh, if you've
got a magic hammer
From your father,
How hard can it be?
If he was a regular contractr
carpenter guy,
I guarantee you
would not be able
To fix the damage
that I do as quickly.
And when felix does
a good job, he gets a me.
But are there medals for
wrecking stuff really well?
To that I say, "ha!"
(growls loudly)
And, no, there aren't.
(indistinct conversations)
Thirty years I've
been doing this
And I've seen a lot of or
games come and go.
Kind of sad. I think about al
those guys from asteroids.
Boom! Gone.Centipede?
Who knows where
that guy is, you know?
Look, a steady arcade gig
is nothing to sneeze at.
I'm very lucky.
It's just,
I got to say,
It becomes kind of hard
to love your job
When no one seems to
like you for doing it.
All clear!
The arcade is closed!
Shoryuken!
Whoo! What a day!
You want to head
to tappers, ken?
If you're buying, buddy.
Felix:
Quitting time!
Ralph:  I don't know.
Maybe I wouldn't be
feeling this way
If things were
different after work.
But it is what it is.
Good job, everyone!
Ralph:
Felix and the nicelanders
Go hang out in their homs
Which he's just fixed,
and everyone, you know.
They go to their homes,
I go to mine
Which happens
to be a dump.
And when I say "a dump,"
I don't mean like
a shabby place.
I mean an actual dump,
Where the garbage goes
And a bunch of bricks
and smashed building parts.
That's what I call home.
I guess I can't
bellyache too much.
I got my bricks,
I got my stump.
It looks uncomfortable.
It's actually fine. I'm go.
But if I'm really
honest with myself...
I see felix up there
getting patted on the back,
People are giving him pie
and thanking him
And so happy
to see him all the time.
Sometimes I think...
Man, it sure must be nice
being the good guy.
(all clapping)
Blinky: Nice share, ralph.
As fellow bad guys,
We've all felt
what you're feeling
And we've come
to terms with it.
Really?
Zangief: Right here.
I am zangief.
I am bad guy.
All: Hi, zangief!
Hi, zangief.
I relate to you, ralph.
When I hit bottom,
I was crushing man's skull
Like sparrow egg
between my thighs.
(all chuckling)
And I think, "why do you have
to be so bad, zangief?
"why can't you be
more like good guy?"
Then I have
moment of clarity.
If zangief is good guy,
Who'll crush man's skull
Like sparrow's egg
between thighs?
And I say, "zangief,
you are bad guy,
"but this does not mean
you are 'bad' guy."
(grunts in approval)
Right. I'm sorry.
You lost me there.
Zombie! Bad guy!
All: Hi, zombie.
Hi, zombie.
Zangief saying
labels not make you happy.
Good! Bad!
(growls)
You must love you.
Yeah! Inside here!
Yes.
Okay. All right, I get you.
Watch out. It's dripping.
Question, ralph.
We've been asking you
to bad-anon for years now
And tonight you
finally show up.
Why is that?
I don't know.
I just felt like coming.
I suppose it has
something to do with
the fact that, uh...
Well, today is the 30th
anniversary of my game.
Well, happy anniversary,
ralph.
Thanks, satan.
Uh, it's sateen,
actually.
Got it.
But here's the thing.
(sighs)
I don't want to be
the bad guy anymore.
(all exclaiming)
You can't mess with
the program, ralph.
You're not going turbo,
are you?
Turbo? No, I'm not going
turbo! Come on, guys!
Is it turbo to want a friend?
Or a medal?
Or a piece of pie
every once in a while?
Is it turbo to want
more out of life?
Yes!
Ralph, ralph, we get it.
But we can't change
who we are.
And the sooner
you accept that,
The better off your game
and your life will be.
Hey. One game
at a time, ralph.
Let's close out with
the bad guy affirmation.
All: I'm bad,
and that's good.
I will never be good,
and that's not bad.
There's no one
I'd rather be than me.
Blinky: Okay, gang,
see you next week.
M. Bison: Listen, I can't do
snacks next week.
Hang in there, ralph.
Blinky: Hey, zombie,
don't forget your hatchets.
There you go.
(female announcer
announcing on pa)
(alarm blaring)
(grunts in frustration)
Step aside, sir.
Random security check.
Random my behind!
You always stop me.
I'm just a surge protector
doing my job, sir.
Name?
Lara croft.
Wreck-it ralph!
And where are you
coming from?
Uh...  Pac-man .
Did you bring
any fruit with you?
No! No. No fruit.
Okay, then.
Where are you heading?
Fix-it felix jr.
Anything to declare?
I hate you.
I get that a lot.
Proceed.
Bad guy coming!
(screaming)
Sonic the hedgehog:
If you leave your game,
Stay safe, stay alert,
And whatever you,
don't die.
Because if you die
outside your own game
You don't regenerate.
Ever. Game ove.
Here you go, buddy.
It's fresh.
Straight from pac-man's.
Hang in there, guys.
(alarm blaring)
name?
(grunts in frustration)
(dance music playing)
♪ celebrate good times
come on! ♪
(bell ringing)
(fireworks exploding)
(fireworks whistling)
"happy 30th anniversary"?
They're having
a party without me.
Pac-man?
They invited pac-man?
That cherry-chasing
dot-muncher
Isn't even part of this game!
Great party, felix.
Why, thank you, friend.
Felix. You're needed on
the dance floor!
(whooping)
All: Whoo!
Nicelanders: Fix-it felix!
Whoo-whoo! Fix-it felix!
(doorbell rings)
Oh! I'll bet that's mario.
Fashionably late,
per the norm.
I'll get it, felix.
(humming)
Ahh!
(music stops)
It's ralph!
(screaming)
he'll wreck the party!
Hide the stemware!
Get rid of him, felix.
Oh, right.
I'll go talk to him.
Carry on, everyone.
(music starts again)
Ralph, can I help you?
Hey, felix.
Just wanted to check on you.
I saw a big explosion
Or something go
over the building there.
Oh, those were
just fireworks.
Fireworks. Okay. Phewf.
Somebody's birthday, or...
Well, it's more
of an anniversary.
The 30th anniversary
of our game, actually.
What? Is that today?
I know!
Oh, I'm such
a dummy with dates.
Anyway, uh,
congratulations.
Thank you, ralph.
And to you, too.
(chuckles)
(chuckles awkwardly)
Uh...
Hi. Just a heads-up, felix.
They're bringing out the cake
in a few shakes.
Hey, glen.
Ralph.
Cake? Heard about this
cake stuff. (chuckles)
Never had it.
No one ever seems
to throw it out
So it never ends up
in the dump.
I never actually
tasted it. Uh...
I've always
wanted to try cake.
I don't suppose
you'd like to
Come in and have
a slice, would you?
Hey-o, everybody!
Oh!
Ah!
(all gasp)
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Fit as a fiddle.
(all exhaling)
now, you all know ralph.
Evening.
(all gasp)
Evening, nell, lucy,
don, dana...
Deanna.
Ralph: Big gene!
Why is he here?
He's just here
for a slice of cake.
And I'm a big
part of the game,
Technically speaking.
Why are you here, gene?
Oh, look! The cake!
(gasps)
Well, I'll be dipped. You've
really outdone yourself, mary.
Norwood: Oh, and look!
There's all of us at the top.
Each apartment
is everyone's
favorite flavor.
Norwood's is red velvet.
Norwood: Guilty!
And lemon for lucy,
rum cake for gene,
And for felix...
Hey, mary.
Um...
What's the flavor of that mud
that I'm stuck in there?
Hmm? Oh. Chocolate.
I've never been
real fond of chocolate.
Well, I did not
know that.
One other little thing.
I hate to be picky, but
this angry little guy here...
My cake!
...Might be a lot happier
If you put him up here
with everyone else.
See that?
Look at that smile.
No, no. You see, ralph,
There's no room
for you up here.
(chuckles) what about this?
We can make room.
Here. We could
take turns. Easy.
(all gasp)
How about we just
eat the cake?
Hang on. Felix needs
to be on the roof
Because he's about
to get his medal!
Then how about we just
take that medal
And give it to ralph for once?
Would that be the
end of the world, gene?
Now you're just
being ridiculous.
Only good guys win medals,
And you, sir,
are no good guy.
I could be a good guy
if I wanted to,
And I could win a medal!
Uh-huh. And when you do,
come and talk to us.
Then would you finally
let me be on top of
the cake with you guys?
If you won a medal,
We'd let you live
up here in the penthouse!
But it will
never happen
Because you're just the bad
guy who wrecks the building.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are!
No, I'm not!
(all exclaim)
(gasps)
Yes, you are.
All right, gene.
You know what?
I'm going to win a medal.
Oh, I am going to
win a medal!
The shiniest medal
this place has ever seen!
A medal that
will be so good
That it will make felix's
medals wet their pants!
And good night!
Thank you for the party.
Is he serious?
Oh, please!
Where's a bad guy
going to win a medal?
Of course
he's not serious.
I've never been more serious
about anything in my life.
That's why I came
straight here, tapper.
You've never given me
a bum steer.
Now, come on. Where can a guy
like me go and win a medal?
I don't think such
a game exists, ralph.
Oh, come on. You know people.
There's got to be...
Male customer:
Tapper, I need a root beer.
Coming!
Hold that thought.
(video game music playing)
Okay. As you were saying.
I was saying, I can't spend
another 30 years
Living alone in the garbage.
I'm not going back
without a medal.
Well, I don't know
what to tell you.
Maybe somebody
left a medal here.
You're welcome to dig
through the lost and found.
Okay, let's see
what we got here.
Oh! Shoo! Shoo!
Go on, get out of here.
Mushroom? No.
What is this? No.
Oh, come on, zangief!
Gross.
(sighs) oh.
What am I doing?
(grunts)
Hey, excuse you!
We are humanity's last hope.
Our mission?
Destroy all cy-bugs.
We are humanity's
last hope.
Uh... You okay there,
space cadet?
We've only been
plugged in a week
And every day it's, "climb
the building, then fight bugs.
"climb the building,
fight more bugs!"
Yeah, yeah. Right. Look.
Easy on the overalls,
spaceman.
It's tough all over,
all right?
And all for what?
A lousy medal?
Medal? You win a medal?
Yeah, medal of heroes.
Ooh. Is it shiny?
Pretty shiny.
Ooh! And it says
"hero" on it?
Uh-huh.
Oh, yeah.
And you say you win it
by climbing a building?
And fighting bugs!
Right, bugs.
Is there any chance I could go
with you to your game
And maybe get
one of those medals?
Negatory.
Does that mean maybe?
No! Look,
only the bravest
And the best
serve in our corps.
Bug!
(screams)
(groans)
Huh.
(shrieks)
We are humanity's last hope.
(grunts)
The arcade will open
in five minutes.
Please report
to your games.
(grunting)
I can't feel my legs.
What is all this stuff?
(beeping rapidly)
Smells like ralph in here.
Okay. All right.
What was it called again?
Hero's something.
Duty. Hero's duty.
Oh, there it is.
Oh!
Sorry, qbert.
It's me, ralph.
Shh!
The wall.
(muttering)
(kids talking)
Morning, kids.
Come on in.
Good to see you.
You, too, little fella.
Announcer over pa:
Quarter alert! Quarter ale!
This is not a drill.
Ooh! Sweet golden medal!
Narrator:
On a planet with no name,
A top-secret experiment
has gone horribly wrong.
You are humanity's
last hope.
Rooting-tooting, ready for
shooting! (chuckles)
Sergeant calhoun:
All right.
Now listen up, because I'm
only going to say this once.
Fear is
a four-letter word, ladies.
If you want to go pee-pee
in your big-boy slacks,
Keep it to yourself.
It's make your
mamas proud time!
I love my mama!
Officer: Heads up!
First-person shooter,
Coming through!
Ooh, robot!
Boop, boop, boop.
(chuckles)
Announcer over pa:
Game play in three,
Two, one.
We are humanity's
last hope.
Our mission?
Destroy all cy-bugs.
You ready, rookie?
Let's find out.
Sweet mother hubbard!
(screams)
Ralph: No, no, no!
Wait a second! Aah!
Cy-bug, twelve o'clock.
Take it, newbie.
Ralph: No, no! Wait, wait!
Watch it, rookie! These
monsters become what they eat.
(grunting)
My gun!
Give me that back.
Shoot the eggs
before they hatch!
Oh, no!
Something's coming
out of their bottom!
Oh, gross!
Markowski!
Get back in formation!
All right, ladies,
The kitten whispers
and tickle fights stop now.
The entrance to the lab
is straight ahead.
I'll meet you guys inside!
No!
Oh! Sanctuary! Sanctuary!
(ralph gasps)
(screaming)
I thought this was going
to be like  centipede!
When did video games
become so violent and scary?
Please, get e
out of here!
Take her!
(girl screams)
Announcer:  Game over.
What a rip-off!
Ah! Get off me!
It's game over. Stop it!
Soldiers: Beacon up!
Officers: Cease fire!
Cease fire!
Announcer:  Attention!
Return to start positions.
Return to start position.
(powering down)
Here, let me help you.
Sorry about that.
Yeah, you must be upset.
Calhoun: Markowski.
Who?
Whoa! Oh, yeah, me.
I'm markowski.
Ah!
What's the first rule
of  hero's duty?
No cuts, no butts,
no coconuts?
Never interfere with
the first-person shooter.
Our job is to get the gamers
to the top of that building
So they can get a medal,
and that's it!
So stick to the program,
soldier!
Right. Right. Aye, aye.
Announcer:
Quarter alert! Quarter ale!
All right, pussy willows.
Back to start positions!
Oh!
Yeah, right. No way I'm going
through that again.
So that's where they
keep the medal, huh?
Hmm. "new racers daily."
Sweet! I got next game.
Go away, kid!
We're going to play
all nine of today's racers!
Yeah!
Sorry.
(video game music playing)
Hmm. Where's
the wrecking guy?
Where's ralph? He should be
wrecking the building.
Shh! Stick with
the program.
Nicelanders:
Fix it, felix!
I can fix it!
(nervous chuckle)
(clears throat)
(whispers) ralph!
Quarter alert! Game on!
(whispering)
do something, felix!
Just act natural.
I'll fix it.
(gasps)
Felix: Ralph! Ralph!
What the...
Ralph? Ralph!
Oh, my land!
Where is he?
Mr. Litwak!
What's the trouble,
sweetheart?
The game's busted.
I can fix it!
Litwak: Oh, boy.
Looks like the game's
gone cuckoo, like my nana.
Sorry, sweetie.
Here's your quarter back.
But what about the game?
I'll have someone
look at it tomorrow...
But if he can't fix it,
It might be time
To put old ralph
and felix out to pasture.
Like my nana.
(all gasp)
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're out of order.
Sweet mercy!
Without ralph, we're doomed!
They're going to
pull our plug!
(screaming)
Okay, everybody, calm down.
Ralph probably fell asleep
In the washroom
of tapper's again.
(bell ringing)
see? There he is now.
Why, it's qbert. What brings
you here, neighbor?
(muttering)
What's he saying, felix?
Stand by. My qbert-ese
is a little rusty.
(clears throat)
(muttering)
(gasps)
Ralph's gone turbo!
(all gasp)
(grunting)
Ooh!
Shiny.
Announcer:  Attention!
The arcade is now closed.
Did you get
a load of markowski?
(laughs)
shut your chew holes.
Cy-bug.
(bouncing sound)
Taste it!
(grunts)
Slick tiddlywinking,
pint-size.
I'm fix-it felix, jr.,
ma'am.
From the game
fix-it felix, jr.
(gasps)
Jiminey jaminey!
Look at that high definition.
Your face!
It's amazing!
Flattery don't charge
these batteries, civilian.
Now, state your business.
Oh, I'm looking for my
colleague, wreck-it ralph?
Never heard of him.
Well, qbert saw him
come in here.
Impossible.
Nothing gets past me.
(metal clanking)
That came
from the tower.
(grunting)
Nice eggs. Nice eggs!
Okay. That was easy.
Congratulations, soldier.
It is my honor to
bestow upon you
The medal of heroes.
Wow!
No way!
Ten-hut!
(laughs) wow!
History will long revere
your courage and sacrifice.
Well, thank you!
You have etched
in the rock of virtue
A legacy beyond compare.
Thanks, guys. At ease!
You are the universes
greatest hero.
(crunches)
oops!
(exclaiming)
The living embodiment of
all this corps represent.
Oh. (screams)
Bravery. Integrity.
Grace under pressure.
And above all, dignity.
(grunting)
Female announcer:
Escape pod activated.
(muffled grunting)
Get off my face!
Kohut: Incoming!
(ralph screaming)
Ralph!
Cy-bug!
(grunting)
A-ha!
Oh, no!
(beeping)
(screaming)
Huh?
(beeping rapidly)
(screaming)
Sayonara , sucker!
(music playing)
Huh?
"sugar rush"?
(theme song playing)
Oh, no!
This is that candy
go-cart game
Over by the whac-a-mole.
I got to
get out of here.
Oh, no! My medal!
(stuttering)
(gasps)
no, no, no, no, my medal!
Oh!
(groaning)
No, no, my medal!
(panting)
(exclaiming)
Hi, mister.
(screams)
Hello.
Man, you scared me, kid.
Ah, I nearly soiled myself.
What's your name?
Uh... Ralph.
Wreck-it ralph.
You're not from here,
are you?
No, well, yeah. I mean,
not from right in this area.
I'm just doing
some work here.
What kind of work?
Some routine
candy tree trimming.
You probably
want to stand back.
In fact, this whole area
Is technically closed
while we're trimming.
Who's "we"?
Candy tree department.
Oh! Where is
everybody else?
Ah, it's just me today.
So you just meant
like the royal "we"?
Yep. That's right.
Hey, are you a hobo?
No. I'm not a hobo,
but I am busy.
Okay? So you go home.
What's that?
Didn't hear you.
Your breath is so bad
it made my ears numb.
Listen,
I tried to be nice.
(mimicking)
You're mimicking me.
You're mimicking me!
Okay.
That is rude, and this
conversation is over.
And this conversation
is over.
Uh, I wouldn't grab that
branch if I were you.
I'm from the candy tree
department, so I know what...
It's a double stripe.
(grunts)
Double stripes break.
Guh-doy!
Why are your hands
so freakishly big?
Uh, I don't know. Why are you
so freakishly annoying?
Why are you
so freakishly...
Sweet mother of monkey milk!
A gold coin!
Don't even think about it.
That is mine.
Race you for it!
Hey!
I don't have to race for it
because it's mine!
Double stripe!
Come back here!
The winner!
Give it back! Give it!
Whoa!
Double stripe.
(screaming)
Thank you!
Wait! Let me talk to you
for one second.
Okay. Here's the thing.
I'm not from
the candy tree department.
Lying to a child.
Shame on you, ralph.
But I wasn't lying about
the medal. That is my medal!
That's why I was climbing
the tree. It's mine!
It's precious to me.
That thing is my ticket
to a better life.
Yeah, well,
now it's my ticket.
What the...
See you, chump!
Come back!
I'll find you!
I will find you!
Double stripe!
(screams)
Nowhere to hide!
Yeah, he banged around in here
like some kind of hot shot,
Then he went barreling down
into that sweet little game
Like a crazy person.
"sugar rush."
Cy-bugs would
chew up that game
Faster than a chicken hawk in
a coop of crippled roosters.
What was that, now?
What are you, thick?
There was a cy-bug
on that shuttle!
Do you even know
what a cy-bug is?
I can't say
that I do, ma'am.
Cy-bugs are like a virus.
They don't know
they're in a game.
All they know is eat,
kill, multiply.
Without a beacon
to stop them,
They'll consume  sugar rush.
But do you think
they'll stop there?
Yes!
Wrong!
Viruses do not stop!
Once those cy-bugs
finish off  sugar rush,
They'll invade every other
game until this arcade
Is nothing but a smoking husk
of forgotten dreams.
Kohut! My cruiser.
Jeepers. Is she
always this intense?
It's not her fault.
She's programmed with the most
tragic back-story ever.
The one day she didn't do
a perimeter check...
Her wedding day.
(shrieks)
(screaming)
Wait, ma'am!
I'm going with you.
Like fun you are,
short stack.
If you die outside your game,
you don't regenerate.
Well, neither do you, ma'am.
And it is my job to fix
what ralph wrecks.
And I cannot ask you
To risk your life
cleaning up his mess.
No flex on this one, ma'am.
I am coming along with you.
(snaps)
(exclaims)
(felix exclaiming)
(music playing)
(crowd cheering)
Sour bill:
Citizens of sugar rush...
Just in time.
...All hail our
rightful ruler, king candy.
Hello, my royal subjects!
Ha-ha! Have some candy!
(all cheering)
Thank you for that stirring
introduction, sour bill.
Mmm-hmm.
And thank you to
today's avatars.
It was a wonderful
day of racing. It was.
But now
the arcade is closed,
So it's time to
wipe the slate clean
And race to decide
our new roster.
The first nine racers
across that finish line
Will represent sugar rush
as tomorrow's avatars!
All: (chanting)
race! Race! Race!
King candy:
Okay, calm down.
Listen! This event is
pay-to-play. We all know thi.
The fee to compete
is one gold coin
From your previous winnings,
If you've ever won,
which I have.
Let me go first!
Announcer:  King candy!
(all chanting)
(laughing)
Announcer:
Taffyta muttonfudge!
Stay sweet!
Adorabeezle winterpop.
Gloyd orangeboar!
(ralph grunting)
Ralph: Little stealer!
Wait till I catch that brat.
Announcer:  Minty zaki.
Snowanna rainbeau.
Rancis fluggerbutter.
Jubileena bing-bing.
Swizzle malarkey.
Candlehead.
(coin tinkling)
Sour bill,
who's that last one?
Announcer:
Vanellope von schweetz!
Yippee! I'm in the race!
Vanellope?
(gasps) the glitch!
(screaming)
King candy:  Now, now!
(laughs)
Everything is all right!
Security!
Come here, kid!
We're not going
to hurt you,
you little freak!
(screaming)
Get back here!
Slow down!
Slow down a little bit.
(ralph grunting)
You! Give me back
my medal right now!
Ah, boy!
Go!
What is that?
Wynnchel:
Come on! Go! Roll!
(grunting)
(growling)
Careful!
What are you doing?
Huh?
(laughing)
Come back here!
I can't move!
Now we got him!
Oh, good, the cops.
She went that way!
Hold still!
Take that!
Ow! What are you doing?
Okay, folks.
(stammers)
Calm down!
Everything's all right.
The monster's been caugh!
We'll repair
all the damage.
Don't worry. We will have r
race before the arcade ope.
And I'm in it. Yes!
There's no way that I am
racing with a glitch.
Rancis, candlehead,
come on.
Sour bill, that glitch
cannot be allowed to race!
And bring that thing
to my castle.
Guys! She took...
(screaming)
(oreos chanting)
♪ or-e-oh
oreo!
(mumbling)
(horn honking)
(beeping)
Sour bill,
de-taffify this monster
So we can see what
we're up against here.
Mm-kay.
(screams)
Milk my duds!
It's wreck-it ralph?
Yeah. Who are you,
the guy that makes the donuts?
(laughs) please.
No. I'm king candy!
I see you're
a fan of pink.
Salmon. Salmon,
that's obviously...
What are you doing here?
Look, your candiness, this is
just a big misunderstanding.
Just get me
out of this cupcake,
I'll get my medal,
and I'll be out of your way.
Your medal? (laughs)
bad guys don't win medals.
Well, this one did.
I earned it
over in  hero's duty.
You game-jumped?
Ralph, you're not
going turbo, are you?
What? No, no.
Because if you think you can
come in here to my kingdom
And take over my game, you've
got another thing coming!
Easy, your puffiness.
It's not my fault
one of your children
Of the candy corn
stole my medal.
"children of the candy corn"?
Who'd...
The glitch!
The coin she used to buy
her way into the race.
That was your medal?
She did what?
I need that back!
Well, I'm afraid I can't
help you. It's gone, you know.
It's nothing but code now.
It will stay that way until
someone wins the cup
At the end of the race.
Maybe I'll have
to have a little talk
With the winner then.
Is that a threat I smell?
Beyond the halitosis you
so obviously suffer from.
Listen, nilly-wafer, I'm not
leaving without my medal!
Yes, you are.
Wynnchel, duncan,
get him out of that cupcake
And on the first train
back home.
If I ever see you here again,
wreck-it ralph,
I'll lock you in my fungeon.
Fungeon?
Fun dungeon, you know?
It's a play on words.
(chuckles) it's the...
Never mind! I've got a glitch
to deal with, thanks to you.
Goodbye, wreck-it ralph!
It hasn't been a pleasure.
This thing is hard as a rock.
I can see that.
Get the tools.
What tools?
Quiet, you!
Ow!
What? No!
Take it easy, big boy!
Stay away from me!
He's getting away!
Quick!
Call out the devil dogs.
(sniffing)
(barking)
(breathing)
Chocolate. I hate chocolate!
I got to get
my medal back.
The pot goes to
the winning racer!
Hey, kids! Can I talk
to you for a second?
(tires screeching)
Hello, fellow racers!
It's that little
crumb snatcher.
Candlehead, taffyta,
rancis, you're looking well.
Came by to check out
the competition, huh?
Well, here it is,
the lickety-split!
Sheesh. Looks like
she built it herself.
I built it myself.
Fastest pedal-power west
of the whac-a-mole.
Check her out.
(honking)
Oh, vanellope,
it's so... You.
(chuckling smugly)
But you have to back
out of the race. Yeah.
Oh, no, I don't,
Because I paid my fee
and I'm on the board...
So, yeah,
I'm definitely racing.
Yeah, well, king candy says
glitches can't race.
I'm not a glitch, taffyta.
I've just got pixslexia, okay?
The rules are there
for a reason, vanellope.
To protect us.
Say I'm you.
I'm in my weird little car
and I'm driving
And I actually feel
kind of cool for once.
And then,
all of a sudden, oh, no.
I'm (stammering)
glitching!
(gasps) hey!
See?
You're an accident
just waiting to happen.
Oh, no!
I (stammers) glitched, too!
Uncool.
Stop it! Stop!
You're breaking it!
Please!
I just want to
race like you guys.
You will never be a racer
because you're a glitch.
And that's all
you'll ever be!
Hey! Leave her alone!
(yelling)
(screaming)
Let's get out of here!
Scram,
you rotten little cavities!
Before I throw you in the mud!
What are you looking at?
You're welcome,
you rotten little thief.
I'm not a thief! I just
borrowed your stupid coin.
I was going to give it back to
you as soon as I won the race.
It's not a coin.
It is a medal.
Coin, medal, whatever.
Just go back to your own dumb
game and win another one.
I can't. I didn't win it
in my game.
I won it in  hero's duty.
Hero's doodie?
It's not that kind of duty.
I bet you really got to watch
where you step
In a game called
hero's doodie!
(laughing)
What did you win
the medal for, wiping?
I hope you washed your hands
after you handled that medal.
Listen!
One more, one more.
Why did the hero
flush the toilet?
Say "why."
why?
Because it was his doodie!
How dare you insult
hero's duty?
You little guttersnipe!
I earned that medal
And you better get it back
for me toot-sweet, sister!
Well, unless you've got
a go-cart
Hidden in the fat folds
of your neck,
I can't help you!
(grunting in frustration)
What a moron.
Hey, genius!
It's a jawbreaker.
You're never
going to break...
Huh.
(panting)
Enjoy your little tantrum,
diaper baby?
Leave me alone.
Look, you want that medal,
right? And I want to race.
So here's what
I'm thinking.
You help me get a new cart...
A real cart...
And I'll win the race
and get you back your medal.
You want me to help you?
All you got to do is
break something for me.
Come on.
What do you say, friend?
We are not friends.
Oh, come on, pal.
You son of a gun.
Come on, buddy.
Let's shake on it.
Ah. Come on, chumbo.
Ralph, my man.
My main man.
Hey!
My arm's getting tired.
Do we have a deal or not?
(grunts) you better win.
Well, I'll say this much,
They don't call your friend
"wreck-it" for nothing.
There's the shuttle.
Is he in there?
Nope. Lucky for him.
Otherwise I would have
slapped his corpse.
No cy-bug, either.
Got to find it before
it lays its filthy eggs.
It came this way,
But the sugar particles
in the atmosphere
Are jamming my sensor.
Can't get a read on it.
So what is it with this
wreck-it joker, huh?
Why did he go awol?
I wish I knew, ma'am.
He was acting
all squirrelly last night...
Going on about
cake and medals...
But I never thought
he'd go turbo.
"go turbo"?
That's right,
you guys just
got plugged in.
Well, back when the arcade
first opened,
Turbo time  was by far
the most popular game.
And turbo...
Turbo-tastic!
He loved the attention.
So, wheroadblasters
got plugged in
And stole turbo's thunder..
New game. All right!
Boy, was he jealous.
So jealous that he
abandoned his game
And tried to take
over the new one.
Player 1: These
are the greatest
graphics I've ever seen!
Turbo-tastic!
Player 2: Hey. Is that...
That looks like turbo.
Player 1: What's turbo doing
in this game? Aw, come on!
Player 2: Mr. Litwak!
Felix:  Turbo ended up putting
both games and himself
Out of order, for good.
Yes, the selfish man
is like a mangy dog
Chasing a cautionary tale.
I know, right?
That's why I have
to get ralph home
Or the same thing's gonna
happen to my game.
(bleeping)
huh?
(grunts)
(both exclaiming)
What is this?
"nesquik sand"?
Quicksand?
Oh, I'll hop out and grab you
one of those vines.
(grunts) huh!
(grunts)
(grunting)
I can't hop. I'm hop-less.
This is hopeless!
We're going to drown here.
Stop thrashing.
Stop moving.
You're making us sink faster.
We're going to die!
Get ahold of yourself!
(laughter)
Felix: The vines.
They're laffy taffy.
They're attracted to whatever
makes them laugh.
Here, hit me again.
(all groan)
That's not funny enough.
Harder!
Look, you're a nice guy.
I can't...
No, ma'am! The arcade
is depending on us.
Now do your duty.
That's an ord...
Oh!
(laughing)
It's working!
Hit me again.
Ooh, your eye.
I can fix it. Now...
Oh! San fran-tastic! Again!
Ow! You mean business!
Ow! Yikes on bikes!
Wow! We're...
Killing... Them!
Comedy gold!
(whimsical singing)
All right, enough with
the goo-goo eyes.
We've got work to do.
Let's go.
(beeping)
Ugh. We lost the cy-bug.
Come on. We'll get
a better view from the air.
You think you can
fix that shuttle?
Can do.
(snoring)
Shh!
All right, do your thing,
knuckles. Bust it open!
What's this? You're a full-on
criminal, aren't you?
Hey, we shook on it.
(sighs)
Thank you, jeeves.
What is this place?
Where are the carts?
You gotta make one.
What? No, no.
Look, kid, bad idea.
Trust me.
I don't make things.
I break things.
Well, it looks like
you're going to be
stepping outside
Your comfort zone,
then, gladys.
Ooh, this is a good one!
Announcer:  Welcome to
the bakery! Let's bake a kar!
Ralph: What is this,
another game?
Vanellope: Yeah, well,
it's a mini-game.
You have one minute
to win it.
What?
Come on, ralph!
Go! Mixing.
Put the ingredients
in the bowl
And throw away the trash.
Hairbrush. No!
Underpants. No, no!
You're getting
all the wrong stuff, kid.
I'm trying!
Let me up there.
I'll do it. No. Yes.
Gross. Milk.
Yes, yes, yes. Oh!
Announcer:  Batter up!
Ah!
Vanellope: Come on!
No sleeping on the job!
Baking! Pump up the heat
And hold
the perfect temperature.
Ralph, a little help here?
I'm on it.
Yeah, no problem.
Give me this thing here.
Vanellope: Okay, good.
Little more.
Yeah, that's it!
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
(dings)
Yes! Come on. Get up, ralph!
Fifteen seconds!
Announcer:  Decorating!
Wheels first.
How many?
Four, doy!
Got it. (grunting)
Now frosting.
A buttload of frosting!
No problem.
Oh.
Announcer:  Time's up!
Congratulations.
You did it,
and here's your cart!
(ralph exclaiming)
Look, kid...
I tried to warn you.
I can't make things.
I just break...
I love it.
You do?
I love it!
I love it! I love it!
Look, it's got a real engine!
And look at these wheels.
(kissing)
I love it!
I finally have a real cart!
Come on. A work of art
like this must be signed.
(snores)
Cream puffs.
(grunts) hmm?
(sniffing)
(gasps) this is beard papa.
The glitch is in the bakery!
Get me king candy!
Oh, what? You have teeth?
I don't think I've ever
seen you smile before.
I'm not smiling.
I was...
I'm gassy, okay?
(laughs)
Hold it right there, glitch!
(gasps)
And wreck-it ralph?
Uh-oh.
(exclaims)
Start the cart!
What are you waiting for?
Come on. Let's go!
I don't know how to
drive a real cart.
You don't what?
Are you hurt, sire?
No, he just glazed me.
Get them!
Gangway!
Oh!
Ah!
Stop, in the name of the king!
That's me!
(siren wailing)
Get off the road!
(tires screeching)
Head for diet cola mountain!
Drive into the wall!
What?
Right there, between the two
sugar-free lollipops!
Are you crazy?
Just do it!
(screaming)
Oh!
Where did they go?
They should have just turned.
Find that glitch!
Destroy that cart!
She can't be allowed to race!
So let me get this straight.
You don't know how to drive.
Well, no, not technically.
I just thought that...
What did you think?
"oh, I'll just magically
win the race
"just because
I really want to!"
Look, wise guy.
I know I'm a racer.
I can feel it in my code.
(grunts in frustration)
That's it! I'm never
getting my medal back.
What is the big whoop about
that crummy medal anyway?
The big whoop?
Well, this may come as a shock
to you, but in my game,
I'm the bad guy
and I live in the garbage.
Cool.
No. Not cool.
Unhygienic and lonely
and boring.
And that crummy medal
was going to change all that.
I go home with that baby
around my neck
And I'll get a penthouse.
Pies.
Ice sculptures. Fireworks!
(grunts)
It's grown-up stuff.
You wouldn't understand.
No, I get it!
That's exactly what racing
would do for me!
Well, guess what?
What?
News flash! Neither one of us
is getting what we want!
(explosion)
What was that?
"diet cola hot springs."
"watch out for
falling mentos."
Yeah! Check it out. Look!
Oh!
Ow! Whoa!
You got to watch out
for the splash.
That stuff is broiling hot.
Ralph: Yeah, I got that.
Thank you.
What is this dump?
I think it's some sort of
unfinished bonus level.
Yeah. It's pretty cool, huh?
I found that secret opening,
and now I live here.
See? Oh, look, look, look.
Welcome to my home!
I sleep in these
candy wrappers.
I bundle myself up like
a little homeless lady.
By yourself?
With all this garbage
around you?
Well, yeah.
I mean, everyone here says
I'm just a mistake
And that I wasn't
even supposed to exist.
What do you expect?
Listen, kid...
I know it's none
of my business
But why do you even
stick around this game?
You really don't know
anything, do you?
Glitches can't
leave their games.
It's one of the joys
of being me.
Hey, what are you doing?
Come on!
I know it's a dump,
but it's all I got.
If you're going to be
a racer,
You're going to have
to learn how to drive.
And you can't do that
without a track.
Whoa!
All right, now.
Let's hustle up.
We've got some driving to do.
I'm going to learn to drive!
Oh, wait.
Do you know how to drive?
Yeah! I mean,
I haven't done it, but...
Look, I flew
a spaceship today, okay?
You crashed it.
Just get in. How hard
can it be? Okay, uh...
Start it up.
(engine starting)
There we go. So there are
some buttons on the floor.
Pedals.
Pedals. Right.
Now, uh,
that's the go pedal.
That I believe is the stopper.
And this... Wait.
What is this?
That doesn't do anything.
Ooh, what does this
joystick do?
Okay, good.
Let's try that again.
♪ I've been looking for
a driver who's qualified
Ow!
♪ I'm a fine-tuned supersoc
speed machine
Ow!
♪ so if you feel me
let me know, know, know
Ow!
♪ so start me up
and watch me go, go, go,o
♪ got you where you wanna o
if you know what I mean
♪ got a ride that smoother
than a limousine
Now shift it.
That's good. Keep going!
Shift it again!
♪ now shut up and drive
drive, drive, drive
(vanellope laughing)
I told you,
racing's in my code!
♪ so if you feel me
let me know, know, know
(chuckling)
I got that medal in the bag!
Hey, ralphie, watch this!
♪ where you wanna go
if you know what I mean?
Whoo-hoo!
♪ I'm zero to 60
in three point five
♪ baby you got the ks
Look out!
Whoa!
♪ shut up and drive
Ah!
Hot cola!
♪ now shut up and drive
So how did I do?
Um...
Well, you almost blew up
the whole mountain.
Right, right.
That's a good note.
You got to get that
glitch under control, kid.
Okay, I will, I will.
And then you think
I got a chance?
Um...
Tiny.
Yes, I'm going to win!
I'm going to win!
Top shelf.
(gasps)
Did you find her?
Tell me you found her.
You didn't?
(laughs hopelessly)
Go. Leave me.
(door closes)
Up, up, down, down...
(mumbling)
Start!
Oh, the code. It's the sweet
lifeblood of the game.
Where are you? Let's see...
Stadium, no. Jumbotron.
Ha-ha! There it is.
The winner's cup.
One of these things is not
like the others... It's you!
We're going to give you
a nice new home.
Success!
(chuckling)
Sour bill, I'm going out.
You're in charge of the castle
until I get back.
Your face is still red.
You might want to hit it
again with your hammer.
Oh, that's not
blunt force trauma, ma'am.
That's just the honey glow
in my cheeks.
Okay.
Ma'am,
I just got to tell you...
You are one dynamite gal.
Wow, you are one dynamite gal.
One dynamite gal.
Dynamite gal.
Dynamite...
(screaming)
Get out.
All I said is
you're a dynamite gal.
I said get out!
Oh. Jiminey jaminey.
Yes?
Oh.
I'm fix-it felix jr., sir,
from the game  fix-it felix jr.
Have you seen my friend ralph?
Wreck-it ralph?
Yes. Yes, that's him!
We should have locked him up
when we had the chance.
Locked him up?
I'm not making
the same mistake with you.
(screams)
Vanellope:  Hurry, hurry!
Let's go. Time's a-wastin'.
Come on, ralph!
This is it.
This is really happening.
I almost don't believe it.
I mean, I have dreamt about it
for so long, and now...
And now... Now I think I'm
going to puke, actually.
I mean, I think I might puke.
You know, like a "vurp."
a what?
Vomit and a burp together,
And you can taste it,
and it's just like rising up.
Oh, this is so exciting!
Yes, it is. It's exciting.
Am I ready to be a real racer?
Ralph, what if the gamers
don't like me?
Who doesn't love a brat
with dirty hair? Come on.
Those people are going
to love you. You know why?
Because you're a winner.
I'm a winner.
And you're adorable!
I'm adorable!
And everyone loves
an adorable winner!
Yeah!
Okay, come on.
Listen to me.
If you get nervous,
just keep telling yourself,
"I must win ralph's medal
or his life will be ruined."
And have fun. Got it?
Got it.
Whoa!
Oh, wait!
(brakes screeching)
Hold on!
Where are you going?
I forgot something!
I'll be right back!
(chuckles)
Kids.
(honking)
Ralph! (chuckles)
there you are. Hello!
You!
I come alone, unarmed.
I've had enough of you,
pillow pants!
Please. Calm down!
Please, look. Don't!
(shuddering)
I'm going to beat
the filling out of you!
You wouldn't hit a guy
with glasses, would you? Ha!
You hit a guy with glasses.
That's... Well played.
(gasps)
what do you want, candy?
Listen, I just want to
talk to you.
I'm not interested in anything
you have to say.
How about this?
Are you interested in this?
My medal. How did you...
It doesn't matter.
It's yours! Go ahead, take it.
(chuckles)
Whoa.
All I ask
is that you hear me out.
About what?
Ralph, do you know
what the hardest part
About being a king is?
Doing what's right,
no matter what.
Get to the point.
Point being, I need your help.
Sad as it is, vanellope
cannot be allowed to race.
Why are you people
so against her?
I'm not against her!
I'm trying to protect her!
If vanellope wins that race
She'll be added
to the race roster.
Then gamers can choose her
as their avatar.
And when
they see her glitching
And twitching
and just being herself,
They'll think our game
is broken.
We'll be put
out of order for good.
All my subjects
will be homeless.
(shouting)
But there's one who cannot
escape because she's a glitc.
Help! Somebody, help! Help!
King candy:  And when
the game's plug is pulle.
(screams) no!
...She'll die with it.
You don't know
that will happen.
The gamers could love her.
And if they don't?
I know it's tough,
But heroes have to make
the tough choices, don't they?
She can't race, ralph,
but she won't listen to me.
So can I count on you to talk
a little sense into her?
Very good.
I'll give you two
some time alone.
(sighs)
I'm back!
Did you miss me?
Yeah... Uh...
Can we talk for a second?
Wait. First, kneel down.
What? No, we really...
Will you just do it?
Okay.
Now, close your eyes.
Vanellope...
Shush! Close them!
(exhales)
Okay. Open them up.
"to stinkbrain."
gee, thanks.
Turn it over.
I made it for you.
Just in case we don't win.
Not that I think there's even
a remote chance
We're not going to win.
Thanks, kid. Listen...
Now rise, my royal chump.
I've got a date with destiny.
Ralph, come on.
Move your molasses.
Um...
I've been thinking.
That's dangerous.
Who cares about this
stupid race anyway? Right?
(laughs)
that's not very funny, ralph.
No, I'm serious,
and it was really fun
To build the car
and everything...
But maybe you shouldn't do it.
Hello? Is ralph in there?
I'd like to speak to him,
please.
Look, what I'm saying is
you can't be a racer.
What?
Why would you...
Wait a minute.
No!
Where did you get this?
Look, I'm going to be
straight with you, kid.
I've been talking
to king candy.
King candy?
Yeah.
You sold me out?
No, I didn't... Listen.
You don't understand.
No, I understand plenty.
Traitor!
I'm not a traitor. Listen.
You're a rat!
And I don't need you, and
I can win the race on my own.
But I'm trying
to save your skin, kid!
Put me down! Let me go!
No, you listen to me.
Do you know
what's going to happen
They'll think
the game's broken.
I don't care!
You're a liar!
You better care, because if
your game goes out of order,
You go down with the ship,
little sister!
I'm not listening to you!
Get out of my way!
I'm going to that race!
No, you're not!
(grunting)
Take me down from here,
ralph, right now!
No. I'm doing this
for your own good!
Wait, wait, wait.
No. No.
No, no, no, no, no!
Please, ralph!
(smashing)
no!
Stop it! Stop it! No!
(vanellope sobbing)
(ralph panting)
You really are a bad guy.
(bell ringing)
Hello? Anybody home?
Felix? Mary?
Well, you actually went
and did it.
Gene. Where is everybody?
They're gone.
After felix went to find you
and then didn't come back...
Everyone panicked
and abandoned ship.
But I'm here now.
It's too late, ralph.
Litwak's pulling our plug
in the morning.
Oh!
But never let it be said
that I'm not a man of my word.
The place is yours, ralph.
Enjoy.
Gene, wait! Wait!
Listen, this is not
what I wanted!
Well, what did you want,
ralph?
I don't know. I just...
(sighs)
I was just tired of
living alone in the garbage.
Well, now you can live alone
in the penthouse.
(sighs)
(thuds)
(beeping)
(humming)
Hey, cough drop.
Explain something to me.
If vanellope was
never meant to exist,
Then why is her picture on
the side of the game console?
Uh...
(shuddering)
What's going on
In this candy-coated
heart of darkness?
Nothing.
Talk!
No.
I'll lick you.
You wouldn't.
Oh, yeah?
Oh! That's like sandpaper!
Mmm. Wonder how many
licks it will take
To get to your center.
I'll take it to my grave!
Fair enough.
Oh!
(exclaims) they call you
sour bill for a reason.
Had enough yet?
Okay, I'll talk, I'll talk!
Vanellope was a racer
Until king candy
tried to delete her code!
Ralph:  Tried to
delete her code?
So that's why she's a glit!
Why is he doing this to he?
I don't know!
Suit yourself.
No, no, no!
I swear I don't know!
He literally locked up
our memories
And I cannot remember!
Nobody can!
But I do know this.
He'll do anything
to keep her from racing.
Because if she crosses
the finish line,
The game will reset and
she won't be a glitch anymore!
Where is she now?
In the fungeon
with fix-it felix.
Felix?
I'm sorry!
That's all I know, I swear!
Now, please, don't put me back
in your filthy mouth again!
(sobbing)
Stick around.
Yes, okay, I will. I will.
Thank you!
Come on.
I know you're out there.
(grunts angrily)
Saccharine-saturated
nightmare!
(beeping rapidly)
(gasps) but... Where?
(screaming)
(screeching)
Doomsday and armageddon just
had a baby and it is ugly!
Hello? Hello?
Somebody! Anybody!
Please let me out!
What's he say?
(imitating ralph)
I'm gonna wreck it!
(groans)
Why do I fix
everything I touch?
Oh! (sobs)
Bam!
Felix!
Ralph!
I'm so glad to see you!
Wait. No, I'm not. What do
you have to say for yourself!
Wait! I don't want to hear it.
I'm not talking to you!
Okay, don't talk. That's fine.
But you have to fix
this go-cart for me pronto.
I don't have to do boo!
Forgive my potty mouth.
I'm just so,
so cross with you!
Do you have any idea
what you put me through?
I ran higgledy-piggledy all
over creation looking for you.
I almost drowned
in chocolate milk-mix!
And then... I met
the most dynamite gal.
Oh! She gives me the honey
glow something awful.
But she rebuffed
my affections.
And then I got thrown in jail!
Felix, pull yourself together.
No! You don't know what
it's like to be rejected
And treated like a criminal!
Yes, I do.
That's every day of my life.
It is?
Which is why I ran off
and tried to be a good guy,
but I'm not!
I'm just a bad guy,
and I need your help.
There's a little girl
whose only hope is this cart.
Please, felix, fix it.
And I promise I will never try
to be good again.
(loud thud)
huh?
I know, I know, I'm an idiot.
And?
And a real numskull.
A selfish diaper baby.
And?
And...
A stinkbrain?
The stinkiest brain ever.
(fanfare)
(cheering)
(engine revving)
King candy: (over pa)
my sweet subjects,
I can without a pinch
of hesitation assure you
That I have never been
so happy in all my life
To say the following wor,
Let the random roster race
commence!
(laughs excitedly)
(tires squealing)
(cars whooshing)
Okay, remember,
you don't have to win.
Just cross that finish line,
and you'll be a real racer.
I'm already a real racer.
And I'm going to win.
(engine roaring)
(beeping)
Announcer over pa:
Power up!
Whoa!
(screams)
Oh! A la mode!
(cheering)
Sweet seekers!
Have some candy.
(laughs)
Behind you!
In front of you!
Huh?
It's the glitch!
The glitch?
Light them up, candlehead.
(laughs)
Announcer:
What's this? Cherry bombs!
(gasps)
I told you. You're just
an accident waiting to happen.
(racers laughing)
(all screaming)
(vanellope grunting)
(sobbing)
My candle!
All right.
Gotta keep it under control.
No more glitching.
Okay, kid.
Let's finish this thing
Without any more surprises.
Oh!
Ow!
Hope you're happy,
junkpile.
This game is going down,
and it's all your fault.
My lady, you came back.
Can it, fix-it!
That cy-bug you brought
with you multiplied.
No. It died in the taffy
swamp. Believe me, I...
(crowd screaming)
Bullroar.
(gun powering up)
Listen up, people. Head to
game central station now!
Move it! Let's go! Let's go!
Go! Go! Go!
No!
(whooping)
Huh?
Get off of my track!
Hey!
Vanellope: What,
are you crazy!
I forbid you to cross
that finish line!
Knock it off!
Felix: Ralph, look!
Ralph: Kid!
Stop it!
I'm not letting you undo
all my hard work!
(both grunting)
Is that...
No way!
What the...
Who are you?
I'm turbo,
the greatest racer ever!
And I did not reprogram
this world to let you
And that
halitosis-riddled warthog
Take it away from me!
(engine revving)
Turbo-tastic.
(laughs evilly)
End of the line, glitch!
(gasps) glitch. That's it.
Come on, vanellope.
I know you said
you wouldn't do it again
But you're going to do it
one more time.
Just focus and concentrate
And glitch!
(shrieks in surprise)
(laughs triumphantly)
Sweet mother of monkey milk!
I did it!
No!
(screams)
Bring it home, kid!
The finish line is wide open!
(vanellope grunts)
No!
Kid! Are you okay?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Let's finish this race!
Oh, my land.
All right. Come on.
We gotta get out of here.
But I didn't cross
the finish line!
Ralph: There is
no finish line!
Move it or lose it, people.
Everybody, out. Now!
Ralph, it's not going to work!
We got to try!
Kid!
Ralph, I told you
I can't leave the game.
Come on. Get through.
Ralph! Stop!
It's got to work!
Stop, it's no use.
(ralph panting)
It's okay, ralph.
Sergeant calhoun:
All right, fix-it.
That's everyone. Now, we've
got to blow up this exit.
Just go. Go without me.
But what about this game?
Nothing we can do about it.
Without a beacon, there's
no way to stop these monsters.
Beacon?
Stay with felix.
Let me borrow
that thing, lady.
Ralph! Where are you going?
I got some wrecking to do!
I'll meet you
at the finish line!
No! Wait!
Fix-it, get behind me!
(grunts)
(yelling)
(rumbling)
Come on!
One more! One...
Oh!
Welcome to the boss level!
Turbo.
(laughs maniacally)
because of you, ralph,
I'm now the most powerful
virus in the arcade!
I can take over
any game I want.
I should thank you
But it would be more fun
to kill you.
Get back here, little guy!
Have some candy!
Where do you think
you're going?
I'm not through with you yet.
Up we go!
No!
Ralph!
Fall back.
(ralph grunting)
Kid!
Vanellope!
Oh, look at that.
It's your little friend.
Let's watch her die together,
shall we?
Ralph: No!
(king candy laughs)
It's game over
for both of you.
No. Just for me!
(gasps) ralph!
Vanellope!
I'm bad, and that's good.
I will never be good,
and that's not bad.
There's no one
I'd rather be...
...Than me.
(loud thud)
Kid!
Don't worry.
I got it under control.
You fools! Why are you
going into the ligh...
(chuckles)
No! No, no, no. Yes...
No! Yes... No!
Go into the light!
Ralph: Whoa!
Chocolate?
(ralph laughs)
It's chocolate!
I love chocolate!
(whooping)
oh, beautiful chocolate!
Vanellope: Yeah!
You did it, ralph!
Oh, way to go, brother!
(laughing)
(gasps)
I... Excuse...
All fixed.
You ready for this?
As ready as I'll ever be.
Whoa!
What's with
all the magic sparkles?
(cheering)
Princess vanellope?
Now I remember.
All hail the rightful ruler of
sugar rush...
Princess vanellope.
(gasps)
I remember.
She's our princess!
Oh, that's right!
We are so sorry
about the way we treated you.
Yeah, those were jokes!
(whining) I was just doing
what taffyta told me to do!
Tut-tut.
As your merciful princess,
I hereby decree
That everyone who was ever
mean to me shall be
Executed.
What? No, please!
Oh, my land.
Oh! This place
just got interesting.
(sobbing)
I don't want to die!
I'm just kidding.
Stop crying, taffyta.
I'm trying, but it won't stop.
Wow.
So this is the real you.
Princess.
Aw, ralph, what are you, nuts?
Come on. This isn't me.
This is me.
Huh?
Look, the code may say
I'm a princess
But I know who
I really am, ralph,
I'm a racer with
the greatest superpower ever.
I was here, I was there.
I was glitching
through the walls.
I'm not giving that up.
Um, pardon me for asking,
But without a princess,
who's going to lead us?
Yeah. Who?
Uh, me. I'm thinking
more along the lines of
A constitutional democracy.
President
vanellope von schweetz.
Has a nice ring to it,
don't you think?
Fix-it, wreck-it,
the arcade's about to open.
Let's move 'em out.
You could just stay here
and live in the castle.
You'd have your own wing
Where no one would ever
complain about your stench
Or treat you bad ever again.
You could be happy.
I'm already happy.
I've got the coolest friend
in the world.
And besides,
I've got a job to do, too.
It may not be as fancy
as being president
But it's my duty.
And it's a big duty!
(chuckles)
Ralph, are you coming,
brother?
See you later,
president fart feathers.
Au revoir,
admiral underpants.
And farewell,
baroness boogerface.
Goodbye, major body odor!
Hasta la vistayou...
Ralph!
All right. To be continued.
Yeah!
All: Hooray!
Ralph:  I'm gonna wreck it!
(grunting angrily)
Hey! Ralph's back!
Isn't that great!
(laughs excitedly)
the gang's all here!
So, I'm happy to report,
and you'll be happy to hear,
I'm taking life
one game at a time.
All right! Yeah, ralph!
Ralph:  Of course,
the job hasn't changed.
But, news flash,
The nicelanders
are being nice to me!
And that got me thinking abot
those poor guys left